<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-193055581255540788</id>
   <published>2013-03-08T09:01:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-03-08T09:01:47.826-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Palaeography"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Latin"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="papyrology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egypt"/>
   <title type="text">PapPal - The Paleography of the Papyri</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.pappal.info/">PapPal</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.pappal.info/images/PapPalHand.png" class="decoded" height="50" src="http://www.pappal.info/images/PapPalHand.png" width="200" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h5><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Paleography of the Papyri</span></h5><span style="font-size: x-small;">Individual letter-forms as well as larger units of text display  paleographical features that are characteristic of the writing styles of  the periods in which they originate. These features are often more  pronounced when a text is written in cursive script than they are in  capital or bookhands. Cursive and semi-cursive writing demonstrates a  degree of individuality that is more easily perceived than in  non-cursive texts. Thus, viewing documentary papyri dated to different  periods provides a fairly clear impression of the basic style of the  epoch in question. Ptolemaic hands are generally easy to distinguish  from Roman, for example, and 5th and 6th c. script has a character  unlike that of the 1st and 2nd c. Yet within these broad chronological  contexts we encounter styles and conventions that depend on a range of  criteria and circumstances, from the type of text that was recorded to  the skill and experience of the writer. One can, for example, often  observe distinct differences between the style of a receipt and that of a  private letter; a chancery hand will look different from a list of  expenditures recorded in the same year; and the Greek script of a native  Latin writer will in some cases diverge significantly from that of a  native Greek writer. In short, we find an impressive diversity of hands,  and this variety frustrates simplistic attempts at a tidy description  of the diachronic development of ancient writing. This is not to say  that any kind of letter-form can be found in any given period. Quite the  contrary, many letter-forms, ligatures, and writing styles are confined  to specific places and times. But recognizing the wide spectrum of  variations ultimately permits more accurate dating of undated hands, as  well as better understanding of the factors that influence specific  writing styles.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">    <span style="font-size: x-small;">In order to provide a reliable point of reference for the  investigation of ancient writing, PapPal collects dated examples of  hands from the 3rd c. BC to the 8th c. AD surviving mainly from  Greco-Roman Egypt. Because many ancient documents preserved on papyrus  are dated to the very day on which they were recorded, viewing them  together brings out features that were typical of a time and, in some  cases, of a place of writing. Furthermore, as no two hands are  identical, comparison of a range of contemporary scripts also  illuminates the variety of writing styles that existed.</span><br /><br />     <span style="font-size: x-small;">The site currently contains primarily Greek papyri. We will soon be adding Greek ostraka and Latin documents.</span><br /><br />    <span style="font-size: x-small;">PapPal permits users to browse images by several different  categories: year, provenance, title and keyword. Images can be viewed  either as a list in which thumbnails are displayed in rows or as a  slideshow. Links accompanying each text direct the user to the project  that hosts the image as well as to a transcription at <a href="http://www.papyri.info/">www.papyri.info</a></span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="pageLinkTop" href="http://www.pappal.info/login">Login</a>                                              <span> | </span>              <a class="pageLinkTop" href="http://www.pappal.info/contact" title="Contact">Contact</a>              <span> | </span>              <a class="pageLinkTop" href="http://www.pappal.info/browsingTips" title="Browsing Tips">Browsing Tips</a>              <span> | </span>              <a class="pageLinkTop" href="http://www.pappal.info/about" title="About">About</a>              <span> | </span>              <a class="pageLinkTop" href="http://www.pappal.info/" title="Home">Home</a>&nbsp;               </span></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span>              <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="pageLinkTop " href="http://www.pappal.info/sample/list" title="Browse Images …">To the Images&nbsp;…</a></span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/193055581255540788/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/03/pappal-paleography-of-papyri.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/193055581255540788"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/193055581255540788"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/03/pappal-paleography-of-papyri.html"
         title="PapPal - The Paleography of the Papyri"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
