<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2989017288452618252</id>
   <published>2013-09-02T08:09:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-09-02T08:09:11.251-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egyptology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egypt"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">Delta Survey Workshop papers online</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.ees.ac.uk/news/index/227.html">Delta Survey Workshop papers online</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">On 22-23 March 2013 the third successful MSA/EES Delta Survey Workshop  took place in Cairo with around 70 participants and 25 papers from  speakers who are active in Delta excavations and research. Following  several requests for copies of the papers, it was decided to make as  many as possible available online and 'open access'.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The first four papers (downloadable PDFs) are now available on a new page on our website: <a href="http://www.ees.ac.uk/research/Delta_Workshop.html">www.ees.ac.uk/research/Delta_Workshop.html</a> and further papers will be added as and when they are completed.<br /><br />The Delta Survey home page has also been updated: <a href="http://www.ees.ac.uk/research/delta-survey.html">http://www.ees.ac.uk/research/delta-survey.html</a><br /><br />For more details see the 'Delta Survey' blog: <a href="http://tinyurl.com/opb5ma7">http://tinyurl.com/opb5ma7</a></span><br /><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Abstracts</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">In the order in which papers appeared on the  programme for the Workshop. PDFs of papers are being added below the  relevant abstracts as they are ready. If you would like to be notified  when additional papers are added, or request a higher quality PDF,  please send an e-mail to <a href="mailto:patricia.spencer@ees.ac.uk?subject=Delta%20Workshop%202013&amp;body=Please%20inform%20me%20when%20a%20paper%20is%20added%20to%20the%20Delta%20Workshop%20page%20of%20the%20EES%20website.">Patricia Spencer</a>.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Mohamed Abd el-Maqsoud</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Tell Hebua (Tjarou) I, II, III. Defense System on the eastern gate of Egypt</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Tell  Hebua is situated on the eastern bank of the Suez Canal, in north-east  Sinai, about 4km from the city Al-Qantara East. The three sites at Hebua  represent an agglomeration located on the edge of a paleo-lagoon.  Excavation carried out recently has revealed a defense system  represented by fortresses reinforced with towers and surrounding  administrative and religious buildings, with palaces and domestic  structures of the New Kingdom and Late Period. Tell Hebua II, which is  750m south-east of Hebua I, has yielded a massive structure representing  a fortified city and containing a series of magazines and a religious  complex of the New Kingdom. Hebua III which lies about 1km south-east of  Hebua II, includes domestic structures with many silos and bread ovens,  with serpentine walls and many ox burials. The discovery of fortified  cities at Hebua (Tjarou) has confirmed inscriptions on the walls of  Karnak of the reign of Sety I who described the fortresses and  installations of North Sinai.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Hesham M Hussein and Sayed Abd el-Aleem</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Tell el-Kedwa (Qedua): Saite Fortresses on Egypt’s Eastern Frontier. </i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  excavation at Tell al-Kedwa was undertaken by an Egyptian  archaeological mission (2008). The site of Tell al-Kedwa lies on flat  ground 25km north-east of Al-Qantara East. Tell al-Kedwa was occupied by  a military fortification which dated to the Saite Period. Previous  excavations had revealed a massive square mud-brick fortress 200m x  200m. The SCA excavation showed that there was more than one fortress at  Tell al-Kedwa. Two forts of the Saite Period have been found; the  earlier structure (fort A) dates from the beginning of the Saite Period,  the later one (fort B) dates from the second half of the same period.</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ees.ac.uk/userfiles/file/DW13%20Hussein_Abd%20el-Aleem.pdf">Download PDF</a></span></h2><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Geoffrey Tassie</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>The Wadi Tumilat in Antiquity and Today</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Two  major surveys of the Wadi Tumilat have been undertaken, the first by  Schott in the late 1920s and the other by Holladay in the late 1970s and  early 1980s. These surveys revealed the presence of several  multi-period sites in the western Wadi Tumilat but their conclusions  were that the Wadi Tumilat only had major occupation from the Late  Period and only minor traces of earlier occupation could be discerned.  The discovery of the large Predynastic to Early Dynastic Periods site of  Kafr Hassan Dawood in the late 1980s challenged this perceived  knowledge. The continued analysis of the excavated material remains  indicates that the site was occupied from 3,400 BC to 2,700 BC and  possibly earlier, making it contemporary with earliest remains at  Minshat Abu Omar. Analysis of the later remains at the site, which were  preliminarily dated to Late Period to Ptolemaic also indicate that the  occupation continued for longer. The results of the current analysis of  both periods, relating to the excavations in the 1990s, will be  presented.<br />&nbsp;</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Irene Forstner-Müller and Pamela Rose</b></span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Tell el-Dab'a/Avaris/Recent Results</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Investigation  of the landscape at Tell el-Dab’a/Avaris (under the excavation  concession of the Austrian Archaeological Institute, Cairo branch, since  1966), has long been an integral element of the research, and began  before landscape archaeology became popular. The focus of this paper is  on area R/III where excavations were undertaken from 2010-12 to combat  the ongoing destruction of archaeological remains by modern agricultural  activity. The area was divided, by streets running from  north-north-west to south-south-east and converging towards the south,  into several insulae. Two different quarters of Avaris could be  distinguished, and thus provided the opportunity to conduct a study on  the function of individual areas in the central part of the town. In the  western part (an administrative quarter consisting of one block)  spacious buildings dating to the later Second Intermediate Period were  discovered, while the eastern district, with narrower side streets, is a  typical domestic town quarter with a layout common at Avaris. In  contrast to the western district, tombs were found within this domestic  quarter, as was usual in domestic quarters at Avaris in the Second  Intermediate Period. Besides other finds over 1,000 sealing impressions  were found in this area: including some with royal names such as that of  King Khyan of the 15th Dynasty.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Manuela Lehmann</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Skylines, bridges and mud in the Delta and elsewhere</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In  this lecture I would like to present the latest results of the ongoing  research at Tell el-Dab’a into developments of the Late Period and early  Ptolemaic Period, when, as at many other sites in the Delta, the  pattern of the settlement changes dramatically compared to earlier  periods due to a new type of architecture in Egypt. This type is also  found in other places in the ancient Near East and is partly still in  use today. An ethnoarchaeological comparison between the ancient Delta  and modern Yemen gives surprisingly fruitful insights into this building  type, its construction and the ways people deal with this architecture.</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ees.ac.uk/userfiles/file/DW13%20Lehmann.pdf">Download PDF</a></span></h2><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></h3><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Tomasz Herbich and Irene Forstner-Müller</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Small harbours in the Nile Delta: the case of Tell el-Dab’a</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  basis for the reconstruction of the historic landscape in the region of  Tell el-Dab’a is geomorphological research carried out in the 1990s by  J. Dorner. Magnetic survey since 1999 has helped to define the position  of the Pelusiac Nile branch, outline the floodplain limits, define  precisely the locations of settled areas and their layouts, and identify  possible locations of the main ports. Moreover, the precise picture of  the shoreline provided by the survey allowed the identification of what  may have been small harbours, two of which - in the area of Ezbet  il-Ezzawin and Ezbet Mehesin - are the theme of this paper. Magnetic  mapping suggests that the waterfronts were artificially formed and  clearly show a vacant space between the waterfront and the settlement  edge. The magnetic image of sediments filling the riverbed may indicate  that it had been deepened. Electro-resistivity survey was carried out  using the vertical electrical sounding method and the resulting  measurements support the hypothesis of the artificial formation of  waterfronts, demonstrating that materials of a high resistivity (most  probably with a high content of sand or gravel) were used in their  construction. Test drilling in Ezbet il-Ezzawin showed the presence of  bricks with a high sand content.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />Mostafa Nor el-Din</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Egyptian rescue excavation in Tell el-Retaba</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Tell  el-Retaba is a major dynastic-period site in northern Egypt and like  many other sites in Egypt it is under constant threat of destruction. An  asphalt road linking Cairo with the city of El-Qantara was built  through Tell el-Retaba some years ago and current development of this  road into a multi-lane highway was approved by Egypt’s Supreme Council  of Antiquities on the condition that full archaeological excavations  should first take place. The salvage project covered an area  approximately 230m long (north-south) and 10m wide (east-west) and the  rescue excavation has added important new data on the long settlement  history of the site from the Second Intermediate Period until the Late  Period.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Aiman Ashmawy Ali</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>The SCA excavation at Tell Basta 2002</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In  2002 the SCA carried out an excavation in the area to the north of the  great temple of Bastet and east of the excavation site of 2001. It is a  high mound with a pointed top which slopes sharply in its northern part.  In the upper level the foundation of complete house was discovered and  parts of three other mud-brick houses, beside a well built of red  bricks. The houses (probably 30th Dynasty or early Ptolemaic Period)  seemed to be laid out in regular orthogonal plan indicating pre-planned  settlements which might have belonged to workers involved in the temple  activities of Nectanebo II at Bubastis. The northern part of the site is  2m deep and excavation here uncovered parts of a large building, most  probably a palace or a large house, beside two earlier silos. The  building is dated, by ceramic evidence, to the 26th Dynasty. A layer of  burned ash was discovered around the silos and between the walls -  similar to the units with burnt ash discovered in 2001 within the  buildings to the west, which represent magazines. The discovery of ash  in the magazines added to our knowledge about ancient measures to  protect the grain and control insects and mites, by using ash, mud and  sand.</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ees.ac.uk/userfiles/file/DW13%20Ashmawy.pdf">Download PDF</a></span></h2><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;</span></h3><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Eva Lange</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Shedding new light on the tales of Herodotus: the hydrogeography of Bubastis and its hinterland</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  famous description of Herodotus about the Temple of Bastet at Bubastis  focuses on the existence of two canals (the ‘Isheru’ or sacred lake)  surrounding the temple, transforming it into an island. These canals  were fed by the Nile branch which passed very close to Bubastis.  Previously the account of Herodotus seemed to be the only available  source for the existence of the canals, but recent research at the site  has produced archaeological evidence for them. They formed the core of a  sacred landscape, built for the cult of Bastet. However, the Isheru of  Bubastis have to be considered as only a part of the picture of the  hydrogeography of the city and its surrounding territory - the situation  of Bubastis adjacent to two main Nile branches of the Delta, and its  evolution, is strongly connected to the existence of access to those  waterways. Any attempt to reconstruct the history of the city needs to  be based on the investigation of its hydrogeography: the course of the  Nile branches, artificial canals and the possible location of the  harbour of Bubastis.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Veit Vaelske</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>‘A horse so prancing is indeed a thing of beauty’. On ‘rider’ terracottas from Tell Basta</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">During  various excavations in Lower Egypt clay statuettes have been found,  consisting of separately formed horses and mounted bearded riders. The  distinctive appearance has led not only to different identifications,  but also to ethnic interpretations. Common are appellations such as  ‘Scythians’ or ‘Persian Riders’ whereby a connection with a multi-ethnic  Nile Delta is implied. This reading might be supported by the dating of  the figurines to the third century BC, in the Egyptian Late Period,  separating the type from Egyptian coroplastic production during the  later Hellenistic Period or the Roman Period. The Tell Basta Project so  far has found about 65 fragments of horse-and-rider-figurines of this  iconographic pattern; enough material to assess in comparison with  previous discussions and to try to establish a classification for this  specific terracotta group.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Manfred Bietak</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>On some palaces and ports in the eastern Delta: a contribution to historical geography.</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">This  paper tries to assess the strategic importance of the eastern Delta by  the position and character of palaces at the easternmost Nile branch  from the Middle Kingdom to the Ramesside Period. It also tries to put  the palatial quarters into the context of the historical geography of  the eastern Delta.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Cezary Baka</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Old Kingdom Settlement in the Nile Delta: an overview</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  Old Kingdom in the Nile Delta is much less well-attested than many  later or even earlier periods. Since there are still too few sites where  Old Kingdom remains have been identified and properly studied, the aim  of this presentation is not to propose even a hypothetic reconstruction  of the settlement network but to comment on the geographic distribution  of those sites which are known. A map of Old Kingdom Delta sites shows a  great disproportion in settlement density and types of archaeological  remains, which can not be explained only by the distribution of research  projects. The Nile Delta in the Old Kingdom was quite different from  its modern state in aspects of its geography and environmental  conditions and can be divided into three main regions: in the eastern  Delta developed urban settlements were located on geziras as well as on  the levées. In the south-western Delta very often only the levées had  suitable conditions for permanent settlement and the small amount of  ground which was habitable during the flood season may have influenced  settlement density. The northern Delta seems to have been much less  densely settled in the Old Kingdom but the small amount of  archaeological data may not signify an absence of settlements, but might  indicate that it took a different form in this more swampy area.<br />&nbsp;</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ayman Wahby and Karim Abdel Fattah</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Some little-known archaeological sites in Dakahlia Governorate</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  aim of our paper is to shed light on some lesser-known archaeological  sites in the governorate of Dakahlia: Tell el-Kabir, about 4km to the  north of El-Kurdi, in Ezbet el-Khudery; Tell el-Balasun, south-east of  El-Kurdi on the road of Shelbaya, in Ezbet el-Bakry (the tell itself is  located in Ezbet Salib); Tell el-Khereba, one of the registered  archaeological sites of el-Sinbellawein - a few red  bricks and pottery  sherds are distributed on the tell; Tell el-Lugga, about 20km south-east  of Sinbellwein and about 5km from Tell el-Farkha, near Ezbet Wahby; Kom  el-Hammamat - one of the registered archaeological sites of Bilqeis,  together with Kom Nuqyza and Tell Yetwal wa Yaqsur; Tell Ibn Salam,  located in El-Menzala lake which surrounds it on all sides; Tell  Halbouny and Tell Murad which are archaeological sites in Shirbin  together with Tell el-Balamun - they are near the village of El-Atrash;  Tell el-Dahab, south of Dikirnis and covered with grass, fragments of  pottery and shells; Tell el-Hufya in Beni Ebeid: Kom Niqeiza, also  called Tell el-Qa’da, and situated at the limit of Dakahlia governorate  near Kafr el-Sheikh - it is covered with fragments of pottery, shells  and red bricks.</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ees.ac.uk/userfiles/file/DW13%20Wahby_AbdelFattah.pdf">Download PDF</a></span></h2><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Assayed el-Banna</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Archaeological  tells in Kafr Ash-Sheikh Governorate which are liable to vanish due to  global climatic changes: a research paper on the management of  archaeological sites </i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">This paper aims to draw attention to  many recent alerts from international and local institutes, warning of  the seriousness of sea-level rise due to global climate change all over  the world. The impact on Egypt could be severe, and in Kafr Ash-Sheikh  Governorate these changes (if they happen) will result in the  disappearance of many archaeological tells. This paper proposes a survey  project to study endangered tells and to decide how we will face this  problem which surely will require the collaboration of authorities -  including the Ministry of State for Antiquities - to study the  consequences of climate change and to devise the needed careful  preventive measures to avoid devastating effects on the archaeological  tells close to the sea in Delta areas. The basic idea of the project is  to prepare an urgent salvage plan to address the negative impacts  expected on archaeological tells in Kafr Ash-Sheikh Governorate which  will be endangered by the effects of climate change. A three-phase plan  of action is proposed: (1) conducting preliminary archaeological surveys  of all archaeological tells within the endangered area, making use of  the SCA datasheet; (2) developing a rescue excavation plan and  identifying the equipment needed and finally (3) carrying out the  excavations.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />Robert Schiestl</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>The Regional Survey around Buto (Tell el-Farain), western Delta: results 2011-12</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In  2011 and 2012 the Regional Survey around Buto (Tell el-Farain),  conducted by the German Archaeological Institute Cairo, focused its  investigations on areas in the vicinity of Buto. Work was conducted in  fields north-east of Buto in areas today used as agricultural land and  on the freestanding tell of Kom el-Gir, about 4km north-east of Buto.  The complete loss of small ancient sites, marked as tells on early  Survey of Egypt maps and often still detectable on 40 year old satellite  images (Corona) can be observed. These sites have almost entirely  disappeared below the current surface. Magnetometric prospection at the  freestanding site of Kom el-Gir has revealed a Graeco-Roman settlement.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Gregory Marouard (on behalf of Pascale Ballet, Sylvie Dhennin, Guy Lecuyot, Gregory Marouard and Bérangère Redon)</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Recent works on the late periods at Buto (2011-12)</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In  collaboration with the German Institute of Archaeology (Cairo) and the  MSA (Inspectorate of Kafr el-Sheikh), and supported by the French  Ministry of Foreign and European Affairs (Paris), IFAO (Cairo) and the  Centre of Alexandrian Studies (Alexandria), the University of Poitiers  has concentrated its recent fieldwork (2011-12) in two main directions.  Firstly, investigating the evolution of the city through a new method of  extensive survey mapping in 2012 on an area over 11,000 m2  in the  northern part of Kôm A. One of the first aims of this survey was to  highlight, for the Kom A area initially, the limits of the town of Buto  during the late phases of its occupation, from the Late Period to the  beginning of the Islamic Period. Secondly, studies on the Hellenistic  and Roman innovations of the bath buildings in sector P10 (Ptolemaic to  the Roman times) where the EES worked in the 1960s, and (in  collaboration with the MSA Inspectorate of Kafr el-Sheikh) in the  Ptolemaic baths near the modern village of Mohammed el-Baz.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Joanne Rowland</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Investigations in Minufiyeh province in 2011 and 2012: in Quesna and Khatatbah</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Since  the last workshop, work has been progressing in two key areas - Quesna,  the necropolis for Athribis, and in the region of Khatatbah, which  represents one of the earliest areas for temporary and permanent  settlers in the Nile Delta. At Quesna, investigations have focused on  the Ptolemaic-Roman cemetery and also the corridors of the sacred falcon  necropolis, where there is now further inscriptional evidence to link  Quesna with Athribis, and the first from the EES investigations in the  falcon necropolis in particular. Excavations in the cemetery have  continued to inform about the range of medical conditions and trauma  which affected the population, as well as providing new information on  the range of burial types. At Khatatbah, summer 2011 saw a specialised  team visiting survey areas within a 5km tract of land south of the  modern town. The finds range throughout the Palaeolithic Period and into  the Neolithic Period and provide a starting point for a more focused  survey with palaeoenvironmental reconstruction in spring 2013.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ahmed Deraz and Mohammed el-Sharkawy</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Recent discoveries in Quesna archaeological area</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  Quesna archaeological area is located about 2km from modern Quesna and  12km from Shebin el-Kom in Minufiyeh Governorate. It contains many  archaeological remains including: the brick-built mausoleum, the Roman  coffin burials and the sacred falcon necropolis. In view of its  importance, the Faculty of Arts, Minufiyeh University decided to  complete the archaeological excavations (halted in 2009) in the south  side of the archaeological area, of the brick-built mausoleum containing  burials of the Late and Ptolemaic Periods, overlaid by Roman burials.  The aims were to complete the excavation of the mausoleum, to try to  find any evidence of other structures, to study burial patterns and  positions, and to research Egyptian religion and architecture in the  period when the mausoleum was in use. Work started on the north side of  the mausoleum and has revealed additional features which will be  described during the paper.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Mohamed Kenawi, Valentina Gasperini and Georgia Marchiori</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Kom al-Ahmer (Kom Wasit). The Italian Archaeological Mission in the western Nile Delta</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">During  the Beheira Survey Project conducted between 2008 and 2011 in the  western Delta, eight sites of wine production, seven sites of olive oil  production, four amphorae workshops, and probably Metelis, the capital  of the nomos, were discovered and documented, in addition to sixty-six  other sites. The rediscovery of the first documented plant nursery  underscored the importance of the region from an economic perspective.  As a result of the survey, the economic importance of the western Delta  can be compared with Alexandria and the rest of Egypt. In 2012  excavation and survey started at Kom al-Ahmer (Kom Wasit), yielding some  important finds that demonstrate the economic importance of the site.  There were also significant pottery finds (fourth-seventh centuries AD)  with imports accounting for 75% percent of the amphorae - the majority  from Cilicia. This confirmation of direct contact with Mediterranean  ports and a large unidentified structure has encouraged us to continue  our excavations.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />Marek Chłodnicki &amp; Krzysztof M. Ciałowicz</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Tell el-Farkha. Excavations 2012-2013</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">During  the seasons 2012-13 excavations at Tell el-Farkha were continued on all  three koms. On the Western Kom, fieldwork was carried out within the  older trench that had been opened in 2006 and excavation undertaken in  the layers between the oldest phases of the administrative-cultic centre  (Naqada IIIB) and the top layers of burnt Naqadian residence, partly  excavated in 2003-04 (Naqada IIIA-Naqada IID2/IIIA). On the Central Kom,  the trench was extended to the west. A building with massive mud-brick  walls (1.5m-1.7m thick) dated to Naqada III B was discovered there. A  new trench for verification of the results of geophysical research was  also opened on the north-western slope of the kom. A rounded building 7m  in diameter on the interior, and with a 2m thick wall, was discovered  there. It had been destroyed at the beginning of the Third Dynasty. The  excavations in 2013 should identify the function of that construction.  On the Eastern Kom, works were concentrated around the large structure  found in 2004 (a mastaba). We found a group of the rooms bordered on the  north by a m thick wall and a similar wall was also found to the south  of the mastaba.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Joanna Debowska-Ludwin</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Early mastabas from Tell el-Farkha</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">At  Tell el-Farkha approximately120 excavated tombs belong to three  distinct cemeteries associated with the Protodynastic and Early Dynastic  Periods and the Old Kingdom, and many have mastaba superstructures. The  oldest mastaba at Tell el-Farkha (NIIIA2/B1) is also the largest and  the most monumental. Not long after, a new necropolis was started next  to, and partially over, the abandoned large mastaba. The impressive  mastaba tombs which make up the cemetery were constructed for members of  a wealthy society and they demonstrate the high status of their owners.  The so-called Early Dynastic graves reflect the changing political  fortunes of the settlement at Tell el-Farkha but also show deeper  evolution within the social structure of the young Egyptian kingdom.   Although burials from this phase of the cemetery were far more  diversified and usually rather poor, quite monumental mastabas were also  constructed.  The latest graves represent the final decline of the  settlement and were only the simplest pit burials. The use of mastaba  tombs at Tell el-Farkha lasted about 500 years and corresponded to the  most prosperous period of the settlement.  Their study makes a major  contribution to our knowledge of early Egyptian burial customs and the  development of typical Egyptian mastaba tombs.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Marcin Czarnowitz</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Nile Delta foreign relations during the Pre- and Early Dynastic Periods in the light of excavations at Tell el-Farkha</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Since  1998 a Polish team has been excavating at Tell el-Farkha in the eastern  Nile Delta. Archaeologists believe that ‘Chicken Mound’ (the meaning of  the name in English) played an important role in relations between the  southern Levant and Egypt. The time of the site’s greatest flourishing  corresponds with the development of the so-called ‘Egyptian colony’ in  Palestine. According to various surveys conducted in the Nile Delta,  Tell el-Farkha was a nodal point on the route from Upper Egypt to the  southern Levant, located at a crossroad with the passage leading into  the Western Delta. A high number of imported pottery fragments and  locally made imitations underlines the role of the site in long range  trade. This paper will once again reexamine the arguments supporting  this theory, showing the most important objects of Levantine provenance  and locally-made imitations. The latter part of the paper will present  also non-pottery evidence of contacts discussing, among other points,  commodities that Tell el-Farkha was able to send to the Levant.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />Jeffrey Spencer (on behalf of Ross Thomas and Alexandra Villing)</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Naukratis (Kom Geif) 2012 field season</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In  October 2012 the first British Museum fieldwork season at Naukratis was  conducted by members of the Museum’s Naukratis Project. Naukratis was  the earliest and, for a period, the only Greek port in Egypt.   Established in the late seventh century BC as a base for Greek (and  Cypriot) traders, and the port of Sais, Naukratis was an important hub  for trade and cross-cultural exchange with artefacts from the site  spanning the late seventh century BC to the seventh century AD (at  least). The new fieldwork complements the Project’s study of earlier  excavations (by Petrie, Hogarth and Leonard/Coulson), clarifying their  results and the helping to contextualise artifacts (see the open access  catalogue: www.britishmuseum.org/naukratis). This research has advanced  our understanding of the site, particularly of the full extent of the  city, its geomorphology, harbour, structures and development over time.  During the first fieldwork season an accurate map of the site was  produced by recording all visible archaeological features, by tying  previous excavations and surveys to our survey, and by the  identification of new archaeological features through the use of  magnetometry.</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.britishmuseum.org/research/publications/online_journals/bmsaes/issue_20/thomas__villing.aspx">Download PDF from British Museum Studies in Ancient Egypt and Sudan (BMSAES)</a></span></h2><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Mohamed Abd el-Meguid</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Alexandria: new strategies - more discoveries</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Using  the simple basic scientific rules for exploration has revealed more  than twenty archaeological sites in Alexandria during the last two  years. These sites help us to understand the complex topography of the  city during its long life. They vary between rock tombs, pottery graves  and simple inhumations spanning the period from the Hellenistic to  Byzantine eras for pagans and Christians, especially in the eastern side  of the city. The western side yielded simple and complex cisterns from  the Roman Period to the Ottoman Period. In the middle of the city parts  of streets have been discovered. Study of these sites, as well as of the  associated objects, is in process.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Penny Wilson</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Optimising Delta Survey information and targeting research problems</i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  collection of information from Delta sites has resulted in a wealth of  data from areas of the Delta, at varying degrees of resolution. Ground  survey, mapping, artefact and pottery recording allied with satellite  imagery and local knowledge have produced a mosaic of material, some of  which has been published (van den Brink, Bietak, Wilson &amp;  Grigoropoulos) or is publicly available through the Delta EES Survey  website. This paper is an attempt to evaluate the survey data and its  coverage, to measure the amount of work still to be done and to raise  particular questions and problems with colleagues. In particular: how  useful is site visiting without other topographical work in the  satellite-survey age? To what extent can local knowledge and interests  be built into site work (the cultural heritage co-efficient)? What is  the intended legacy of the survey work – for all archaeologists,  geographers and government agencies interested in the work (looking at  the EAIS objectives)? What overall chronological, geological and  humanistic frameworks are applicable? How can the Delta Survey be  augmented in a low-cost, low-tech way by researchers in Egypt (training  and funding, quality control)?</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Robert Littman and Mohamed Kenawi</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Tell Timai (ancient Thmuis) </i></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">An  international team of scholars sponsored by the University of Hawaii  has been working at Tell Timai (ancient Thmuis) since 2007. The first  goal of the project is to preserve and conserve this exceptional example  of a Ptolemaic and Roman period metropolis from destruction, while  studying an invaluable source of history of the life, economy, and  culture of Egypt in Late Antiquity.  The work at Thmuis is writing a new  chapter of Egyptian history in the Nile Delta.  Here we present the  introduction to that chapter with an archaeological overview of the  history of the town and our hopes for its future.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2989017288452618252/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/09/delta-survey-workshop-papers-online.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2989017288452618252"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2989017288452618252"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/09/delta-survey-workshop-papers-online.html"
         title="Delta Survey Workshop papers online"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
