<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-497380666902755748</id>
   <published>2012-02-21T16:43:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2012-02-21T16:43:56.195-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Journal Systems Enhancement</title>
   <content type="html">Many of the &lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html"&gt;Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies&lt;/a&gt; are served from the &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca/?q=ojs"&gt;Open Journal Systems&lt;/a&gt; platform.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.surffoundation.nl/en/Pages/default.aspx"&gt;SURFfoundation&lt;/a&gt;, has just announced the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;development of two plug-ins permitting the enhancement OJS publications with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;related research data:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.surffoundation.nl/en/actueel/Pages/EnhancedPublicationsnowpossiblewithOpenJournalSystems.aspx"&gt;Enhanced Publications now possible with Open Journal Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Research results published within tried-and-tested system using plug-ins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="print_title"&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="grey"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;       21-02-2012    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Internet makes it possible to present publications in combination with related research data, as &lt;a href="http://www.surffoundation.nl/en/themas/openonderzoek/verrijktepublicaties/Pages/default.aspx"&gt;Enhanced Publications&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://www.surffoundation.nl/en/projecten/Pages/EJME.aspx"&gt;The Enhanced Journals…Made Easy&lt;/a&gt; project (EJME), which is funded by SURF, has designed a practical work  process for publishers of Open Access journals so as to enhance academic  journals with the associated data files. The project involved the  development of two plug-ins for &lt;a href="http://pkp.sfu.ca/?q=ojs"&gt;Open Journal Systems&lt;/a&gt;,  a system for managing and publishing journals. Open Journal Systems  (OJS) is the most frequently used open source package worldwide for  academic journals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Journal Systems&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;OJS is used internationally to promote and increase access to  research results. It is used for more than 10,000 journals. The plug-ins  developed during the EJME project add capabilities to OJS. The &lt;a href="http://www.uva.nl/"&gt;University of Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.uu.nl/"&gt;Utrecht University&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.dans.knaw.nl/"&gt;DANS&lt;/a&gt; (Data Archiving and Network Services), and &lt;a href="http://www.aup.nl/"&gt;Amsterdam University Press&lt;/a&gt; have made use of a tried-and-tested system for creating enhanced  publications so as to stick as close as possible to the publication  process used by researchers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication process&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Authors and editors who use OJS can now easily add data files  to articles, including the associated metadata. The data files are then  available – without any extra action being necessary – for everyone  involved in the editorial process, including peer reviewers. When the  article is published, there are references to the datasets, both on the  webpage and in a machine-readable file. It is also important that the  editorial team can make it possible for the data to be automatically  submitted to a reliable data repository when the article is published. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;According to &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/jeroen-sondervan/3/aa2/36a"&gt;Jeroen Sondervan&lt;/a&gt; (Amsterdam University Press), “This integration of research data and  results on the one hand and publications on the other creates a  completely new way of assessing, verifying, and publishing. The  combination of OJS and the EJME plug-ins brings this a step closer.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practical testing&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;The EJME plug-ins link up with the work process followed by the  editors of Open Journals: from the researcher’s intention to publish to  the Open Access publication of the article. The plug-ins that have been  developed have been tested in practice by two journals published by two  different publishers:&lt;br /&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://dpc.uba.uva.nl/cgi/t/text/text-idx?c=jalc"&gt;Journal of Archaeology in the Low Countries&lt;/a&gt; (JALC), published by Amsterdam University Press (AUP)&lt;br /&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.thecommonsjournal.org/"&gt;International Journal of the Commons&lt;/a&gt; (IJC), published by UBU/Igitur Publishing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Knowledge Project&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Staff of the international OJS are enthusiastic about the EJME  plug-ins and have included them in their plug-in library. “We are very  happy with what EJME has done. The plug-ins are extremely useful and  robust, and the documentation is clear and well written," says &lt;a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/kevin-stranack/13/521/128"&gt;Kevin Stranack&lt;/a&gt; of Public Knowledge Project (PKP), the organisation that manages and  develops the OJS. PKP is negotiating with Utrecht University regarding  collaboration to improve the functionality for depositing research data  via OJS.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More information&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;For editors of Open Journals: more about &lt;a href="http://wiki.surffoundation.nl/display/vp/Enhanced+Journals+Made+Easy+%28EJME%29"&gt;how to present enhanced publications via the available plug-ins&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/497380666902755748/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/02/open-journal-systems-enhancement.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/497380666902755748"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/497380666902755748"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/02/open-journal-systems-enhancement.html"
         title="Open Journal Systems Enhancement"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
