<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5898090875362887917</id>
   <published>2013-12-13T17:07:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-12-13T17:07:28.559-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">The Center for the Study of New Testament Manuscripts (CSNTM): Manuscripts</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://csntm.org/manuscript">The Center for the Study of New Testament Manuscripts (CSNTM): Manuscripts</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The requirements that need to be satisfied for using these images in  publication vary from manuscript to manuscript. Each possessing   institute or individual has its own requirements. If you wish to  publish any of these images, you will need to get permission from CSNTM   first. We can then direct you to the contact person of the institute  that owns the manuscript(s) for further instructions. CSNTM does not   charge for the use of these images, though the institute that owns the  manuscripts may. At minimum, CSNTM needs to be credited with the   photographs and the possessing institute needs to be credited with  ownership of the manuscript in all research for which these images are   used. For more information about usage of manuscript images, contact <a href="mailto:info@csntm.org">info@csntm.org</a></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In order to find your way through the images of manuscripts, you should download the scripture index for each      manuscript (it's the first document on each manuscript's page). Only a few manuscripts currently have a scripture      index, but more are coming.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Center for the Study of New Testament Manuscripts (CSNTM) is  continuing to grow its online resources. Today we are proud to announce  that we now have i<a href="http://csntm.org/manuscript">mages of 128 papyri manuscripts in our archives, 111 digital papyri manuscripts online, and 80 of these available publically</a>  (the remaining are available for private viewing only due to contractual  arrangements). <b>This includes the new high resolution images of the Chester Beatty Papryi!</b></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5898090875362887917/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/12/the-center-for-study-of-new-testament.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5898090875362887917"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5898090875362887917"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/12/the-center-for-study-of-new-testament.html"
         title="The Center for the Study of New Testament Manuscripts (CSNTM): Manuscripts"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
