<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-244695579768645979</id>
   <published>2010-04-21T12:17:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2010-04-21T12:25:27.922-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">L'ANNÉE PHILOLOGIQUE update</title>
   <content type="html">The following message was distributed by email this morning to members of the&lt;a href="http://www.apaclassics.org/"&gt; APA&lt;/a&gt; and is reproduced here with permission (hyperlinks added).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:85%;"&gt;Dear APA Member:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We are very pleased to announce that &lt;a href="http://www.annee-philologique.com/aph/"&gt;L'ANNÉE PHILOLOGIQUE on the&lt;br /&gt;Internet (APh Online)&lt;/a&gt; now has a new and more powerful user interface.&lt;br /&gt;Here are some of its most important new features:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• A Quick Search screen now appears on the initial page and is available&lt;br /&gt;on all subsequent screens.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• A single screen presents all available indices and filters for&lt;br /&gt;advanced searches.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• Each page of search results can be sorted by Author, Title, or&lt;br /&gt;Publication Date.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• An AJAX script makes indices for modern and ancient authors more&lt;br /&gt;powerful.  As the user starts typing in the text box, a list of possible&lt;br /&gt;selections begins to appear, and the list is refined as each letter is&lt;br /&gt;added or removed.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• More options are available for exporting records including: text file,&lt;br /&gt;PDF File, RIS Format, and RefWorks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• Users can save searches, records, and personal parameters such as&lt;br /&gt;sorting options, number of results per page, and e-mail address.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;• APh Online has migrated to OpenURL 1.0 which facilitates rapid&lt;br /&gt;"clicking through" to an electronic version of modern scholarship cited&lt;br /&gt;in an APh record such as a full-text article in JStor.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;We are very grateful to the &lt;a href="http://www.mellon.org/"&gt;Andrew W. Mellon Foundation&lt;/a&gt; for its generous&lt;br /&gt;grant of $48,000 to support the planning of these upgrades, which were&lt;br /&gt;designed by Prof. Eric Rebillard, Director and Editor of APh Online,&lt;br /&gt;with input from Classics librarians and colleagues from the Cornell&lt;br /&gt;University Library.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I am also pleased to report that APA members can look forward to another&lt;br /&gt;major improvement in the near future.  The Mellon Foundation has just&lt;br /&gt;awarded the APA a major grant ($215,000) to create the Classical Works&lt;br /&gt;Knowledge Base (CWKB), a relational database and link resolver that will&lt;br /&gt;allow users of APh Online to "click through" from citations of ancient&lt;br /&gt;texts in an APh record to online versions of those texts, i.e., to do&lt;br /&gt;for ancient texts what is already possible for modern ones.  Prof.&lt;br /&gt;Rebillard will also direct this project in collaboration with Cornell&lt;br /&gt;librarians David Ruddy and Adam Chandler.  A fuller description of the&lt;br /&gt;project and a prototype can be found at &lt;a href="http://cwkb.org/"&gt;cwkb.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;And in the latest development, a planning grant from the &lt;a href="http://www.kressfoundation.org/"&gt;Samuel H. Kress&lt;br /&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt; has made it possible for Prof. Rebillard to begin exploring&lt;br /&gt;the possibility of linking from images cited in L'ANNÉE records to&lt;br /&gt;online versions of the images themselves.  I hope to have good news&lt;br /&gt;about this initiative by the end of my Presidency this Winter.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As the Director of the Database of Classical Bibliography project, which&lt;br /&gt;was completed last year, I am particularly pleased to see how the&lt;br /&gt;earliest CDROMs, published by the APA in the 1980's, have been&lt;br /&gt;transformed into an up-to-date, web-based resource for the 21st century.&lt;br /&gt;Members must understand that our ability to continue to bring this kind&lt;br /&gt;of major improvement to the field of Classics depends on the success of&lt;br /&gt;the current Gateway campaign.  If we cannot continue to operate the&lt;br /&gt;American Office of L'ANNÉE after the current NEH funding ends, we will&lt;br /&gt;be unable to influence the further development of this vital scholarly&lt;br /&gt;resource.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.apaclassics.org/campaign/campaign.html"&gt;Gateway campaign's Endowment for Classics Research and Teaching&lt;/a&gt; will&lt;br /&gt;be able to serve both immediate needs like those of the American Office&lt;br /&gt;and future needs that we cannot yet envision.  If you have not yet made&lt;br /&gt;a pledge to the Gateway campaign, it is very important that you do so&lt;br /&gt;now.  If you have already made a contribution, won’t you consider&lt;br /&gt;increasing it? Visit the APA web site (&lt;a href="http://www.apaclassics.org"&gt;www.apaclassics.org&lt;/a&gt;) and click on&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.apaclassics.org/supportAPA.html"&gt;Support APA&lt;/a&gt; at the top of the page to learn how to make your pledge&lt;br /&gt;either online or by mail.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Thank you very much for your attention to this message and for your&lt;br /&gt;support of the APA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dee L. Clayman&lt;br /&gt;President&lt;br /&gt;April 21, 2010&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;------------------&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;P.S.  The Winter 2010 Newsletter is now posted on the APA web site in&lt;br /&gt;two formats:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://webmail.uchicago.edu/wm/mail/fetch.html?urlid=g01a0cdeeaa4b73c9b7ab6cc4e15ae9016l1kkgahnl&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.apaclassics.org%2FNewsletter%2F2010newsletter%2F310news.html" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.apaclassics.org/Newsletter/2010newsletter/310news.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://webmail.uchicago.edu/wm/mail/fetch.html?urlid=g01a0cdeeaa4b73c9b7ab6cc4e15ae9016l1kkgahnl&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.apaclassics.org%2FNewsletter%2F2010newsletter%2F310news.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.apaclassics.org/Newsletter/2010newsletter/310news.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a name="data:post.title" id="data:post.url" onmouseover="'return" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onclick="return addthis_sendto()"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif" alt="Bookmark and   Share so Your Real Friends Know that You Know" style="border: 0pt none;" height="16" width="125" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/244695579768645979/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/lannee-philologique-update.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/244695579768645979"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/244695579768645979"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/lannee-philologique-update.html"
         title="L'ANNÉE PHILOLOGIQUE update"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
