<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7750476677460522448</id>
   <published>2013-11-06T19:00:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-11-06T19:09:51.123-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Classics"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Reception"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Practitioners' Voices in Classical Reception Studies</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 1 June 2010. Updated 6 November 2013] </span><br /><br /><a href="http://www2.open.ac.uk/ClassicalStudies/GreekPlays/Practitioners/index.htm">Practitioners' Voices in Classical Reception Studies</a><br />ISSN: 1756-5049<br /><div align="justify"><span style="font-size: 85%;"><i></i></span></div><blockquote><div align="justify"><span style="font-size: 85%;"><i>PVCRS </i>is  very much a companion publication  to our ejournal <i><a href="http://www2.open.ac.uk/ClassicalStudies/GreekPlays/newvoices/index.htm">New  Voices in Classical Reception Studies</a> </i> and our <a href="http://www2.open.ac.uk/ClassicalStudies/GreekPlays/e_archive/about.htm">Eseminar  Archive</a>. All add to the range of resources that are made freely  available on the Open University Reception of Classical Texts Research  Project website. <i>New Voices </i> provides a refereed platform for  newer researchers to publish their work. The Eseminar Archive makes  available the records of the annual seminar that discusses all aspects  of classical reception. <i>Practitioners' Voices </i> is a response to  the growing awareness that Classical Reception research has to  recognise the full range of processes that shape the impact of classical  material in new contexts. Its aim is to provide a Forum in which  theatre directors, designers, dramaturgs, actors, poets, translators,  and all involved in the creative  practices that are so crucial to  classical receptions can discuss the relationship between their work and  the classical texts, themes and contexts on which they draw. </span></div><div align="justify"><span style="font-size: 85%;">We hope that the Forum will also lead  to further dialogue between creative practitioners and critics and  academics (who are after all also practitioners). </span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">Special Issue 2013: Contemporary Women Writers</span></h1><span style="font-size: x-small;">                                                                                                                 </span></blockquote><div class="node " id="node-328"><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">      </span><div class="meta">      </div><span style="font-size: x-small;">  </span></blockquote><div class="content"><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">  </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="2013 banner" class="go1 border" height="220" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/hero_small/2013%20banner%203.png" title="2013 banner" width="935" /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/introduction">Introduction, by Fiona Cox and Elena Theodorakopoulos</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span lang="EN-US">This special issue of&nbsp;<i>Practitioners’ Voices in Classical Reception Studies</i>&nbsp;is a collection of conversations with women writers conducted&nbsp;</span><span lang="EN-US">over a period of around twelve months&nbsp;</span><span lang="EN-US">as&nbsp;</span><span lang="EN-US">part  of a research project on the significance of contemporary women’s  writing in the reception of classical myth and literature today.&nbsp;</span><span lang="EN-US">&nbsp;<strong><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/introduction">Read on</a></strong></span></span><br /> <br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Jane Alison" class="go1  border" height="112" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/Jane%20Alison_1.png" title="Jane Alison" width="88" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/332/">Jane Alison</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Jane Alison</b> is a novelist and university teacher, who studied Classics at Princeton  and Brown Universities, and Creative Writing at Columbia. Her first  novel <i>The Love Artist </i>(Farrar, Straus and Giraux) is an imaginary  evocation of Ovid’s exile, and has been translated into seven  languages. She has subsequently written <i>The Marriage of the Sea </i>(Farrar, Straus and Giraux, 2004) and <i>Natives and Exotics</i> (Harcourt, 2005)<i>. </i>Her most recent book is a memoir entitled <i>The Sisters Antipodes </i>(Houghton,  Mifflin and Harcourt, 2009). She teaches creative writing at the  University of Miami. This interview between Jane Alison and Fiona Cox  took place via e-mail during November 2012.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="" class="go1  border" height="106" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/tiffany%20pic.jpg" title="" width="159" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/337">Tiffany Atkinson</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><span lang="EN-US">Tiffany Atkinson</span></b><span lang="EN-US"> is a poet and literary critic. She is a senior lecturer at the  department of English and Creative Writing at Aberystwyth University.  Her poetry is published in journals and anthologies, including for  instance <i>Women’s Work: Modern Women Poets Writing in English</i> (ed. Amy Wack and Eva Salzman, Bloodaxe: 2010).&nbsp; <i>Catulla et al</i> (Bloodaxe 2011) was her second poetry collection, and was shortlisted  for the Wales Book of the Year Award 2012. She is also the editor of <em>The Body: A Reader</em> (Palgrave: 2004). Her third collection of poems, <i>So Many Moving Parts</i> will be published by Bloodaxe Books in January 2014. Atkinson read from <i>Catulla et al</i> and spoke about her poetry at a workshop on contemporary women’s  writing and classical reception held at the University of Exeter on 5  July 2012 with funds provided by the British Academy. A version of her  talk is published in <i>Essays and Studies</i> 2011 (<i>Essays and Studies Collected on behalf of the English Association</i>,  vol 64) as ‘Black and White and Re(a)d all over: the Poetics of  Embarrassment’.&nbsp; This conversation between Tiffany Atkinson, Fiona Cox  and Elena Theodorakopoulos, mainly about <i>Catulla et al</i>, took place on 6 July 2012 at the University of Exeter.</span></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Josephine Balmer" class="go1  border" height="112" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/Jo%20Balmer%20pic.JPG" title="Josephine Balmer" width="96" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/339">Josephine Balmer</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><span lang="EN-US">Josephine Balmer</span></b><span lang="EN-US"> is a poet, classical translator, scholar and literary critic, whose  work has appeared in numerous anthologies. She writes literary reviews  for a range of newspapers and journals, and was the reviews editor for <i>Modern Poetry in Translation</i> from 2004-2009. Her volumes of classical translation are: <i>Sappho: Poems and Fragments</i> (1984), <i>Classical Women Poets</i> (1996), and <i>Catullus: Poems of Love and Hate</i> (2004), all with Bloodaxe Books. Her poetry collections are <i>Chasing Catullus: Poems, Translations, and Transgressions</i> (2004), and <i>The Word for Sorrow</i> (2009). She has also written on classical translation for academic essay collections and journals, including most recently for <i>Classical Reception Studies Journal</i>. Her book for the <i>Classical Presences</i> series (OUP), <i>&nbsp;Piecing Together the Fragments: Translating Classical Verse, Creating Contemporary Poetry</i> is published in September 2013. This interview focuses substantially on <i>The Word for Sorrow</i>.  It is a conversation between Jo Balmer, Fiona Cox, and Elena  Theodorakopoulos and took place at the University of Birmingham on 12  December 2012, when Jo Balmer was a guest speaker at the Annual Meeting  of Postgraduates working in the Reception of the Ancient World.</span></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Elizabeth Cook" class="go1  border" height="112" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/EC%20high%20res%20jpg_1.jpg" title="Elizabeth Cook" width="75" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/335">Elizabeth Cook</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><span lang="EN-US">Elizabeth Cook</span></b><span lang="EN-US"> is a poet, fiction writer and scholar. She is the editor of <i>John Keats: The Major Works</i> (Oxford University Press, 1990), and has lectured in English literature. She wrote the libretto for Francis Grier’s oratorio <i>The Passion of Jesus of Nazareth</i> (2006). Her poetry collection <i>Bowl</i> was published by Worple Press (2006) and reprinted in 2013 (the title  poem was a Poem on the Underground). Her poetry, reviews, and other  writing have appeared in journals including <i>Poetry London</i> and <i>The London Review of Books.</i> She has translated Seneca’s <i>Thyestes</i>, a work whose keen urgency appeals. She is the author of <i>Achilles</i> (Methuen Press 2002), a fiction that also has a continuing performance  life at a variety of venues (it won a Fringe First Award at the  Edinburgh Festival and was performed by Greg Hicks at the National  Theatre).&nbsp; She is nearing completion of a novel, <i>Lux</i>, set in the  reign of King David and in sixteenth century England. Currently she is  Writer in Residence at St Edmundsbury Cathedral. This conversation  between Elena Theodorakopoulos and Elizabeth Cook took place at Cook’s  home in London on 6 December 2012.</span></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Marie Cosnay book" class="go1  border" height="112" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/Cosnay%20book.png" title="Marie Cosnay book" width="83" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/341">Marie Cosnay</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><span>Marie Cosnay</span></b><span> is a teacher, translator, and novelist. She currently works at the Collège </span><span lang="FR">François-Truffaut  de Saint-Martin-de-Seignanx. She is also a campaigner on behalf of  immigrants under threat of deportation. Among her many titles are the  novels <i>Noces de Mantoue </i>(Editions Laurence Teper, 2009), <i>Des Métamporphoses </i>(Cheyne, 2012), the translation <i>Ovide – d’Orphée à Achille </i>(NOUS, 2011) and non-fictional works such as <i>Comment on expulse – responsabilités en miettes </i>(Editions  du croquant, 2011), which employ classical allusions in order to  highlight the situation facing today’s immigrants within France. This  interview between Fiona Cox and Marie Cosnay took place via e-mail  during November 2012. Interview translated by Fiona Cox.</span></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div class="grid"><div class=" default"><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Marie Darrieusecq" class="go1  border" height="112" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/Marie%20Darrieussecq%20%C2%A9%20H%C3%A9l%C3%A8ne%20Bamberger.jpg" title="Marie Darrieusecq" width="75" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/330">Marie Darrieussecq</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span lang="FR">Marie Darrieussecq</span><span lang="FR"> is one of France’s leading contemporary writers. She came to fame in 1996 with the publication of <i>Truismes </i>(P.O.L., 1996) [trans. by Linda Coverdale as <i>Pig Tales</i>]. She has written numerous other novels - <i>Naissance des fantômes</i> (1998), <i>Le Mal de mer</i>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<i>Précisions sur les vagues</i> (1999), <i>Bref Séjour chez les vivants</i> (2001), <i>Le Bébé</i> (2002), <i>White</i> (2003), <i>Le Pays</i> (2005), <i>Zoo</i> (Nouvelles, 2006), <i>Tom est mort</i> (2007) and <i>Clèves</i> all published by P.O.L.&nbsp; She has also translated Ovid’s <i>Tristia </i>and <i>Epistulae ex Ponto,&nbsp;</i>producing a version entitled <i>Tristes Pontiques </i>(P.O.L., 2008)<i>.</i> This interview between Fiona Cox and Marie Darrieusecq took place on  June 8th, 2012 in London. Interview translated by Fiona Cox. <i>&nbsp;</i></span></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Barbara Köhler" class="go1  border" height="102" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/kohler_1.png" title="Barbara Köhler" width="159" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/342">Barbara Köhler</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><span lang="EN-US">Barbara Köhler</span></b><span lang="EN-US"> is a poet, essayist, and literary translator. Her prize-winning poetry collections include <i>Deutsches Roulette</i> (1991) and <i>Wittgenstein’s Nichte</i> (1999); she has also published literary translations of Samuel Beckett and Gertrude Stein. Her book <i>Niemands Frau, Gesänge zur Odyssee</i> (Suhrkamp 2007) is a response to the <i>Odyssey</i>. <i>Niemands Frau</i> was the subject of a symposium at St Hilda’s College Oxford in  September 2011. Since then Köhler has returned to the subject of the <i>Odyssey</i> in an essay published in <i>Neufundland</i> (Edition Korrespondenzen 2012) which also contains her new version of  Sappho frg.16. During 2012-13 she taught a seminar on the <i>Odyssey</i> at the University of Bonn where she was the Thomas-Kling-Poetikdozent.  In Spring 2013 she is Artist in Residence at the Institute for German  Cultural Studies at Cornell University where she is also teaching a  seminar on the <i>Odyssey</i> and its continued significance for modern poetry. The interview between Elena Theodorakopoulos and Barbara </span>Köhler <span lang="EN-US">took place at the author’s home in Duisburg, Germany on 25 February 2013. Translated by Elena Theodorakopoulos.</span></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Gwyneth Lewis" class="go1  border" height="112" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/GL%20Keith%20Morris.JPG" title="Gwyneth Lewis" width="75" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/344">Gwyneth Lewis</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><span lang="EN-US">Gwyneth Lewis</span></b><span lang="EN-US"> was the first National Poet of Wales in 2005-06. The six-foot high  words, in both Welsh and English on the front of the Wales Millenium  Centre in Cardiff are written by her. She has written non-fiction works  and librettos, and has held fellowships at Universities including  Harvard, Stanford and Cambridge. In 2010 she was awarded the  Cholmondeley Award by the Society of Authors in honour of her poetry.&nbsp; <i>Chaotic Angels</i> (Bloodaxe Books 2005) is a collection of her poems in English, but she  has written and published in both English and Welsh. Her most recent  poetry collection is <i>Sparrow Tree</i> (Bloodaxe Books, 2011) won the </span><span>Roland Mathias Poetry Award</span><span lang="EN-US">. She is also the author of <i>A Hospital Odyssey</i> (Bloodaxe Books, 2010), an epic poem set in a modern hospital. This  interview between Elena Theodorakopoulos, Polly Toney and Gwyneth Lewis  took place in November 2012 at the University of Birmingham.</span></span><br />  <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Alice Oswald Memorial" class="go1  border" height="112" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/Screen%20Shot%202013-08-14%20at%2023.44.57.png" title="Alice Oswald Memorial" width="71" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/oswald">Alice Oswald</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><span>Alice Oswald </span></b><span>is  a poet. She read Classics at Oxford, before training as a professional  gardener. Her poetry is infused with her responses to the natural world.  She won a Forward Poetry Prize for Best First Collection for <i>The Thing in the Gap-Stone Stile </i>in 1996, and the T.S. Eliot prize for <i>Dart </i>in 2002. In 2009 her volume <i>Weeds and Wild Flowers </i>won the Ted Hughes Award for New Work in Poetry. Her most recent book is the highly acclaimed <i>Memorial </i>(Faber, 2011), a work which she describes as an ‘excavation of the <i>Iliad</i>.’ Oswald recited from <i>Memorial </i>at a workshop on contemporary women’s writing and the classical tradition held at the University of Exeter on July 5<sup>th</sup> 2012 and funded by a British Academy small research grant. This  interview between Fiona Cox and Alice Oswald took place at Oswald’s home  on Remembrance Sunday, November 11<sup>th</sup>, 2012.</span></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Jo Shapcott" class="go1  border" height="112" src="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/files/arts-pv-pr/imagecache/feature_block/Shapcott%2C%20Jo_NEW2.jpg" title="Jo Shapcott" width="96" /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/348">Jo Shapcott</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><span>Jo Shapcott</span></strong><span> is a poet, editor and professor of creative writing. She has published many volumes of poetry, including <em>Electroplating the Baby</em><i> </i>(Bloodaxe, 1988) and <em>My Life Asleep</em><i> </i>(Oxford University Press, 1998). She is also the author of <em>Tender Taxes – Versions of Rilke’s French Poems</em><i> </i>(Faber, 2001). Her most recent poetry collection, <em>Of Mutability</em> (Faber, 2010) won the Costa Book of the Year Award. She was a contributor to <em>After Ovid – New Metamorphoses</em><i> </i>&nbsp;(Faber, 1994), and more recently contributed to <em>Metamorphosis – Poems Inspired by Titian</em><i> </i>(Yale  University Press, 2012). This interview between Fiona Cox and Jo  Shapcott took place at the Faber Offices in London on July 23, 2012.</span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />&nbsp;</span></div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Picture credits for the page: photograph of Jane Alison courtesy of  Steady70;&nbsp;photograph of Elizabeth Cook by Peter Everard  Smith;&nbsp;photograph of Marie Darrieusecq by Hélène Bamberger; photograph  of Barbara Köhler by Christiane Zintzen;&nbsp;photograph of Gwyneth Lewis by  Keith Morris; photograph of Jo Shapcott by Johnny Ring.&nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/2012">Issue 3 (2012)</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">featuring Christie Brown, Richard Shirley Smith, Marian Maguire, Robert Crawford, Norman McBeath and Craig Hamilton</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><div class="grid"><div class="feature-block ou-light-blue feature-block-link"><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/2010">Issue 2 (2010)</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">featuring Josephine Balmer,&nbsp;Maureen Almond, Oliver Taplin, Martin Wylde, Helen Eastman, Michael Ewans and Ian Ruffell.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br class="clear" /></span></div></div><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www8.open.ac.uk/arts/research/pvcrs/node/279">Issue 1 (2007)</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">featuring Dorinda Hulton,&nbsp;Jane Montgomery Griffiths, David Stuttard and David Fitzpatrick</span></blockquote></div></div><div style="text-align: center;">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div><div><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=116259103207720939" id="data:post.url" name="data:post.title" onclick="return addthis_sendto()" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onmouseover="'return"></a><br /><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7750476677460522448/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/open-access-journal-practitioners.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7750476677460522448"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7750476677460522448"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/open-access-journal-practitioners.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Practitioners' Voices in Classical Reception Studies"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
