<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-333344090200729066</id>
   <published>2011-01-24T11:48:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2011-01-24T11:48:29.785-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New (Partially) Open Access Journal:  Popular Archaeology</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.popular-archaeology.com/">Popular Archaeology</a><br /><blockquote><div id="logo"><a href="http://popular-archaeology.com/" title="popular archaeology"><img alt="popular archaeology" src="http://popular-archaeology.com/image/53997/popular-archaeology_com?max_width=600&amp;max_height=100" /></a>  </div><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: black;">Popular Archaeology magazine is a  100% online periodical dedicated to participatory, or public,  archaeology.&nbsp; Unlike most other major magazines related to archaeology,  no paper copies will ever be produced and distributed, so it will always  be "green", and it will always be less costly to produce and therefore  far less costly to purchase by premium subscribers (although regular  subscriptions are always free).&nbsp; Most of our writers and contributors  are either professionals or top experts in their fields, or are  individuals relating first-hand experiences; however, the magazine is  unique among other archaeology-related magazines in that it makes it  easy to invite and encourage members of the public (YOU) to submit  pertinent articles, blogs, events, directory listings, and classified  ads for publication.&nbsp; As a volunteer or student, do you have a  fascinating story to tell about an archaeological experience?&nbsp; As a  professional archaeologist, scholar, educator, or scientist, do you have  a discovery, program or project that you think would be of interest to  the world?&nbsp; Do you have an archaeology-related service or item for sale?  Would you like to have your archaeology-related blog post featured on  the front page? ( Ad and specially featured item prices are lower than  what you will find in any other major archaeology magazine).&nbsp; Through  Popular Archaeology, you can realize all of these things. Moreover,  because the content is produced by a very broad spectrum of  contributors, you will see more feature articles than what you would  typically find in the major print publications, with the same content  quality. &nbsp;&nbsp; </span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: black;">As a community of professionals,  writers, students, and volunteers, we invite you to join us as  subscribers in this adventure of archaeological discovery.&nbsp; It could  open up a whole new world for you.</span></span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><br /><br />See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div><div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /><a class="addthis_button" href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-edit.g?blogID=116259103207720939&amp;postID=6754506920629089811" title="data:post.title" url="data:post.url"><img alt="Bookmark and Share" height="16" src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/v2/lg-share-en.gif" style="border: 0pt none;" width="125" /></a></div><br /><br /><br /><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js#username=xa-4b4cc6be5f7e0135" type="text/javascript"></script></div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/333344090200729066/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/01/new-partially-open-access-journal.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/333344090200729066"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/333344090200729066"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/01/new-partially-open-access-journal.html"
         title="New (Partially) Open Access Journal:  Popular Archaeology"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
