<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6972049376819296728</id>
   <published>2013-06-07T09:17:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-06-07T09:17:28.896-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Reinhard on LAWDI</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[In the interest of promoting <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OM6XIICm_qo">Linked Open Data</a>, Punk Archaelogy, and recursion, I repost here the full text of Andrew Reinhard's contribution to Bill Caraher's blog <i><a href="http://mediterraneanworld.wordpress.com/">The Archaeology of the Mediterranean World</a> </i>recapitulating last week's<i> </i><a href="http://wiki.digitalclassicist.org/Linked_Ancient_World_Data_Institute">Linked Ancient World Data Institute.</a><br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2 class="entry-title"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://mediterraneanworld.wordpress.com/2013/06/06/linked-archaeology-is-punk-archaeology/">Linked Archaeology is Punk&nbsp;Archaeology</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">    </span><div class="date"><span style="font-size: x-small;">June 6, 2013 <a href="http://mediterraneanworld.wordpress.com/2013/06/06/linked-archaeology-is-punk-archaeology/#respond" title="Comment on Linked Archaeology is Punk Archaeology"><span class="sep">§</span> <span class="commentcount">Leave a Comment</span></a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">           </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Andrew Reinhard gives us the scoop on the punk mentality and linked data practices in archaeology.&nbsp;</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">So on Tuesday, <a href="http://mediterraneanworld.wordpress.com/2013/06/04/north-dakota-man-camp-project-update/">I had a sweet guest blogger and people really liked it</a>.  So when Andrew Reinhard (a punk archaeologist of the highest order)  wanted to post something here, I not only couldn’t say “no”, but I  couldn’t say YES fast enough. And when he wanted to talk about &nbsp;what he  learned at the Linked Ancient World Data Institute (#LAWDI), I was all  in.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">(This is the SECOND time in less than 6 months that I’ve been lucky  enough to introduce Andrew to the uninitiated (which I was as well about  8 months ago)).</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="Punk Archeology 49" border="0" height="300" src="http://mediterraneanworld.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/punk-archeology-49.jpg?w=450&amp;h=300" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="Punk Archeology-49.jpg" width="450" /><em>Punk Archaeology 2013. Photograph by Timothy Pasch.</em>&nbsp;</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">So here are Andrew Reinhard’s thoughts on linked archaeology and punk archaeology:</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">“The idea that there’s such a thing as ‘final publication’ of archaeological material is bullshit.”</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">I said this to a room full of colleagues all of whom had a stake in  the new-new thing: Linked Ancient World Data (or LAWD). The cool thing?  Nobody disagreed.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.neh.gov/divisions/odh/institutes/linked-ancient-world-data-institute">The Linked Ancient World Data Institute</a> (#lawdi) was an open source love-in funded by an NEH Digital Humanities  grant spread over two spring, 3-day sessions. The first session was  held in 2012 at the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World (<a href="http://isaw.nyu.edu/">ISAW</a>)  in New York City, and the second concluded this past Saturday, June  1st, at Drew University in Madison, New Jersey. LAWDI, the collective  brainchild of Sebastian Heath, Tom Elliott, and John Muccigrosso, was  created to bring together a diverse and progressive band of scholars,  librarians, and museum professionals of the ancient world, many of whom  were also technologists, to explore the nature of Linked Open Data (LOD)  as it relates to antiquity and how to share it across the Internet.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ours was a multinational, happy band, female and male, older and  younger, tool-builders and tool-users, some with projects completed, and  others with projects just underway, some facile with the finer points  of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Resource_Description_Framework">RDF</a> and <a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/rdf-sparql-query/">SPARQL</a>,  others not so much, yet all demonstrated good faith in the belief that  we could help each other learn. And link. There were no Luddites here.  There were only LAWDites.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Assaulted by unseasonable heat and humidity, we embraced “Digital  Humanities chic”—cargo shorts and tshirts, flip-flops and sandals. This  was Open Access fantasy camp fueled by coffee and alcohol. Run more like  a workshop than a formal conference, papers were replaced largely by  practice, jumping in feet first to understand what RDF is, what the  difference is between a URI and a URL, how to mint URIs, how to make  archaeological data discoverable and usable. “My data is your data, and  your data is my data,” Tom Elliott said in 2012.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">We followed the Freirean model of student-teachers and  teacher-students, each learning from the other. Numismatists like Andrew  Meadows and Ethan Gruber demonstrated the open data masterpiece that is  <a href="http://nomisma.org/">Nomisma.org</a>, while Dan Pett of the British Museum modeled his <a href="http://finds.org.uk/">Portable Antiquities Scheme</a> as a crowd-assisted project. Chuck Jones of the ISAW library discussed  its digital collection practices and followed up with an Open Access  tour de force via the <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/">Ancient World Online’s</a> collection of over 1,200 OA journals on antiquity worldwide. Eric Kansa demoed his <a href="http://opencontext.org/">OpenContext.org</a> site for hosting and sharing archaeological projects and there data.  Sebastian Heath and I attacked issues in archaeological publication from  two fronts, Heath by way of XML, HTML, and <a href="http://isaw.nyu.edu/publications/isaw-papers">ISAW Papers</a>, and me by way of making digital, linkable content available alongside traditional print publication.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Parts of each day were dedicated to “student” presentations, where  both nascent and established projects in linked archaeological data were  showcased, many of which came prepared with questions ranging from how  to prepare data for global consumption, to how to link to established  online geographical tools like<a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/"> Pleiades</a> and <a href="http://pelagios-project.blogspot.com/">Pelagios</a>,  and beyond. William Murray discussed his 3D project with ships’  battering rams used in the Battle of Actium. Rebecca Benefiel and Sara  Sprenkle presented their prototype of a new web application involving  the ancient graffiti of Pompeii. Katy Meyers argued for the need for  open data in bioarchaeological collections and mortuary site datasets to  avoid a sampling bias that limits interpretation of that data. There  were a dozen more presentations like these on interesting, useful  projects.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Each speaker came ready to share, ready to ask questions, and ready  to receive help. The spirit of LAWDI created an incredibly supportive  environment that allowed for free (and ego-free) dialogue about what to  do with archaeological data not just to bring it into the world,  rescuing it from inside a silo or behind a paywall, but also how to  connect with tools and websites already in use in order to make data on  anything from findspots to artifact types to cuneiform inscriptions more  open and more useful in ways the holders of that data might not have  even imagined.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Dinners and late-night hack-a-thons followed each day’s sessions,  with smaller groups spiralling off to attack specific problems of  ancient geography or naming authorities with code, or to discuss  problems of archaeological data in a more theoretical way, supplemented  with breaks in the action for air-guitar, rugby scores, and beer-runs.  By the end of the BBQ on the final day, our brains were beyond full, but  the inertia and creativity driven by the constant conversation carried  all of us home to immediately begin working on existing projects and the  next, new-new things for our respective disciplines.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">If the above doesn’t sound “punk-rock”, it should. We turned the  traditional conference structure on its ear and skanked on its head.  Most people in the room over those three days had already embraced the  DIY (do-it-yourself) attitude shared by all punks. If a tool doesn’t  exist, build it. If you have a question, ask it. If you can help  somebody, do it. The spirit of community was evident, and all LAWDites  formed a tight bond by the end with the sense that we’re all in this  together, and what we’re doing is for the greater good.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Many projects are either under-funded or are done for free,  hand-coded in basements late at night or early in the morning, at times  built with tools never intended for the purpose to which they were put. A  big part of Punk is making noise with the instruments you have,  learning by playing, and getting better by playing with others.  Creativity thrives when there’s no money, and the Punk attitude drives  us to find ways around these restrictions, often creating better, leaner  end-products than if we’d had a bottomless pool of resources, time, and  materials. We build because we have to. And we recognize the problems  inherent in ransomed scholarship and in the old ways of thinking about  archaeological data and how that data is/are made available. It’s Punk  to question authority. It’s Punk to question the establishment. It’s  Punk to question the status quo. We don’t do it to be subversive (most  of the time). We do it because we feel there is a better way to go about  the business of sharing information openly, and making that information  easily discoverable and hopefully easy to use. It’s not about the  money, and it’s not about the notoriety. But it is about the big picture  and how we want to see the world. We live in it, and therefore we have a  voice to change it if we want. That’s Punk. And that’s Linked Ancient  World Data.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">When I said that the concept of “final publication of archaeological  material” is “bullshit”, I meant it with every cell in my body.  Publication of archaeological data is the conversation-starter. While it  might mark the end of the push for tenure, or the conclusion of the  analysis of a pottery assemblage or hoard of coins, the publication  contains the synthesis and ideas of only one author (or perhaps a  handful). Who knows what other information can be gleaned by another set  of eyes, another brain. How can that data be re-assessed, re-mixed,  re-used, recycled? That questioning, that reconsideration is how we move  our field(s) forward, and is how science works (or is supposed to  work). And it’s also how Punk works. By checking our egos at the door  when we submit our research, we can engage in an open and constructive  dialogue with our current peers and those who come after, and our ideas  on the ancient world will become more focused and occasionally  overturned from those critical questions we weren’t afraid to ask.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Now that the Linked Ancient World Data Institute is formally complete  with both 3-day sessions behind us, all participants find themselves at  the vanguard of a Punk Archaeology movement. Join us online as part of  the Linked Ancient World Data Initiative. Details of more formal meetups  and hangouts, plus informal gatherings be they real or virtual, online  or in London or New York or elsewhere, will become available soon and  throughout the coming months. Better yet, don’t wait for these to  happen. Do it yourselves. Use the #lawdi hashtag on Twitter. Subscribe  to the Ancient World Online. Read the ISAW Papers. Google “Linked  Ancient World Data” or “LAWD” or “AWLD”. You’ll find us. Be a punk. Join  the initiative, and help create the new status quo of open, free, and  shared archaeological data.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">NOTE: I’ll update this post via the Comments area once the 2013 LAWDI  program is open, as well as the Twitter archive and collection of links  to get readers started.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Andrew</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="GOPR0155" border="0" height="337" src="http://mediterraneanworld.files.wordpress.com/2013/06/gopr0155.jpg?w=450&amp;h=337" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" title="GOPR0155.JPG" width="450" /></span><em><span style="font-size: x-small;">Andrew’s less mild-mannered persona. Photograph by Chad Bushy. </span></em></div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6972049376819296728/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/06/reinhard-on-lawdi.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6972049376819296728"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6972049376819296728"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/06/reinhard-on-lawdi.html"
         title="Reinhard on LAWDI"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
