<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5428434045437733549</id>
   <published>2012-06-22T10:17:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-06-22T10:17:24.876-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#"
             term="Center for Hellenic Studes"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Papurology"/>
   <title type="text">The Derveni Papyrus: An Interdisciplinary Research Project</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/cgi-bin/WebObjects/workbench.woa/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=2273"&gt;The Derveni Papyrus: An Interdisciplinary Research Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Editors : Leonard Muellner, G. Nagy, Ioanna Papadopoulou&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Information Architects: Saïd Esteban Belmehdi, Julien Razanajao, François Recher.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Over the last 45 years the text of the Derveni Papyrus has undergone  extensive reconstruction and study. Theokritos Kouremenos, George M.  Parássoglou, and Kyriakos Tsantsanoglou have been among the leaders of  this effort, publishing an authoritative text of the papyrus along with  extensive commentary in 2006 (Casa Leo S. Olschki, Firenze).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Introduction to the Text by K. Tsantsanoglou&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Derveni papyrus is a most interesting new document of&amp;nbsp; Greek  literature. It is perhaps the only papyrus to have been found on Greek  soil, and is, if not the oldest Greek papyrus ever found, no doubt the  oldest literary papyrus, dated roughly between 340 and 320 B.C. Its name  derives from the site where it was discovered, some six miles north of  Thessaloniki, in whose Archaeological Museum it is now preserved. It was  found among the remnants of a funeral pyre in one of the tombs in the  area, which has also yielded extremely rich artifacts, primarily items  of metalware. After the exacting job of unrolling and separating the  layers of the charred papyrus roll, and then of joining the numerous  fragments&amp;nbsp; together again, 26 columns of text were recovered, all with  their bottom parts missing, as they had perished on the pyre.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The book, composed near the end of the 5th century B.C., contains the  eschatological teaching of a mantis; the content is divided between  religious instructions on sacrifices to gods and souls, and allegorical  commentary on a theogonical&amp;nbsp; poem ascribed to Orpheus. The author’s  outlook is philosophical, displaying, in particular, a physical system  close to those of Anaxagoras, the Atomists, and Diogenes of Apollonia.  His allegorical method of interpretation is especially interesting,  frequently reminiscent of Socrates’ playful mental and etymological&amp;nbsp;  acrobatics as seen in Plato’s Cratylus. The identification of the author  is a matter of&amp;nbsp; dispute among scholars. Names like Euthyphron of  Prospalta, Diagoras&amp;nbsp; of Melos, and Stesimbrotus of Thasos have been  proposed with varying degrees of likelihood.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Digital edition of the Derveni Papyrus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;A few years ago The Center for Hellenic Studies made the Greek text  of the papyrus available online, as it was published in 2006, © Olschki,  Firenze.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The following key institutions worked in conjunction for this online project:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.olschki.it/"&gt;Casa Leo S. Olschki&lt;/a&gt;, Firenze, Italy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.unige.it/"&gt;Universita degli Studi di Genova&lt;/a&gt;, Italy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.auth.gr/home/index_en.html"&gt;Aristotle University of Thessaloniki&lt;/a&gt;, Greece&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amth.gr/en/info.html"&gt;Archaeological Museum of Thessaloniki&lt;/a&gt;, Greece&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/"&gt;Center for Hellenic Studies&lt;/a&gt;, Harvard University, USA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Continuing our effort to improve the digital edition of the Derveni  Papyrus, we developed a new form for the text under the framework of the  CHS-iMouseion Project. This user-friendly teaching and research tool  offers the option of masking or revealing the readings of the editors by  simply clicking on the text (wherever the arrow appears).  Furthermore,  one can easily navigate from one column to another, either successively  via the arrows or randomly via the sidebar menu. The iMouseion  architecture provides as well the possibility of a multiversion Derveni  Papyrus. Due to the existence of unplaced fragments, this exceptionally  challenging document is still being reconstructed. New reconstructions  can be displayed side by side, offering a simultaneous view of the  different versions of each column.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;As the study of the papyrus continues, the CHS Derveni Papyrus  Project team updates the content of this site. The CHS held a Conference  in July 2008. The Proceedings are now available here. Furthermore, we  are happy to announce the new edition of the first six columns by Franco  Ferrari, under the multiversion iMouseion environment, as well as the  articles and images which complete this new edition.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Read the Derveni Papyrus Online:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dp.chs.harvard.edu/index.php?col=1&amp;amp;ed=KPT"&gt;Editio princeps 2006&lt;/a&gt; (Olschki, Firenze)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dp.chs.harvard.edu/index.php?col=0&amp;amp;ed=Ftac"&gt;New Edition of columns I-VI by Franco Ferrari&lt;/a&gt;. Read F. Ferrari’s Introduction &lt;a href="http://dp.chs.harvard.edu/DP_FF_1_6.php"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dp.chs.harvard.edu/index.php?col=1&amp;amp;ed=multi"&gt;Multiversion&lt;/a&gt; (KPT-FF)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;And see &lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/09/open-access-publications-of-center-for.html"&gt;Open Access Publications of the Center for Hellenic Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5428434045437733549/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/06/derveni-papyrus-interdisciplinary.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5428434045437733549"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5428434045437733549"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/06/derveni-papyrus-interdisciplinary.html"
         title="The Derveni Papyrus: An Interdisciplinary Research Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
