<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4861929132658310347</id>
   <published>2011-09-05T11:10:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-09-05T11:10:25.092-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">JSTOR Hebrew Journals Pilot Project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://about.jstor.org/hebrew-journals-pilot-project">JSTOR Hebrew Journals Pilot Project</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Hebrew Journals Pilot Project is the result of an extensive collaboration with the&nbsp;<a href="http://lib.haifa.ac.il/">University of Haifa Library</a>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<a href="http://jnul.huji.ac.il/">National Library of Israel</a>&nbsp;to  digitize, test and make available the complete back runs of four core  journals published in Hebrew. This Pilot represents an effort to  preserve and expose these critical materials to a broader audience. The  University of Haifa has collaborated with the National Library of Israel  and other organizations in a set of projects to preserve and widely  disseminate scholarship in Hebrew, of which the Hebrew Journals Pilot  Project is one.</span><br /><h5>  <span style="font-size: x-small;">When and who can access these materials?</span></h5><span style="font-size: x-small;">All  institutions participating in JSTOR may sign up to access this Pilot  without fee, as part of their existing JSTOR access. Institutions may  write to&nbsp;<a href="mailto:support@jstor.org?subject=Hebrew%20Journals%20Pilot%20Project%20Interest">support@jstor.org</a>.  We'll reply with information about how to sign up.&nbsp;This material will  become available on JSTOR starting in Fall 2010. Once it is available,  we will contact all institutions who have expressed interested letting  them know they have access to these materials.</span><br /><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">Because of the  experimental and collaborative nature of this project, JSTOR will invite  all users of this content to share their feedback. We will take the  feedback we receive to help develop expertise and processes for  digitizing content in non-Roman languages, displaying journals in  non-right-to-left reading order, and understanding how JSTOR can be of  assistance to the scholarly community worldwide.</span></div><h5>  <span style="font-size: x-small;">Why a Hebrew Journals Project?</span></h5><span style="font-size: x-small;">This  project is first and foremost a collaboration between the University of  Haifa, the National Library of Israel and JSTOR to meet the needs of  scholars working throughout the world in Hebrew language scholarship. By  collaborating, the University of Haifa will gain expertise in creating  digital content, and JSTOR will gain vital knowledge as it works to  expand the range of languages represented on the JSTOR platform,  particularly through the experience the University shares through its  participation in other digitization projects in Hebrew.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  journals in the Hebrew Journals Pilot support JSTOR's and the University  of Haifa's shared goal of widening the scope of available materials in  JSTOR to support research and new scholarship. The University of Haifa  is working with the National Library of Israel to ensure that full back  runs of the digitized journals are preserved in print, while JSTOR will  serve as the stable platform for access.</span><br /><h5>  <span style="font-size: x-small;">What materials are available?</span></h5><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  University of Haifa identified four journal titles in Hebrew with  significant impact to scholars working in these representative fields  around the world. Placing these critical titles alongside the larger  JSTOR corpus offers the researcher a unique opportunity to leverage  their impact on scholarly research. These titles are strongly referenced  within existing JSTOR content and will provide a high value to  researchers and students alike.&nbsp;The four journal titles represented in  this pilot project span a range of disciplines, including Jewish  Studies, geography, history, sociology, and the social sciences. We are  delighted to have gained the support of the publishers of the following  four titles:</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.jstor.org/action/showPublication?journalCode=horigeog"><i>Horizons in Geography</i></a> -covering all aspects of geography in the Middle East and the greater  region, such as historical geography and physical geography.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.jstor.org/action/showPublication?journalCode=megamot"><i>Megamot</i></a> -dedicated to behavioral studies: psychology, sociology, social work, and related fields.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.jstor.org/action/showPublication?journalCode=tarbiz"><i>Tarbiz</i></a> - the leading Jewish Studies journal in Hebrew.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.jstor.org/action/showPublication?journalCode=zion"><i>Zion</i></a> -a widely used Hebrew periodical of history, published by the Historical Society of Israel</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  four titles are available to all Hebrew Journals Pilot participants.  Institutions may join the Hebrew Journals Pilot Project by contacting <a href="http://support@jstor.org/">support@jstor.org</a>. There is no additional cost to participate.&nbsp;</span><br /><h5>  <span style="font-size: x-small;">How will these journals be displayed on JSTOR?</span></h5><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  University of Haifa, with consultation from JSTOR, worked toward  creating digitized content in accordance with JSTOR's existing  production standards. As with all the journals on JSTOR, complete runs  will be displayed as faithful replications of the original print copies,  and users will be able to search and browse.</span><br /><h5>  <span style="font-size: x-small;">What makes this project a Pilot project?</span></h5><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  Hebrew Journal Pilot Project is a new endeavor for JSTOR. As such, we  are hoping to learn as much as possible from these collaborative  efforts. The purpose of the Pilot Project is to gather feedback on the  relevance of the content to researchers' needs and the quality of the  content and presentation. We hope to learn to improve these types of  facets in the future, but we need your feedback to do so. Your feedback  will be essential to helping us learn from this pilot and improve the  presentation of the content. We look forward to your comments!</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Institutions may sign up for the Hebrew Journals Pilot Project by contacting&nbsp;<a href="mailto:support@jstor.org?subject=Hebrew%20Journals%20Pilot%20Project%20interest">support@jstor.org</a>.</span></blockquote><br /><div style="text-align: center;">And see also<span style="font-weight: bold;"> </span><span style="font-family: 'PrimaSans BT,Verdana,sans-serif';"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/06/ancient-world-in-jstor.html">The   Ancient World in JSTOR</a>: AWOL's full list of journals in JSTOR with   substantial representation of the Ancient World.</span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4861929132658310347/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/jstor-hebrew-journals-pilot-project.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4861929132658310347"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4861929132658310347"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/jstor-hebrew-journals-pilot-project.html"
         title="JSTOR Hebrew Journals Pilot Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
