<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3568258277565843562</id>
   <published>2012-11-10T08:01:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2012-11-10T08:02:58.295-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Last House on the Hill: A New hybrid publication from the Cotsen Institute</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[From:<br /><div class="MsoNormal"><a href="mailto:wendrich@humnet.ucla.edu"><span style="font-family: &quot;Garamond&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 10.0pt;">Willeke Wendrich</span></a></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-family: &quot;Garamond&quot;,&quot;serif&quot;; font-size: 10.0pt;">Editorial Director Cotsen Institute of Archaeology Press</span></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">New hybrid publication from the Cotsen Institute of Archaeology Press,</span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">available at the AAA meetings this Fall: <a href="http://lasthouseonthehill.org/"><i>Last House on the Hill</i></a></span></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: justify;"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i><span style="background: none repeat scroll 0% 0% white;">Last House on the Hill</span></i><span style="background: none repeat scroll 0% 0% white;"> is a digital multigraph mirror of the <a href="http://unmpress.com/books.php?ID=20000000005615&amp;Page=book">printed monograph</a> of the same name.  The book and digital component comprise the final report of the  Berkeley Archaeologists at Çatalhöyük (BACH) project, in which  a team from the University of California at Berkeley excavated a group  of Neolithic 9000-year old buildings at this famous cultural heritage  location in Central Anatolia, Turkey. </span><span style="color: #272627;">By creating an on-line media- and data-rich edition of <i>Last House on the Hill</i>, we hope to keep alive, and open for  critique and further elaboration, the narratives about the archaeology,  history, cultural heritage, and memories of the BACH project. &nbsp;The  digital edition of <i>Last House on the Hill</i> is available as a “Cloud”-based database  running on your desktop and as an iPad application, which brings  together digital versions of the printed texts and authors’ supplemental  materials along with the full archaeological record.  The ambition of the digital edition of <i>Last House on the Hill</i> is  to embed, interweave, entangle, and otherwise link the complete project  database (including all media formats such as photographs, videos,  maps, line drawings as well as data analysis  and interpretation) with the final synthetic contents held in the  printed edition in an open access, sharable platform. It is an  open-ended data stream that can grow and—as long as it is well  curated—can live for many decades. Rather than building a repository  of content </span>that merely replicates in digital the fragmented nature of miscellaneous archives<span style="color: #272627;">,  we have worked to ensure that the on-line edition provides a  sustainable and extensible framework through which researchers,  visitors,  and future scholars can all make substantive contributions and that it  will serve as an engaging model for the digital publication of  archaeological content.</span></span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><br /></div><div class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: #272627;">An  essential information management challenge for a project of this  magnitude is how to make sense of such an enormity of information and  rich media. &nbsp;</span>Through the metaphor of  a strongly visual, web-like navigation through content, we provide an  interface to meaningful relations existing amongst the records and  different media collections that would otherwise remain unexplored, such  as who or what is represented in a photography,  drawing, or mentioned in a document.<span style="color: #272627;"> We  believe that the mass of archaeological documentation gains its full  significance for a study of the past if it is represented as the  relationships among people, places and things, their representation  through media, and the contingencies of time and space, all of which  contribute to the creation of the archaeological record. Thus, the  ultimate aim of the digital edition of <i>Last House on the Hill </i>is to have both archaeologists and a broader public be inspired to</span> track back from the “official” interpretation to the original<span style="color: #9900ff;"></span><span style="color: #272627;">data and media in order to download, recontextualize and remix them in creative and productive ways. </span>In the age of mobile computing, iPads, and Android  devices, there is an ever-increasing market pressure to provide  easy-to-use and powerful tools for self-expression (publishing), coupled  with robust digital asset management  and archiving through “cloud” computing. We are optimistic that these  market changes will continue to positively influence traditional  archives and publishers to reconsider what it means to be “done” with an  archaeological publication. </span></div><div class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />Further information about the Last House on the Hill project <a href="http://www.codifi.info/last-house-on-the-hill/">is available here</a><br /><br /><span style="color: #272627;"></span></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: #272627;">The book has been published by the Cotsen Institute of Archaeology Press and is distributed through UNM Press.</span></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3568258277565843562/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/11/last-house-on-hill-new-hybrid.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3568258277565843562"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3568258277565843562"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/11/last-house-on-hill-new-hybrid.html"
         title="Last House on the Hill: A New hybrid publication from the Cotsen Institute"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
