<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2991059502125210979</id>
   <published>2011-04-16T08:33:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-06-27T10:25:51.772-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Forthcoming Open Access Journal:  Egyptological</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.egyptological.com/">Egyptological</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">Egyptological is a new concept in archaeological publishing, which is  available free of charge to all readers.&nbsp; Part of the Egyptological  Online (E.O.) group of websites Egyptological was founded by Andrea  Byrnes and Kate Phizackerley in 2011.&nbsp; Our idea was to provide the first  free online-only Egyptology magazine which would provide our readers  with:</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A free-of-charge resource</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A diverse selection      of high quality material to reflect varied  levels of academic and popular interest, all subject to editorial review</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Research papers and popular articles</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Exhibition,      book, DVD and website reviews</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Conference reports</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Events and course calendars</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A regularly updated photograph gallery</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A platform for both new and existing writers to publish their material in a friendly      and helpful environment</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Assistance for      new writers if required</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">The opportunity      to join a community of like-minded people to  advance the spread of good      quality information about ancient Egypt</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">Egyptological covers all areas and periods of ancient Egyptian  prehistory up to and including the Coptic period. If you have an  interest in Ancient Egypt we hope that you will find articles,  exhibition, book and DVD reviews, and much more value-added content to  keep you entertained and informed.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Egyptological provides an environment for writers and researchers of  all levels of experience.&nbsp; It is divided into three main sections to  enable you to find the type of content that you are looking for:</span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.egyptological.com/journal" title="Journal">Journal</a>  features hand-picked research papers produced to academic standards and  subjected to a rigorous editorial review process which follows  guidelines for academic publications.&nbsp; Papers in Journal will usually  refelct the specialized research interests of the authors. </span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.egyptological.com/magazine" title="Magazine">Magazine</a>  publishes articles, book, television and DVD reviews and exhibtion and  conference reports.&nbsp; Articles tend to be several pages long and are  aimed at a wide audience.&nbsp; All articles are subject to editorial review. </span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.egyptological.com/colloquy" title="Colloquy">Colloquy</a>  is the place for short pieces, quick reviews and informal articles on a  vast variety of topics.&nbsp; There are also a frequently changing photo  album contributed by readers, events and courses listings and our  Discussion forum for asking questions, making suggestions and putting  forward ideas.&nbsp; This section will be updated on an ad hoc basis.&nbsp; Expect  to find a&nbsp; real mix of content here!</span></blockquote><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Each issue will include at least three major articles in the Journal  and Magazine sections with many more features and reviews to browse and  enjoy, which will be added to the website on a more regular and less  formal basis.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">Our editorial and technical staff are all volunteers, and our writers  all contribute articles free of charge. This enables us to operate both  the Editions and the Magazine section without advertising or other  commercial input.&nbsp; By accepting advertising in the Colloquy section we  are able to pay hosting and other costs whilst ensuring that the  magazine remains free of charge to all visitors.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">We very much hope that you enjoy Egyptological.&nbsp; Don’t forget to <a href="http://www.egyptological.com/about/founders/contact-general" title="Contact">get in touch</a> with us if you have any questions or ideas.</span></blockquote><blockquote>The first issue will appear on June 30, 2011.<br /><br /></blockquote><br /><div style="text-align: center;">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a>.</div><div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /><a class="addthis_button" href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-edit.g?blogID=116259103207720939&amp;postID=6754506920629089811" title="data:post.title" url="data:post.url"><img alt="Bookmark and Share" height="16" src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/v2/lg-share-en.gif" style="border: 0pt none;" width="125" /></a></div><br /><br /><br /><br /><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js#username=xa-4b4cc6be5f7e0135" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2991059502125210979/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/04/new-open-access-journal-egyptological.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2991059502125210979"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2991059502125210979"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/04/new-open-access-journal-egyptological.html"
         title="Forthcoming Open Access Journal:  Egyptological"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
