<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9188228193087139792</id>
   <published>2013-09-04T08:00:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-09-04T08:00:05.480-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Ceramics"/>
   <title type="text">Samian Research</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.rgzm.de/samian/home/frames.htm">Samian Research</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Website comprises a suite of  databases concerned with samian  ware. Their aim is to standardize the recording and publishing of samian  ware in such a way that the data is available both for comaparative  identification, and more significantly for scientific analysis using  statistical and mapping tools. All have their individual search masks  appropriate to the questions likely to require resolution. The databases  comprise the following:</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">- Names on samian ware<br />- Ovolo Vessels<br />- Name marked pots </span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">These databases have been developed historically as 'stand alone'  applications. At some future date it would be desirable to achieve a  complete cross-index, but this is beyond the current capacit y of the  contributors.</span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Names on samian ware</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">As a result of a co-operation agreement between the Universities of  Reading and Leeds together with the Römisch-Germanisches Zentralmuseum  Mainz, the life-löng  study madeby Brian Hartley and Brenda Dickinson of  the stamps and signatures on samian ware will also become available on  the database. This is published as a series of books (Institute of  Classical Sudies, London, from 2008 onwards), and replaces the <em>Index of Potters' Stamps</em> (Oswald, 1931). </span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ovolo vessels</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">This database is presently devoted to South Gaulish decorated samian  ware which has an ovolo. The illustrations of decorated ware have been  taken from scanned rubbings where possible, to ensure accuracy and a  fair representation of the condition of the vessel concerned. The  principles employed can be extended to other production centres when  specialists are available to enter the necessary data.</span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Name-marked vessels</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;"> These vessels carry either potters' stamps or signatures. Data  capture started with the name-marked decorated products of the South   Gaulish samian industry    of the first century AD., and has mainly come from the international  Pegasus    research group led by <a href="mailto:geoffrey.dannell@btinternet.com">Geoffrey Dannell, </a>and the work of <a href="mailto:%20mees@rgzm.de">Allard Mees</a> (Mees 1995). Additional materials came from the records of<a href="mailto:M.Polak@let.kun.nl"> Marinus Polak</a> (Radboud University Nijmegen), <a href="mailto:%20websterpv1@Cardiff.ac.uk">Peter   Webster</a> (Cardiff University) and   Alain Vernhet (CNRS Millau - F). The Lezoux archive of Brian Hartley  was added with the outstanding help of Robert Hopkins. Products from  Rheinzabern are currently being added, and it is hoped that the database  can be extended over time to include all of the other main production  centres of Gaul and Germany. </span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Restricted Access</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Some parts of this database have restricted access. In order to protect the commercial interests of the <a href="http://www.rgzm.de/Samian/Home/Books.htm">book publishers</a>,  data output of the Guest accounts may be limited by omitting fields  like images, dating and literature or are incomplete concerning the  number of output records.</span><br /> <h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Credits</span></h3><span style="font-size: x-small;">Without the help from Wendy and Robert Hopkins, Katja Hölzl and many others, these digitised versions of  hitherto scattered archives would not have been processed so rapidly.</span></blockquote><div class="ygtvitem" id="ygtv34"><table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" class="ygtvtable ygtvdepth0 ygtv-collapsed ygtv-highlight0" id="ygtvtableel34"><tbody><tr class="ygtvrow"><td class="ygtvcell ygtvlp" id="ygtvt34"><br /></td><td class="ygtvcell ygtvhtml ygtvcontent" id="ygtvcontentel34"><br /></td></tr></tbody></table></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9188228193087139792/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/09/samian-research.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9188228193087139792"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9188228193087139792"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/09/samian-research.html"
         title="Samian Research"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
