<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2659302436246444636</id>
   <published>2012-06-19T09:24:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-06-19T09:25:05.750-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#"
             term="American School of Classical Studies at Athens"/>
   <title type="text">Open Linked Hesperia Bibliographic Citations</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 class="headline" style="font-weight: normal; margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"> <a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/news/newsDetails/hesperia-bibliographic-citations-now-on-zotero"><span style="font-size: small;">Hesperia Bibliographic Citations Now on Zotero</span></a></h2><i><i>by Andrew Reinhard</i></i><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Bibliographic citation data for 1,500+ <i>Hesperia</i> articles are now freely available on the <a href="http://www.zotero.org/">Zotero</a> platform. Zotero is a widely used, open bibliography tool that helps  scholars collect, organize, cite, and share research sources.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Researchers who use Zotero while writing articles and books that reference <i>Hesperia</i> articles can download citation data by visiting the <a href="https://www.zotero.org/groups/american_school_of_classical_studies_at_athens">ASCSA’s group page</a>. You can choose to browse the collection of articles from 1932 to 2012 by <a href="http://bit.ly/KBGTmR">volume year</a>, or you can search with keywords across <a href="http://bit.ly/L5Dfo6">all articles</a>.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> When you find a citation you need, you can download that data to your  own collection of research bibliography. Zotero will automatically  format it in the style of your choice (e.g., Chicago Manual of Style).  Citation data include article title/subtitle, author, abstract,  volume/issue/page numbers, and publication date.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> For those researchers with access to JSTOR, Zotero citation entries for <i>Hesperia</i> also contain links to the articles themselves. Once older volumes of <i>Hesperia</i> (1932–2009) become available online for free later this year, these links will be updated to point to the ASCSA’s website.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> ASCSA monographs are also on Zotero in the <a href="http://bit.ly/M6QhyU">“ASCSA Books” collection</a>,  organized by series (e.g., Corinth, Isthmia). This is a work in  progress, with about 70 more books to be added to complete the open  bibliography of all ASCSA publications.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Although most books and all <i>Hesperia</i> citation data are now  online and ready to use, there is still work to be done to make this  content more discoverable by researchers. Tagging is the most important  task remaining. All books and some articles need to be tagged with  keywords pertaining to their content (e.g., “sigillata,” “Pylos,”  “dentition,” etc.). Tagging citations with keywords will allow scholars  to find bibliography more easily as they research and write their own  articles and books.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> ASCSA staff, members, and alumni can help complete the tagging project by creating a free <a href="http://www.zotero.org/">Zotero</a> account and requesting access to the American School of Classical Studies at Athens <a href="https://www.zotero.org/groups/american_school_of_classical_studies_at_athens">group page</a>. Once admitted, you’ll be able to add tags to any <i>Hesperia</i> articles.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> For questions about ASCSA citation data on Zotero or on how to use this  open bibliography research tool, please contact Andrew Reinhard,  Director of Publications, at <a href="http://draft.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=116259103207720939">areinhard@ascsa.org</a>.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2659302436246444636/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/06/open-linked-hesperia-bibliographic.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2659302436246444636"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2659302436246444636"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/06/open-linked-hesperia-bibliographic.html"
         title="Open Linked Hesperia Bibliographic Citations"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
