<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2165475210426686650</id>
   <published>2013-02-08T14:25:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-02-08T14:25:25.270-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Classics"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="open access"/>
   <title type="text">APA Statement on Open Access to Scholarly Publishing in the UK</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://apaclassics.org/index.php/apa_blog/apa_blog_entry/apa_statement_on_open_access_to_scholarly_publishing_in_the_uk/">APA Statement on Open Access to Scholarly Publishing in the UK</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Open Access (OA) to Scholarly Publishing in the UK<br /> </strong>Comments submitted by<br /> <strong>The American Philological Association </strong>(<strong>APA</strong>)<br /> Denis Feeney, President (dfeeney@princeton.edu)<br /> Michael Gagarin, Vice President for Publication and Research (gagarin@austin.utexas.edu)<br /> <br /> The APA, the principal learned society representing scholars and  teachers of Classics located primarily in the US and Canada, is strongly  committed to OA as a goal for all publication and research in the area  of Classics. We recognize, however, that the move to OA raises complex  and difficult issues, and we thus welcome the proposals made in the  Finch Report to address these issues, many of which would be positive  steps in the direction of OA. At the same time, the Finch report raises  some significant concerns, which in our view must be addressed in any  plan for implementing their recommendations. Many of these stem from the  fact that the report views OA primarily as it affects medical and  scientific research. Because conditions affecting the social sciences  and humanities differ in several significant respects, we are concerned  about the negative effects on research in Classics in the US and abroad.<br /> <br /> 1. Most research in Classics is single-author, and either is not funded  or is funded by grants or fellowships that only provide relief from  teaching; this leaves no consistent funding for author publishing  charges (APCs). Requiring researchers to pay to have their work  published would seriously burden those who are poor or not connected to a  well-endowed institution; any system that favors the rich could  significantly reduce the quality of journal publications.<br /> <br /> 2. Publication in the form of monographs or collections of essays is  much more important in the social sciences and humanities than in the  sciences. In Classics in particular, the proliferation of essay  collections in the last few decades has meant that many senior scholars  -- those with the best access to APC funds -- rarely if ever publish in  refereed journals. Journals would therefore be left to recover the costs  of publishing almost entirely from younger scholars, who are least able  to pay.<br /> We mention as a footnote that an experiment, funded by the Mellon  Foundation, is underway in the US for an OA monograph series; it is too  early to predict the results.<br /> <br /> 3. Classics, like many humanistic fields, is broadly international;  indeed a good many APA members are housed in other countries, including  the UK. Many journals publish articles in more than one language and  scholars everywhere publish their work with presses and journals in many  other countries. Any movement to OA in the UK alone, especially if a  requirement for OA is included in future Research Assessments, would  restrict the ability of UK scholars to have their work published, reduce  the submission of papers to UK journals by non-UK scholars, and  discourage journals in other countries from publishing the work of UK  scholars. The harm done to the international exchange of ideas in  Classics would be notable.<br /> <br /> 4.For all of these reasons, we strongly support the Conclusion of the  British Academy's submission to the House of Lords Select Committee,  that the special circumstances of the humanities and social sciences be  particularly considered in planning the implementation of the proposed  OA policies. </span></blockquote><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-size: small;">&nbsp;This is the text of the<span style="font-size: small;"> </span></span></span><a href="http://apaclassics.org/index.php/apa_blog/apa_blog_entry/apa_statement_on_open_access_to_scholarly_publishing_in_the_uk/">APA Statement.</a> I encourage you to read the original where the statment is contextualized.&nbsp; There is no coment function evident on the APA blog but those who wish to comment may do so here.]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2165475210426686650/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/02/apa-statement-on-open-access-to.html#comment-form"
         title="2 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2165475210426686650"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2165475210426686650"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/02/apa-statement-on-open-access-to.html"
         title="APA Statement on Open Access to Scholarly Publishing in the UK"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
