<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8770335455917750002</id>
   <published>2013-07-22T15:30:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-07-22T15:53:07.797-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Enkomi"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Cyprus"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">Enkomi Digitisation Project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="prefaces-0 clearfix" id="preface-wrapper"><div style="text-align: left;"></div><div id="mission"><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 28 June 2011. Updated 22 July 2013] </span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.enkomicm.org/digitisation-artefacts-enkomi-tombs">Enkomi Digitisation Project: The Digitisation of the Artefacts of the Enkomi tombs</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.enkomicm.org/sites/default/files/acquia_marina_logo.png" class="decoded" src="http://www.enkomicm.org/sites/default/files/acquia_marina_logo.png" /> </blockquote></div><div style="text-align: left;"><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>The Digitisation of the Artefacts of the Enkomi tombs (British Excavations) in the Cyprus Museum </b></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">  Dr. Despo Pilides, Curator of Αntiquities, Department of Antiquities, Cyprus</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span>  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>The Project</b></span> <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The idea for the proposal of this assignment was triggered by the  corresponding project undertaken by the Greek and Roman Department of  the British Museum, which consisted partly of the digitization of the  material excavated by the British at Enkomi as part of the Turner  Bequest excavations from 1894 to 1896. The Cyprus Museum objects from  these excavations and the digitization of this material will provide a  link and ultimately unite the two databases, thus reconstituting, to the  extent possible, the contents of the tombs.</span> </blockquote><blockquote><div></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">  The proposal was submitted and approved by the Promotion Foundation for  Research in 2008. Its duration of 24 months (from January 2009 to  December 2010) involved archival research concerning the excavations of  one hundred tombs of the Late Bronze Age, of considerable wealth,  excavated in 1896 and published in 1900. Two thirds of the objects were  transferred to the British Museum as per the terms of the Antiquities  Law at the time which allowed the excavator, the owner of the land and  the Government a share of one third each of the total number of objects  found.&nbsp; The excavators usually bought the land and were, therefore,  granted two thirds of the finds. The Cyprus Museum share was kept in the  old premises at Victoria Street. It was then transferred to the new  Cyprus Museum, around 1909 and was given new accessory numbers.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">  The programme is a collaborative effort between the Department of  Antiquities, the Open University of Cyprus and the British Museum. Its  implementation will ensure the preservation of the collection, it will  provide accessibility to objects belonging to the so-called “old  collection” in the Cyprus Museum store rooms and consequently facilitate  research. Furthermore, it will promote the use and application of  statistical and analytical techniques for archaeological data and will  give the opportunity to educational institutions to use it as a teaching  aid.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><br /><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">  Having in mind that Enkomi is located in the occupied part of Cyprus  and that the material of the excavations from the site, initiated at the  end of the 19th century, is dispersed in different museums of the  world, the digitisation of its material is of primary importance. The  project may act as a precedent in bringing together dispersed material  from the same sites, located in different museums and obstructing a  holistic view of those sites. It constitutes the first organised attempt  to create a database of antiquities kept in the Cyprus Museum, and the  first attempt to transmit data and information through the internet, and  via a collaboration between major institutions.</span></div><ul class="menu"><li class="leaf first dhtml-menu  active-trail"><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a class="active" href="http://www.enkomicm.org/digitisation-artefacts-enkomi-tombs" id="dhtml_menu-1907-1">The project</a></span></li><li class="dhtml-menu collapsed start-collapsed "><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://www.enkomicm.org/tombs" id="dhtml_menu-1880-1" title="">Tombs</a></span></li><li class="dhtml-menu collapsed start-collapsed "><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://www.enkomicm.org/object-types" id="dhtml_menu-1754-1" title="">Object types</a></span></li><li class="leaf  dhtml-menu "><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://www.enkomicm.org/sitemap" id="dhtml_menu-2188-1" title="Display a site map with RSS feeds.">Site map</a></span></li></ul></blockquote></div></div></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8770335455917750002/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/06/enkomi-digitisation-project.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8770335455917750002"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8770335455917750002"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/06/enkomi-digitisation-project.html"
         title="Enkomi Digitisation Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
