<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2017436921866171983</id>
   <published>2014-01-18T15:00:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2014-01-18T15:37:46.255-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Classics@</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;span class="title"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;[First posted in AWOL &lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/11/more-open-access-journals.html"&gt;1/11/2009&lt;/a&gt;, most recently updated 18 January 2014]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=1167"&gt;&lt;span class="title"&gt;Classics@&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;img alt="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/dImage?bdco=472&amp;amp;bdc=12" src="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/dImage?bdco=472&amp;amp;bdc=12" height="47" width="400" /&gt;&lt;span class="title"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;table align="left" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" id="two-col-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id="left-cell" style="vertical-align: top;"&gt;&lt;div class="body"&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Classics@&lt;/i&gt;,  edited by a team working for the Center for    Hellenic Studies and  headed by Gregory Nagy and James O'Donnell, is    designed to bring  contemporary classical scholarship to a wide audience    on the World  Wide Web. Each issue will be dedicated to its own topic,    often with  guest editors, for an in-depth exploration of important    current  problems in the field of Classics. We hope that &lt;i&gt;Classics@&lt;/i&gt; will  appeal not only to professional classicists, but also to the     intellectually curious who are willing to enter the conversation in our     discipline. We hope that they find that classical scholarship engages     issues of great significance to a wide range of cultural and  scholarly    concerns and does so in a rigorous and challenging way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Each issue of &lt;i&gt;Classics@&lt;/i&gt; is meant to be not static but  dynamic, continuing to evolve with    interaction from its readers as  participants. New issues will appear    when the editors think there is  good material to offer. Often it will    emphasize work done in and  through the Center for Hellenic Studies, but    it will also call  attention to fresh and interesting work presented    elsewhere on the  web. It stresses the importance of    research-in-progress, encouraging  collegial debate (while discouraging    polemics for the sake of  polemics) as well as the timely sharing of    important new information&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 11&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=5139"&gt;Issue 11: The Rhetoric of Abuse in Greek Literature&lt;/a&gt;.  This volume grew out of the need for a venue in which to engage  collaboratively on the topic of abuse. Abuse has of course been widely  studied, and in the last few years there has been a renewed interest in  abuse as a broader cultural and literary phenomenon, but there are  reasonable restrictions as to how it has been addressed. One goal of  this volume is to initiate a scholarly discussion that will allow  greater heterogeneity in the material covered and in the theoretical  models brought to bear on that material. Another is to encourage  experimentation and collaborative exchange among scholars working in  seemingly unconnected fields. Most importantly, perhaps, we would like  to foster a deeper understanding of the role of abuse in all of Greek  literature, across genres and time periods, through the kind of  cumulative knowledge that comes from collaborative work in different  fields.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 10&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=4871"&gt; Issue 10: Historical Poetics in Nineteenth and Twentieth Century Greece: Essays in Honor of Lily Macrakis&lt;/a&gt;.  History needs art to give it form; art needs history to give it  resonance. This relationship of history and art is the theme of the  essays by distinguished international scholars collected in this volume.  Its publication celebrates the career and work of Professor Lily  Macrakis. She is an eminent chronicler of modern Greek history whose  seminal work, &lt;em&gt;Venizelos: A Study in Cretan Leadership&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;,  remains essential to an understanding of the most influential Greek  leader of the 20th century. Among her other accomplishments, Professor  Macrakis was president of The Modern Greek Studies Association from 1977  to 1979 and has been an influential figure in the organization since  its inception. Equally significant has been her role as a devoted  teacher of Greek history and culture to multitudes of students.  Professor Macrakis thus truly embodies the spirit and significance of  the articles presented in this Festschrift so fittingly dedicated to  her.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=4026"&gt;Issue 9: Defense Mechanisms in Interdisciplinary Approaches to Classical Studies and Beyond&lt;/a&gt;.  Nowadays people speak of “defense mechanisms” as both negative and  positive forms of behavior: examples of negative forms are denial,  repression, acting out, projection, rationalization,  intellectualization, while one of the few positive forms is assertion, a  way of responding that takes the middle ground between aggressive and  passive. In the spirit of this positive form of assertion and in both  technical and non-technical senses of the expression “defense  mechanisms,” the present issue of Classics@ has been given its title.  The aim is to publish online research papers and essays in Classics and  in other disciplines, related or unrelated, that explore strategies  where the primary purpose is to defend assertively rather than attack.  The justification is straightforward: discoveries and discovery  procedures in research require and deserve a reasoned defense.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 8: A Homer commentary in progress, eds. D. Frame, L. Muellner, and G. Nagy (coming soon)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 7&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=3369"&gt;Issue 7: Les femmes, le féminin et le politique après Nicole Loraux, Colloque de Paris (INHA), novembre 2007&lt;/a&gt; is the result of a conference held in Paris (INHA, 15–17 November 2007)   which was co-organized by the Centre Louis Gernet (CNRS-EHESS), the  Équipe Phéacie (Université Paris I Panthéon-Sorbonne and Université  Denis-Diderot Paris VII) and the Réseau National Interuniversitaire sur  le Genre (RING, Paris). The aim of the conference was to explore Nicole  Loraux’s legacy concerning the feminine and the &lt;em&gt;polis&lt;/em&gt; both in Hellenic Studies and in feminist scholarship.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=3232"&gt;Issue 6: Reflecting on the Greek Epic Cycle&lt;/a&gt; is the result of a conference held in Ancient Olympia on 9–10 July  2010, which was co-organized by the Center for Hellenic Studies (Harvard  University) and the Centre for the Study of Myth and Religion in Greek  and Roman Antiquity (University of Patras). The goal of the conference  was to explore problems concerning the surviving fragments of the Greek  Epic Cycle that have heretofore been neglected. Guest Editor: Efimia D.  Karakantza.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=2653"&gt;Issue 5: Proceedings of the Derveni Papyrus Conference&lt;/a&gt; reflects a three-day symposium on the Derveni Papyrus hosted by the  Center for Hellenic Studies in July, 2008, on the occasion of the recent  publication of the edition by Theokritos Kouremenos, George M.  Parássoglou, and Kyriakos Tsantsanoglou (Florence, Olschki, 2006; the  text of the papyrus from that edition is available on this website &lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=2273"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).  The symposium was an opportunity to gather scholars who in the course  of the past decades have been working on this text to address a set of  issues relating to the edition and integration of the papyrus, its  translation, and its interpretation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div class="body"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=3534"&gt;Issue 4: The New Sappho on Old Age: Textual and Philosophical Issues&lt;/a&gt; is the online edition of a print volume published by the Center for  Hellenic Studies in 2009 (available through Harvard University Press, &lt;a href="http://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?recid=29507"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;).  This volume is the first collection of essays in English devoted to  discussion of the newly-recovered Sappho poem and two other incomplete  texts on the same papyri. Containing eleven new essays by leading  scholars, it addresses a wide range of textual and philological issues  connected with the find. Using different approaches, the contributions  demonstrate how the "New Sappho" can be appreciated as a gracefully  spare poetic statement regarding the painful inevitability of death and  aging. Guest Editors: Ellen Greene and Marilyn B. Skinner.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=1307"&gt; Issue 3: The Homerizon: Conceptual Interrogations in Homeric Studies&lt;/a&gt; is the result of a colloquium held at the Center. The colloquium had as     its goals the serious interrogation of cherished assumptions about     Homeric “culture” and “texuality”; and the exploration of the wider     cultural significance of the perennial Homeric Question(s).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=1324"&gt; Issue 2: Ancient Mediterranean Cultural Informatics&lt;/a&gt;.  The second issue of    Classics@ is the first edition of an ongoing  project of    publication aimed at documenting this emerging  sub-discipline of our    field, the scholarship of creating, analyzing,  and disseminating    humanist learning electronically. This issue  features articles    describing these projects and others like them —  new work of high    quality that is expanding the depth and breadth of  our field. It also    looks back at the history of this sub-discipline,  and forward toward    emerging standards, tools, and potentials. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Issue 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;amp;bdc=12&amp;amp;mn=1341"&gt;Issue 1: New Epigrams Attributed to Posidippus    of Pella&lt;/a&gt;.  Editors: Gregory Nagy and James O'Donnell. Guest Editors of    Issue  One: Benjamin Acosta-Hughes, Elizabeth Kosmetatou, Martine Cuypers, and  Francesca Angiò.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: right;"&gt;See the full &lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html"&gt;List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td id="right-cell" style="vertical-align: top;"&gt;&lt;table border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" id="sidebar-table"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td id="sidebar-cell"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2017436921866171983/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/08/open-access-journal-classics.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2017436921866171983"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2017436921866171983"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/08/open-access-journal-classics.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Classics@"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
   <georss:featurename>Washington, DC 20008, USA</georss:featurename>
   <georss:point>38.9451658 -77.0622028</georss:point>
   <georss:box>38.9204668 -77.1016848 38.969864799999996 -77.02272079999999</georss:box>
</entry>
