<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5833345455657350631</id>
   <published>2009-11-30T10:09:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2012-02-15T15:48:35.036-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Eleven More Open Access Journals</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://capra.group.shef.ac.uk/index.html">Cave Archaeology And Palaeontology Research Archive</a><br />ISSN <a class="libx-autolink" href="http://getit.library.nyu.edu/resolve?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:journal&amp;__char_set=utf8&amp;rft.issn=1467-8837&amp;rfr_id=info:sid/libx&amp;rft.genre=journal&amp;sfx.ignore_date_threshold=1" style="border-bottom: 1px dotted;" title="libx-autolink">1467-8837</a><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;">Published is the journal <a href="http://www.heritage.g/sizveleni_e.html">"Georgian Antiquities"</a>, in collaboration with G. Chubinashvili Institute                of History of Georgian Art of the Academy of Sciences of Georgia.                Its editorial board comprises Western and Georgian specialists.                The journal presents: new publications, documentation and photographs,                schemes, etc. on unknown or forgotten monuments; new interpretation                of the known monuments or phenomena; significant unpublished archival                material, etc. The journal is issued quarterly in Georgia, once                a year the whole material is published in English. Editors of the                journal will be pleased to receive articles from the Western scholars                on diverse aspects of the Near Eastern, Western European and Georgian                art.</span></blockquote><br /><a href="http://www.envarch.net/publications/circaea/index.html">CIRCAEA The journal/Bulletin of the Association for Environmental Archaeology</a> (1983-1996). It was superceded in 1997 by the journal, <a href="http://www.envarch.net/publications/envarch/index.html" style="font-style: italic;">Environmental Archaeology: The journal of human palaeoecology</a>.<br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;">The AEA promotes the advancement of the study of human interaction with the environment in the past through archaeology and related disciplines. We hold annual conferences and other meetings, produce a quarterly newsletter for members, and publish our conference monographs, as well as our journal - Environmental Archaeology: The journal of human palaeoecology. AEA membership is open to all those actively involved or interested in any aspect of environmental archaeology.</span></blockquote><a href="http://www.heritage.ge/sizveleni_e.html">Georgian Antiquities - Sakʻartʻvelos siżveleni</a><br /><span style="font-family: Times New Roman,Times,serif;"><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-family: Times New Roman,Times,serif;"><span style="font-size: 85%;">Georgian              Cultural Heritage Information Centre (GCHIC) is a Non-Governmental              Organisation aimed at obtaining and keeping archive of the qualified              information on diverse branches of the Georgian cultural heritage,              as well as ensuring accessibility and availability of this information              through scholarly and popular publications, exhibitions, electronic              network, etc. GCHIC organises research-recording expeditions throughout              Georgia and to the Georgian cultural heritage sites abroad; processes              information based on typology, chronology, geography - in the form              of ID cards, lists, annotations, etc.; disseminates information on              the site facing the danger of vanish or damage; ensures protective              measures on the unique and endangered heritage sites; supports interested              individuals (teams) and professionals in obtaining better knowledge              on significant well-known as well as less-known Georgian cultural              heritage sites</span></span></blockquote><span style="font-family: Times New Roman,Times,serif;"><br /></span><a href="http://www.heroicage.org/">The Heroic Age. A Journal of Early Medieval Northwestern Europe</a><br />ISSN 1526-1867<br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"><i></i></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;"><i>The Heroic Age</i> is dedicated to the exploration all aspects of early medieval Northwestern Europe, from a variety of vantage points and disciplines from the beginning of the fourth century through the beginning of the thirteenth.   By bringing various points of view to the table, we hope to open new vistas of investigation and strengthen ties among early medieval studies and its popular bases.  The title "Heroic Age" is applicable to literary, historical, folkloric studies and the material culture that lies behind the people who lived, wrote, and championed their beliefs and created cultures in the period.  We will strive to understand and promote understanding of  this dynamic early medieval period.</span></blockquote><br /><a href="http://www.herculaneum.ox.ac.uk/?q=newsletters">Herculaneum Archaeology</a>. (The Friends of Herculaneum Society)<br /><a href="http://www.ub.uni-heidelberg.de/helios/fachinfo/www/arch/hephaistos/Hephaistos.html"><br />HEPHAISTOS: New Approaches in Classical Archaeology and related Fields / Kritische Zeitschrift zu Theorie und Praxis der Archäologie und angrenzender Gebiet</a>e<br />ISSN <a class="libx-autolink" href="http://getit.library.nyu.edu/resolve?url_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info:ofi/fmt:kev:mtx:journal&amp;__char_set=utf8&amp;rft.issn=0174-2086&amp;rfr_id=info:sid/libx&amp;rft.genre=journal&amp;sfx.ignore_date_threshold=1" style="border-bottom: 1px dotted;" title="libx-autolink">0174-2086</a><br /><br /><a href="http://www.swanet.org/zarchives/aahs/">GLYPHS: The Monthly Newsletter of the Arizona Archaeological and Historical Society, An Affiliate of the Arizona State Museum, University of Arizona</a><br /><br /><a href="http://orissa.gov.in/e-magazine/Journal/JournalMain.htm">The Orissa Historical Research Journal</a><br /><br /><a href="http://www.le.ac.uk/has/ps/past/past.html">Past:  The Newsletter of The Prehistoric Societ</a>y<br /><br /><br /><a href="http://www.prehistoricsociety.org/publications/reviews/">The Prehistoric Society:  Book Reviews</a><br /><br /><a href="http://www.swanet.org/zarchives/urara/">Vestiges.  The monthly Newsletter of URARA, the Utah Rock Art Research Association</a><br /><br />See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5833345455657350631/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/11/eleven-more-open-access-journals.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5833345455657350631"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5833345455657350631"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/11/eleven-more-open-access-journals.html"
         title="Eleven More Open Access Journals"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
