<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7813010385594992633</id>
   <published>2013-09-04T08:00:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-09-04T07:53:47.139-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Latin"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Epigraphy"/>
   <title type="text">Epigraphischen Datenbank Heidelberg - Epigraphic Database Heidelberg (EDH)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/home">Epigraphischen Datenbank Heidelberg - Epigraphic Database Heidelberg (EDH)</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/images/subHeaderMitteAlt.png" class="decoded" src="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/images/subHeaderMitteAlt.png" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Die <b>Aufgabe</b> der <i>Epigraphischen Datenbank Heidelberg (EDH)</i> besteht in der systematischen Aufnahme der antiken lateinischen und  bilinguen (dabei zumeist lateinisch-griechischen) Inschriften in einer  komplexen Datenbank. Aufgrund ihrer interdisziplinär angelegen  Konzeption und Arbeitsweise zählt sie zu den international führenden  Datenbankvorhaben zur raschen Sammlung und zuverlässigen historischen  Auswertung epigraphischer Zeugnisse. Die besonderen Merkmale der <i>EDH</i> liegen auf der <a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/hilfe/liste/provinzen" target="_blank">regionalen Systematik</a>, der beliebigen Kombinierbarkeit der gespeicherten Metainformationen und der wechselseitigen Verknüpfung der <a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/inhalt/einfacheSuche" target="_blank"><i>Epigraphischen Text-Datenbank</i></a>&nbsp; mit den beiden weiteren Teildatenbanken der <i>EDH</i>, der <a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/inhalt/bibliographie" target="_blank"><i>Epigraphischen Bibliographie</i></a> und der <a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/inhalt/fotos" target="_blank"><i>Epigraphischen Fotothek</i></a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Ihr <b>Ziel</b> liegt darin, die epigraphische Dokumentation  der Provinzen des römischen Reiches bis zum Jahr 2020 (vorgesehenem  Laufzeitende) so vollständig und zuverlässig wie möglich für  online-Recherchen zur Verfügung zu stellen. Auf Beschluß der <i>Commissione epigrafia e informatica</i> der <i>AIEGL</i> aus dem Jahr 2003 für die Errichtung der internationalen epigraphischen Datenbankföderation <a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/projekt/geschichte#anker11/2003" target="_blank"><i>EAGLE</i></a> <i>(Electronic Archives of Greek and Latin Epigraphy</i><i><span style="font-style: normal;">) obliegt der </span></i><i><i>EDH</i></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;"> seitdem die Betreuung der Inschriften der <b>römischen Provinzen</b>, während die bis dahin über die </span></i><i><i>EDH</i></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;"> bereits erfaßten Inschriften Italiens</span></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;"> </span></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;">der </span></i><i><i>Epigraphic Database Rome (EDR)</i></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;"> </span></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;">zur weiteren Bearbeitung und Vervollständigung des Datenbestandes durch letztere </span></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;">überlassen worden sind. </span></i>Zweck der <i>EAGLE</i>-Föderation  ist es, möglichst alle lateinischen und griechischen Inschriften der  Antike nach einheitlichen Kritierien im Internet zugänglich zu machen.<i><span style="font-style: normal;"> Die Gründung von</span></i><i><i> EDR</i></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;"> </span></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;">erfolgte zu diesem Zweck </span></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;"> in enger Kooperation mit der </span></i><i><i>EDH</i></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;"> und na</span></i><i><span style="font-style: normal;">ch deren Modell</span></i>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> The <b>task</b> of the <i>Epigraphic Database Heidelberg (EDH)</i> is the systematic entry of ancient Latin and bilingual (usually Latin  and Greek) inscriptions into a complex database. As a result of its  interdisciplinary approach, conception and method of work <i>EDH</i>  is to be counted among the leading international database projects which  collects and provides reliable historical analysis of epigraphic  monuments. A distinguishing feature of <i>EDH</i> is its <u>regional focus</u>, its capability of combining the stored metadata as freely as possible and the reciprocal linking of the <u><i>Epigraphic Text Database</i></u>&nbsp;with both of the constituent databases of <i>EDH</i>, the <u><i>Bibliographic Database</i></u> and the <u><i>Photographic Database</i></u>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Its <b>aim</b> is to render the epigraphic documentation of  the provinces of the Roman Empire as completely and reliably as possible  for online research work. Under the leadership of the <i>Commissione epigrafia e informatica of the AIEGL</i> a decision was made in 2003 to create an international epigraphic database confederation <span style="color: navy;"><span lang="zxx"><u><i>EAGLE</i></u></span></span> <i>(Electronic Archives of Greek and Latin Epigraphy)</i>. Since then <i>EDH</i> is responsible for the inscriptions of the <b>Roman provinces</b>. The inscriptions of Italy which had already been entered into EDH were passed on to the <i>Epigraphic Database Rome (EDR)</i>.  It is now the domain of EDR to improve these records as well as adding  to their number in order to complete the entry of all inscriptions of  Italy. The long term aim of this confederation is to make all Latin and  Greek inscriptions from Antiquity available on the Internet in a  standardised system of criteria. It was with this in mind that <i>EDR</i> was founded on the model of and in cooperation with <i>EDH</i>.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <i>Epigraphic Database Heidelberg</i> contains the texts of <b>Latin and bilingual</b> (i.e. Latin-Greek) <b>inscriptions of the Roman Empire</b>.  The epigraphic monuments are collected and kept up to date on the basis  of modern research. With the help of seach functions specific queries  can be carried out - e.g. a search for words in inscriptions and / or  particular descriptive data. The seach results are often displayed  together with photos and drawings.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The geographic focus is provided by the provinces of the Roman Empire. The total number of records rises continuously.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Research Project is made up of three constituent databases</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/inhalt/einfacheSuche">Epigraphic Text Database</a>&nbsp;(<a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/inschrift/lastUpdates">last update</a>)</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/inhalt/fotos">Photographic Database</a>&nbsp;(<a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/foto/lastUpdates">last update</a>)</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/inhalt/bibliographie">Bibliographic Database</a>&nbsp;(<a href="http://edh-www.adw.uni-heidelberg.de/bibliographie/lastUpdates">last update</a>)</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">A fourth constituent database for the collection of geographic coordinates is at present under construction.</span></blockquote><br /><div style="text-align: center;">And see also: <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/11/greek-and-latin-epigraphic-databases.html">EAGLE       : Electronic Archive of Greek and Latin Epigraphy</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7813010385594992633/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/09/epigraphic-database-heidelberg-edh.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7813010385594992633"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7813010385594992633"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/09/epigraphic-database-heidelberg-edh.html"
         title="Epigraphischen Datenbank Heidelberg - Epigraphic Database Heidelberg (EDH)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
