<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-971432285508137393</id>
   <published>2012-10-04T16:17:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-10-10T18:13:10.195-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New Book Online from the Oriental Institute: Papers Presented to John Huehnergard on the Occasion of His 60th Birthday</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href="https://oi.uchicago.edu/news/"&gt;Announced today&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img align="right" alt="book cover" src="https://oi.uchicago.edu/i/saoc67_5.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;SAOC 67.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Language and Nature: Papers Presented to John Huehnergard on the Occasion of His 60th Birthday&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Edited by Rebecca Hasselbach and Na'ama Pat-El&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class="buy"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a class="purch" href="http://www.oxbowbooks.com/bookinfo.cfm/ID/161147/" title="Purchase Book"&gt;Purchase Book&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="download" href="https://oi.uchicago.edu/pdf/saoc67.pdf" title="Download PDF"&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="terms" href="https://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/epi.html"&gt;Terms of Use&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;John as a Teacher and Mentor. Rebecca Hasselbach and Na'ama Pat-El&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Research of John Huehnergard. Rebecca Hasselbach and Na'ama Pat-El&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;A Brief Note on the Festschrift Illustrations. X Bonnie Woods&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Contributions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Functional Values of &lt;u&gt;iprus&lt;/u&gt; Forms in Old Babylonian &lt;u&gt;summa&lt;/u&gt; Protases. Eran Cohen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Hypotaxis-Parataxis Dichotomy and Elliptic Conditional Clauses in Semitic. Lutz Edzard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;t-Stem Verbs without Metathesis in Aramaic and Hebrew Documents from the Judean Desert. Steven E. Fassberg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;People without Town: The &lt;u&gt;ʿapiru&lt;/u&gt; in the Amarna Evidence. Daniel E. Fleming&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Denominal, Lexicalized &lt;u&gt;hiphil&lt;/u&gt; Verbs. W. Randall Garr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Treatment of Vowel Length in Arabic Grammar and Its Adaptation to Hebrew. Gideon Goldenberg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Wisdom in Ugaritic. Edward L. Greenstein&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Predicate Nominals and Related Constructions in Neo-Mandaic. Charles G. Häberl&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Yaqtul and a Ugaritic Incantation Text. Jo Ann Hackett&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Verbal Endings -&lt;u&gt;u&lt;/u&gt; and -&lt;u&gt;a&lt;/u&gt;: A Note on Their Functional Derivation. Rebecca Hasselbach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ibn Khaldun as a Historical Linguist with an Excursus on the Question of Ancient Gaf. Wolfhart Heinrichs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;A Morphosyntactic Explanation of &lt;u&gt;teposotikem&lt;/u&gt; (Jer 25:34). Jeremy M. Hutton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Canaano-Akkadian: Linguistics and Sociolinguistics. Shlomo Izre'el&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Evidential Function of the Perfect in North-Eastern Neo-Aramaic Dialects. Geoffrey Khan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Les noms de plantes akkadiens dans leur contexte sémitique. Leonid Kogan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Grammaticalization and the Biblical Hebrew Pseudo-Cohortative. Paul Korchin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Biblical Hebrew Verbal System in a Nutshell. Dennis Pardee&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Syntax of &lt;u&gt;‘aser&lt;/u&gt; and &lt;u&gt;se&lt;/u&gt;C — Yet Again. Na'ama Pat-El&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Late Biblical Hebrew in the Book of Haggai. Gary A. Rendsburg&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Two Modern South Arabian Etymologies. Aaron D. Rubin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;“If Water Had Not Been Made to Dry Up, This Earth Would Have Been Drowned”: Pahlavi *awas- “to dry.” P. Oktor Skjærvø&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Vowel Syncope and Syllable Repair Processes in Proto-Semitic  Construct Forms: A New Reconstruction Based on the Law of Diminishing  Conditioning. Richard C. Steiner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Reconciling Some Morphological Eccentricities of the Semitic Genitive Case Marker. David Testen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Mixed Linguistic Features in a Judeo-Arabic Text from Algeria: The Sarh to the Haftarot from Constantine. Ofra Tirosh-Becker&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Alternierende Metrik in der akkadischen Poesie. Josef Tropper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;On Personal Names Ending in -&lt;u&gt;ayu&lt;/u&gt; in the Amarna Letters and in Texts from Canaan. Wilfred van Soldt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Jumping Spiders (Araneae: Salticidae) of the Concord Area, Middlesex County, Massachusetts. Richard K. Walton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Verbal Endings in the Afroasiatic Prefix Conjugations. Andrzej Zaborski&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Prepositional Phrases as Subjects in Several Semitic Languages. Tamar Zewi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;This book includes thirty contributions — twenty-nine papers and one  artistic contribution — by John's colleagues, former students, and  friends, on a variety of topics that represent John's versatility and  many interests, including philology, history, natural history, and art.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Many of the papers concentrate on the Akkadian speaking world,  reflecting one of the major languages John Huehnergard has worked on  throughout the years. Eran Cohen reviews and discusses the functional  value of Akkadian &lt;u&gt;iprus&lt;/u&gt; in conditional clauses in epistolary and legal texts. Lutz Edzard discusses the Akkadian injunctive &lt;u&gt;šumma&lt;/u&gt;,  used in oath formulae. Daniel Fleming asks who were the ‘Apiru people  mentioned in Egyptian texts in the Late Bronze Age and what was their  social standing as is reflected in the Amarna letters. Shlomo Izre'el  offers a revised and improved version of his important study of the  language of the Amarna letters. Leonid Kogan offers a comparative  etymological study of botanical terminology in Akkadian, while Josef  Tropper argues that Akkadian poetry, as well as Northwest Semitic  poetry, are based on certain metric principles. Wilfred von Soldt lists  and discusses personal names ending in -&lt;u&gt;ayu&lt;/u&gt; from Amarna.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;A number of papers deal with Arabic grammarians and their concepts of  language. Gideon Goldenberg discusses the concept of vocalic length in  Arabic grammatical tradition and in the medieval Hebrew tradition that  was its product. Wolfhart Heinrichs's contribution shows that Ibn  Khaldūn held innovative views of language and its evolution.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Several other papers deal with Hebrew and the Hebrew Bible. Steven Fassberg deals with verbal &lt;u&gt;t&lt;/u&gt;-forms  that do not exhibit the expected metathesis in Hebrew and Aramaic of  the Dead Sea Scrolls. Randall Garr studies one class of denominal &lt;u&gt;hiphil&lt;/u&gt; verbs and asks why these verbs are assigned to the causative stem  despite their non-causative semantic content. Ed Greenstein suggests  that the roots of biblical wisdom can be located in second-millennium  Canaanite literature by identifying wisdom sayings and themes in the  Ugaritic corpus. Jeremy Hutton sheds more light on &lt;u&gt;t&lt;/u&gt;G forms in  Biblical Hebrew. Paul Korchin explains occurrences of the cohortative in  Biblical Hebrew that do not conform to the normative volitive function.  Dennis Pardee provides a detailed study of the Hebrew verbal system as  primarily expressing aspect, not tense. Gary A. Rendsburg argues in  favor of Late Biblical Hebrew features in the book of Haggai.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Four papers deal with linguistic aspects of non-Classical Semitic  languages. Charles Häberl looks into predicates of verbless sentences in  Semitic and particularly in Neo-Mandaic. Geoffrey Khan discusses the  functional differences between the preterite and the perfect in NENA.  Aaron D. Rubin provides Semitic etymologies of two Modern South Arabian  words. Ofra Tirosh-Becker discusses the language of the Judeo-Arabic  translation of the books of Prophets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Papers on comparative Semitics are likewise numerous. Jo Ann Hackett takes another look at Ugaritic &lt;u&gt;yaqtul&lt;/u&gt; and argues for the existence of a preterite &lt;u&gt;yaqtul&lt;/u&gt; on comparative grounds, among others. Rebecca Hasselbach tackles the evasive origin of the Semitic verbal endings -&lt;u&gt;u&lt;/u&gt; and -&lt;u&gt;a&lt;/u&gt;. Na'ama Pat-El continues the discussion of the origin of the Hebrew relative particle &lt;u&gt;š&lt;/u&gt;eC-  from a syntactic and comparative perspective. Richard C. Steiner  proposes a new vowel syncope rule for Proto Semitic. David Testen argues  for a different reconstruction of the Semitic case system. Tamar Zewi  shows that prepositional phrases can function as subjects in a variety  of Semitic languages. Andrzej Zaborski suggests that Berber and Cushitic  preserve archaic features that have been lost for the most part in the  Semitic languages.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;There is one paper on an Indo-European language with important ties  to Semitic languages in P. Oktor Skjaervo discussion of the Pahlavi verb  *ãwãs 'to dry.'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Finally, Richard Walton contributes a paper about the jumping spiders  of Concord, Massachusetts, a project he labored on with John  Huehnergard.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The book is beautifully decorated by the drawings of the artist X  Bonnie Woods, who prepared special illustration for this volume, based  on cuneiform.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 67&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Chicago: The Oriental Institute, 2012&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;ISBN: 978-1-885923-91-2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Pp. xxii + 476 (frontispiece John Huehnergard); 3 tables, 30 original illustrations, 32 linked mp4 videos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span class="pubprice"&gt;$54.95&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class="rev"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;For an up to date list of all Oriental Institute publications available online see:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/10/oriental-institute-open-access.html"&gt;The Oriental Institute Open Access Publications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/971432285508137393/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/new-book-online-from-oriental-institute.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/971432285508137393"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/971432285508137393"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/new-book-online-from-oriental-institute.html"
         title="New Book Online from the Oriental Institute: Papers Presented to John Huehnergard on the Occasion of His 60th Birthday"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
