<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6723829900873570557</id>
   <published>2013-05-08T18:45:00.005-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-05-08T18:45:44.615-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Announcing the Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href="http://www.stoa.org/archives/1736"&gt;Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;May 8th, 2013 by Hugh Cayless&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Colleagues: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;We are very pleased to announce the creation of the Duke  Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3), a new Digital Classics  R&amp;amp;D unit embedded in the Duke University Libraries, whose start-up  has been generously &lt;a href="http://today.duke.edu/2013/05/mellondc3"&gt;funded&lt;/a&gt; by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation and Duke University’s Dean of Arts &amp;amp; Sciences and Office of the Provost. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The DC3 goes live 1 July 2013, continuing a long tradition  of collaboration between the Duke University Libraries and papyrologists  in Duke’s Department of Classical Studies. The late Professors William  H. Willis and John F. Oates began the Duke Databank of Documentary  Papyri (DDbDP) more than 30 years ago, and in 1996 Duke was among the  founding members of the Advanced Papyrological Information System  (APIS). In recent years, Duke led the Mellon-funded Integrating Digital  Papyrology effort, which brought together the DDbDP, Heidelberger  Gesamtverzeichnis der Griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens (&lt;a href="http://www.rzuser.uni-heidelberg.de/%7Egv0/"&gt;HGV&lt;/a&gt;), and APIS in a common search and collaborative curation environment (&lt;a href="http://papyri.info/"&gt;papyri.info&lt;/a&gt;), and which collaborates with other partners, including &lt;a href="http://www.trismegistos.org/"&gt;Trismegistos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.ulb.ac.be/philo/cpeg/bp.htm"&gt;Bibliographie Papyrologique&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://dev.ulb.ac.be/philo/bad/copte/baseuk.php?page=accueiluk.php"&gt;Brussels Coptic Database&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="http://orientw.uzh.ch:8080/apd/project.jsp"&gt;Arabic Papyrology Database&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The DC3 team will see to the maintenance and enhancement of &lt;a href="http://papyri.info/"&gt;papyri.info&lt;/a&gt; data and tooling, cultivate new partnerships in the papyrological  domain, experiment in the development of new complementary resources,  and engage in teaching and outreach at Duke and beyond. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The team’s first push will be in the area of Greek and  Latin Epigraphy, where it plans to leverage its papyrological experience  to serve a much larger community. The team brings a wealth of  experience in fields like image processing, text engineering, scholarly  data modeling, and building scalable web services. It aims to help  create a system in which the many worldwide digital epigraphy projects  can interoperate by linking into the graph of scholarly relationships  while maintaining the full force of their individuality. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The DC3 team is: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ryan BAUMANN: Has worked on a wide range of Digital  Humanities projects, from applying advanced imaging and visualization  techniques to ancient artifacts, to developing systems for scholarly  editing and collaboration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hugh &lt;a href="http://philomousos.com/"&gt;CAYLESS&lt;/a&gt;: Has over  a decade of software engineering expertise in both academic and  industrial settings. He also holds a Ph.D. in Classics and a Master’s in  Information Science. He is one of the founders of the &lt;a href="http://epidoc.sf.net/"&gt;EpiDoc&lt;/a&gt; collaborative and currently serves on the Technical Council of the &lt;a href="http://www.tei-c.org/index.xml"&gt;Text Encoding Initiative&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;div dir="ltr"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Josh SOSIN: Associate Professor of &lt;a href="http://classicalstudies.duke.edu/"&gt;Classical Studies&lt;/a&gt; and History, Co-Director of the &lt;a href="http://papyri.info/"&gt;DDbDP&lt;/a&gt;, Associate editor of &lt;a href="http://grbs.library.duke.edu/"&gt;Greek, Roman, and Byzantine Studies&lt;/a&gt;; an epigraphist and papyrologist &lt;a href="http://people.duke.edu/%7Ejds15/cv.html"&gt;interested&lt;/a&gt; in the intersection of ancient law, religion, and the economy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6723829900873570557/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/05/announcing-duke-collaboratory-for.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6723829900873570557"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6723829900873570557"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/05/announcing-duke-collaboratory-for.html"
         title="Announcing the Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
