<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1459095974644038657</id>
   <published>2013-12-16T09:39:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-12-16T07:38:46.624-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">National Treasures Department of the Israel Antiquities Authority</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.antiquities.org.il/t/Default_en.aspx">National Treasures:  Selected Artifacts from the Shelby White Leon Levy Center for National Treasures</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.antiquities.org.il/t/images/mainlogo-eng.gif" class="decoded" src="http://www.antiquities.org.il/t/images/mainlogo-eng.gif" /> </blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;"><a href="http://www.antiquities.org.il/modules_heb.asp?Module_id=102" style="color: black;"></a></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.antiquities.org.il/modules_heb.asp?Module_id=102" style="color: black;">The National Treasures Department of the Israel Antiquities Authority</a> is responsible for the housing,  documentation and control of antiquities in Israel. The National Treasures' collections comprise hundreds  of thousands of artifacts that range from prehistoric periods to the end of the Ottoman period. Most of the  artifacts are housed and catalogued in the repositories of the Shelby White and Leon Levy Center for  National Treasures, and approximately 50,000 artifacts are on loan at archaeological exhibitions in Israel and abroad.<br /><br /> This on-line site offers a selection of published artifacts from the collections of the National  Treasures and is available for researchers, curators, students and the general public in Israel and abroad.  This site is updated continuously, and new artifacts are added on a regular basis.  <br /><br />   The artifacts on the site are arranged both chronologically (according to archaeological periods)  and typologically (according to the type of artifact), allowing either a gradual guided entry through  the main title pages to the artifact's information card, or directly to the artifact's information card  using an advanced search box.<br /><br />   The artifact's information card presents detailed archaeological data about the selected artifact,  including provenance, type, dimensions, material, site where discovered, dating and bibliography.  In addition, hi-resolution images of on-line artifacts may be purchased on-line from the photographic  archives of the Israel Antiquities Authority. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><a href="http://www.antiquities.org.il/t/search_en.aspx?q=&amp;submit1=%E7%F4%F9" style="color: #a34d34;">To the List of Items &gt;&gt;</a></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1459095974644038657/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/02/open-access-national-treasures.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1459095974644038657"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1459095974644038657"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/02/open-access-national-treasures.html"
         title="National Treasures Department of the Israel Antiquities Authority"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
