<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5052218266544957447</id>
   <published>2011-11-21T10:46:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2011-11-21T10:52:53.182-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Acta Linguistica Asiatica</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://revije.ff.uni-lj.si/ala/index">Acta Linguistica Asiatica</a><br />ISSN: 2232-3317<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">ACTA LINGUISTICA ASIATICA is a journal devoted to the study of Asian languages, their translation and teaching.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">ALA   is an interdisciplinary scholarly journal which publishes research   papers, survey papers and technical notes on the subjects of Asian   linguistics, translation studies and the teaching of Asian languages,   book reviews on representative works on the same subjects and reports   from outstanding events. ALA encourages the interlinking of different   linguistic disciplines, fosters dialogue among different theoretical   orientations and their practical application, proposes new approaches to   existing research themes, draws attention to relevant questions,   informs about recent findings and events in the above areas.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">ALA   is published three times a year. Articles in each first and second  issue  are written only in English with an English and a Slovene  abstract, while  articles in each third issue can also be written in  Slovene with a Slovene and  an English abstract. </span><br /><div class="Style2"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><div class="Style2"><span style="font-size: x-small;">ACTA LINGUISTICA ASIATICA je revija za azijsko jezikoslovje, prevodoslovje in didaktiko azijskih jezikov.</span></div><div class="Style2"><span style="font-size: x-small;">ALA  je interdisciplinarna znanstveno-strokovna revija, ki objavlja izvirne  znanstvene članke, pregledne znanstvene članke in strokovne članke s  področja azijskega jezikoslovja, prevodoslovja in didaktike azijskih  jezikov, recenzije reprezentativnih del z istih področij ter poročila o  odmevnih dogodkih. ALA spodbuja povezovanje jezikovnih strok, krepi  dialog med različnimi teoretskimi orientacijami in prakso, odpira  izvirne pristope k obravnavi tem, opozarja na aktualna vprašanja,  obvešča o aktualnih dognanjih in dogodkih z omenjenih področij.</span></div></blockquote><div class="Style2"><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">ALA  izhaja trikrat letno. Članki prve in druge vsakoletne številke so  pisani le v angleščini, pri čemer ima vsak članek tudi angleški in  slovenski izvleček. Članki tretje številke so lahko pisani tudi v  slovenščini, pri čemer ima vsak članek tudi slovenski in angleški  izvleček.</span><br /><br /><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">2011</span></h3><div id="issue" style="clear: left;">    <h4><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://revije.ff.uni-lj.si/ala/issue/view/4">Vol 1, No 2 (2011)</a></span></h4></div><h4><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://revije.ff.uni-lj.si/ala/issue/view/3">Vol 1, No 1 (2011)</a></span></h4></blockquote></div><br /><br /><div style="text-align: center;">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5052218266544957447/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/11/open-access-journal-acta-linguistica.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5052218266544957447"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5052218266544957447"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/11/open-access-journal-acta-linguistica.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Acta Linguistica Asiatica"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
