<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-685486070485029505</id>
   <published>2013-02-07T10:00:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-02-07T10:50:22.633-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text"> Old Latin manuscripts of St John's Gospel</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-family: Gentium; font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 16 July 2009. Updated 7 February 2013]</span> </span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.iohannes.com/vetuslatina/index.html"><span style="font-size: small;">Vetus Latina Iohannes, The Verbum Project,&nbsp; The Old Latin manuscripts of St John's Gospel</span></a><br />E<span style="font-size: small;">dited by P. H. Burton, J. Palserak, H. A. G. Houghton, D. C. Parker</span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.iohannes.com/images/EagleOvalSmall.jpg" class="decoded" height="171" src="http://www.iohannes.com/images/EagleOvalSmall.jpg" width="200" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="color: black; font-family: Gentium; font-size: medium;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Gentium; font-size: small;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This electronic edition of the Old Latin manuscripts of St John's Gospel  is the initial stage of a full edition of the Old Latin materials for  this Gospel in the series <i>Vetus Latina. Die Reste der Altlateinischen Bibel nach Petrus Sabatier neu gesammelt und herausgegeben von der Erzabtei Beuron</i>.  The second stage consists of the collection and addition of patristic  citations of the Gospel. This division was adopted for two reasons. The  first is that the Gospels are unique in the Old Latin Bible, in that the  main text-types are represented by extant manuscripts and not by  citations. The transcriptions (and their apparatus) thus provide a  framework to which the citations may then be added. The second reason is  more pragmatic: the rules with regard to length and size of project of  the Arts and Humanities Research Board, which funded both this work and  its continuation, are such that the preparation of the full edition  required to be split into two stages. The transcribing and editing of  the manuscripts made a suitable first stage with its own worthwhile  results.</span></span><br /><br /><span style="color: black; font-family: Gentium; font-size: x-small;"> The Verbum Project, as we called it, began in October 2002 and ran for  three years within what was then the Centre for the Editing of Texts in  Religion (now the <a href="http://itsee.bham.ac.uk/" target="_blank">Institute for Textual Scholarship and Electronic Editing</a>)  in the Department of Theology and Religion, University of Birmingham.  Although free-standing, it built upon and shared ideas with the  Principio Project, whose goals included a similar electronic edition of  the Greek majuscule manuscripts of John. The project was directed by  David Parker, while Jon Balserak and Philip Burton worked full-time on  the project, the latter having responsibility for the practical  decision-making. They produced the bulk of the transcriptions, although  Hugh Houghton (who was working on a doctoral thesis more closely related  to the patristic citations) and David Parker also made contributions.  The production of the electronic edition and most of the proofreading  have been undertaken by Hugh Houghton.&nbsp;</span></span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="color: black; font-family: Gentium; font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: black; font-family: Gentium;">The methodology followed was to make transcriptions following the TEI  guidelines as applied by other editions which have used the same  software to make the edition, namely Peter Robinson's Collate programme,  with further modifications to suit the special needs of biblical  manuscripts as already developed by the Münster Institut für  Neutestamentliche Textforschung and the Principio Project (itself a  project within the <a href="http://igntp.org/" target="_blank">International Greek New Testament Project</a>).  These conventions aim to reproduce the page of each manuscript as  nearly as possible, recording the original spelling, the use of  abbreviations (including indication of the nomina sacra by a superline  over the second letter), formatting with columns, lines, spaces and  running titles, and variations in the form of letters such as capitals  or digraphs (e.g. æ). The use of tagging also permits the indication of  lacunae or gaps, letters which cannot be clearly made out, erasures, and  corrections to the text. </span></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: blue;"></span></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: blue;"><a href="http://www.iohannes.com/vetuslatina/index.html" target="_top">Title</a></span></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="color: blue;"><a href="http://www.iohannes.com/vetuslatina/introduction.htm" target="main">Introduction</a><br /> <a href="http://www.iohannes.com/vetuslatina/manuscripts.htm" target="main">Manuscripts</a><br /> <a href="http://www.iohannes.com/vetuslatina/instructions.htm" target="main">Instructions</a><br /> <a href="http://arts-itsee.bham.ac.uk/AnaServer?verbum+0+start.anv" target="_blank"><span style="color: red;">Electronic Edition</span></a><br /> <span style="color: blue;"><a href="http://www.iohannes.com/vetuslatina/acknowledgments.htm" target="main">Acknowledgments</a></span><br /><span style="color: blue;"><a href="http://www.iohannes.com/vetuslatina/technical.htm" target="main">Technical and FAQ</a><br /> <a href="http://www.iohannes.com/feedback.html" target="main">Feedback</a><br /> <a href="http://www.iohannes.com/vetuslatina/reporterror.html" target="main">Report an error</a></span></span></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"> </span></span><br /></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/685486070485029505/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/07/old-latin-manuscripts-of-johns-gospel.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/685486070485029505"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/685486070485029505"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/07/old-latin-manuscripts-of-johns-gospel.html"
         title=" Old Latin manuscripts of St John's Gospel"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
