<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1655841608592466744</id>
   <published>2011-03-11T06:14:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2011-03-30T18:46:48.958-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">LSJ at TLG</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href="http://stephanus.tlg.uci.edu/lsj/#eid=1&amp;amp;context=lsj"&gt;The Liddell-Scott Jones Lexicon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Thesaurus Linguae Graecae (TLG) is proud to announce the release of a  new online version of Liddell-Scott-Jones (LSJ), the premier lexicon  for classical Greek. The TLG version represents five years of intensive  work to produce a fully edited and searchable version of LSJ with links  to the TLG corpus.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;History of the printed volume:&amp;nbsp; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; Liddell-Scott-Jones (&lt;a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/greek-english-lexicon/oclc/32820286&amp;amp;referer=brief_results" target="_blank"&gt;known as LSJ or Liddell-Scott&lt;/a&gt;)   is the standard lexicographical resource for Classical Greek.  LSJ was  first published in 1843 by Oxford Clarendon Press edited by Henry  George Liddell and Robert Scott and based on earlier lexicographical  work by Schneider and Passow. It was subsequently revised 8 times. The  8th edition (1897) was the last edition published during Liddell's  lifetime. Two abridged editions (the &lt;a href="http://www.worldcat.org/search?q=0199102074" target="_blank"&gt;"little Liddell"&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.worldcat.org/search?q=0199102066" target="_blank"&gt;intermediate LSJ (or "middle Liddell")&lt;/a&gt;  were also published by Oxford in 1843 and 1889 respectively). The  modern reader can greatly benefit from reading the fascinating story of  the creation of LSJ in the &lt;a href="http://www.tlg.uci.edu/lsj/00-Preface_etc.html" target="_blank"&gt;Preface&lt;/a&gt; of the volume. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;  The last edition of LSJ was published in ten parts between 1925 and  1940.  A list of Addenda and Corrigenda to the 1940 edition was  published in 1968 and bound with subsequent printings but the revisions  were not merged into the main lexicon composed by Liddell and Scott. In  1996, Oxford University Press published the &lt;a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/greek-english-lexicon-supplement/oclc/237097979?referer=di&amp;amp;ht=edition" target="_blank"&gt;LSJ Supplement&lt;/a&gt;  with 320 pages of corrections and additions but the main text of the  lexicon was not revised. More recent bibliographical efforts, most  notably the &lt;a href="http://dge.cchs.csic.es/" target="_blank"&gt;Diccionario Griego-Español (DGE)&lt;/a&gt;,  carried out in Madrid, Spain under the direction of Francisco R.  Adrados and Juan Rodríguez Somolinos, have resumed the task of a new  lexicon for ancient Greek based on modern lexicographical methods and  updated data. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Digital versions:&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; LSJ was first made available in digital form in the mid-90s thanks to the &lt;a href="http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper/text?doc=Perseus%3Atext%3A1999.04.0057%3Aalphabetic+letter%3D*a%3Aentry+group%3D1" target="_blank"&gt;Perseus Project&lt;/a&gt; with funding by the National Science Foundation.  The Perseus digital  version was subsequently licensed to a number of projects (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://perseus.uchicago.edu/Reference/lsj.html"&gt;Chicago Perseus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://archimedes.fas.harvard.edu/pollux/" target="_blank"&gt;Pollux:Archimedes Project&lt;/a&gt;, etc.) and was ported to &lt;a href="http://text.handheldclassics.com/"&gt;phone apps&lt;/a&gt;.  All these sites provide some searching capabilities and links but not  links to the TLG data. They are also based on the Perseus digital file  which has not been extensively corrected. Digital scans of the lexicon  can be downloaded from a variety of sources, including but not limited  to the &lt;a href="http://www.archive.org/details/greekenglishlex00liddrich" target="_blank"&gt;Internet Archive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=GlRFAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;dq=liddell-scott&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=dw_peLoPeV&amp;amp;sig=yYmxA2QA828WfeKma4vPNC600NY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;ei=EtRiTfLeDcLagQfKjr3TAg&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;oi=book_result&amp;amp;ct=result&amp;amp;resnum=5&amp;amp;ved=0CDcQ6AEwBDgK#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=fals" target="_blank"&gt;Google Books&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/37894457/%CE%9B%CE%B5%CE%BE%CE%B9%CE%BA%CF%8C-Liddell-Scott" target="_blank"&gt;Scribd&lt;/a&gt;. However, without markup and searching capabilities, the value of the scans is rather limited. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;  A CD ROM version published by &lt;a href="http://www.logos.com/product/3879/liddell-and-scott-greek-english-lexicon" target="_blank"&gt;Logos Software&lt;/a&gt; incorporated the 1996 Supplement and many improvements and corrections to the printed version. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The TLG version:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; The TLG embarked into this project in 2006. Recognizing the fact that  LSJ is the most central reference work for all scholars and students of  ancient Greek, we decided that producing a fully corrected and reliably  accessible online version with links to TLG texts was a worthwhile  undertaking. The digital LSJ was a natural extension of our larger and  ongoing lemmatization project. In the process of improving automatic  recognition of all word forms in our texts, we have digitized and  extracted information such as headwords, meanings, grammatical use from a  large number of dictionaries. Making LSJ available to the public was  another step in this direction. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;  Digitization, markup and correction of LSJ proved to be far more time  consuming and demanding from a scholarly point of view than we  anticipated, hence the entire project took five years to complete. The  effort began by extracting identifiable sections of the text, such as  headwords and meanings, that we could proofread using TLG correction  software or by collating multiple digital versions. This approach was  helpful but not entirely effective. Ultimately, the bulk of editing  required a human eye. The final project contains a number of  enhancements compared to the printed version. A number of lower case or  ambigious entries have been converted to upper case and a large number  of typographical errors have ben corrected.A list of Corrigenda will be  posted soon. Sub-entries in the printed edition marked with hyphens,  have been expanded and treated as headwords. Greek words (both headwords  and Greek inside entries), and English definitions can be searched and  LSJ citations are linked to the TLG updated editions (when possible).    Nishad Prakash worked tirelessly to create an attactive as well as user  friendly interface.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;  We are very pleased to make this invaluable resource available free and open to the scholarly community. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;  Maria Pantelia&lt;br /&gt;TLG Director&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1655841608592466744/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/02/lsj-at-tlg.html#comment-form"
         title="1 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1655841608592466744"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1655841608592466744"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/02/lsj-at-tlg.html"
         title="LSJ at TLG"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>1</thr:total>
</entry>
