<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5901163823926928680</id>
   <published>2009-04-01T12:59:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2009-04-01T14:19:24.571-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">SOAS Research Online</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.soas.ac.uk/">The School of Oriental and African Studies</a>, University of London has a very interesting and useful <a href="https://eprints.soas.ac.uk/">eprint server</a>.  From the point of view of ancient studies, there is a lot of material at the <a href="https://eprints.soas.ac.uk/view/divisions/2400.html">Department of the Languages and Cultures of the Near and Middle East</a>, significantly a large set of full-text, open access articles by Andrew George.  Many of the entres include bibliographic metadata, but it possible to limit a search to include only open access full text results.<br /><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21276">Babylonian and Assyrian: a history of Akkadian</a> From: Postgate, J. N., (ed.), Languages of Iraq, Ancient and Modern. London: British School of Archaeology in Iraq, pp. 31-71<br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21294">Babylonian texts from the folios of Sidney Smith, part three: a commentary on a ritual of the month Nisan</a> From: Guinan, Ann K. and Ellis, Maria deJ. and Ferrara, A. J. and Freedman, Sally M. and Rutz, Matthew T. and Sassmannshausen, Leonhard and Tinney, Steve and Waters, M. W., (eds.), If a Man Builds a Joyful House: Assyriological Studies in Honor of Erle Verdun Leichty. Cuneiform Monographs (31). Leiden, Netherlands: Brill, pp. 173-185<br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21277">Gilgamesh and the literary traditions of ancient Mesopotamia</a> From: Leick, Gwendolyn, (ed.), The Babylonian World. London: Routledge, pp. 447-459<br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21295">In search of the é.dub.ba.a: The ancient Mesopotamian school in literature and reality</a> From: Sefati, Y, (ed.), "An Experienced Scribe who Neglects Nothing". Ancient Near Eastern Studies in Honor of Jacob Klein. Bethesda, Md: CDL Press (USA), pp. 127-137<br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21296">Palace names and epithets, and the Vaulted Building</a> Sumer [2001-2002]<br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21279">SB Gilgamesh I, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21280">SB Gilgamesh II, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21281">SB Gilgamesh III, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21282">SB Gilgamesh IV, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21283">SB Gilgamesh V, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21284">SB Gilgamesh VI, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21285">SB Gilgamesh VII, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21286">SB Gilgamesh VIII, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21287">SB Gilgamesh IX, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21288">SB Gilgamesh X, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21289">SB Gilgamesh XI, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21290">SB Gilgamesh XII, score transliteration</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21278">Sources of the Standard Babylonian poem</a><br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21275">The civilizing of Enkidu: an unusual tablet of the Babylonian Gilgamesh epic</a>. Revue d'assyriologie [2007]<br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21293">The Epic of Gilgamesh: Thoughts on genre and meaning</a> From: Azize, J and Weeks, N, (eds.), Gilgamesh and the World of Assyria. Proceedings of the Conference Held at the Mandelbaum House, the University of Sydney, 21-23 July 2004. Ancient Near Eastern Studies Supplement (21). Leuven: Peeters, pp. 37-66<br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21291">The Gilgamesh epic at Ugarit</a> Aula Orientalis [2007]<br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21292">Ur-Namma B 71</a> Nouvelles assyriologiques brèves et utilitaires<br />George, Andrew. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21297">What's new in the Gilgamesh Epic?</a> Bulletin of the Canadian Society for Mesopotamian Studies, 34<br />Schwemer, Daniel. <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/abzu-displayentry.pl?RC=21298">Hittite Prayers to the Sun-god for Appeasing an Angry Personal God. A Critical Edition of CTH 372–4</a> In: Jacques, M., (ed.), “Mon dieu, qu’ai-je donc fait ?” Les prières pénitentielles (dingir-šà-dab-ba) et l’expression de la piété privée en Mésopotamie. Habilitationsschrift Zürich<br /><br /><a href="https://eprints.soas.ac.uk/cgi/search/advanced">Search around a bit</a>, you're sure to find other interesting things.]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5901163823926928680/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/04/soas-research-online.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5901163823926928680"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5901163823926928680"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/04/soas-research-online.html"
         title="SOAS Research Online"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
