<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4139787167517093555</id>
   <published>2012-02-20T18:44:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2012-02-20T18:44:45.243-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Music"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Musicology"/>
   <title type="text">Forthcoming Open Access Journal: NEMO-Online Near-Eastern Musicology Online</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href="http://nemo-online.org/"&gt;NEMO-Online: Near-Eastern Musicology Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class="post-format-icon"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;div class="entry-container fix"&gt;     &lt;div class="entry fix"&gt;      &lt;div class="first-para"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;ICONEA, CERMAA and PLM are research groups  based in London&amp;nbsp;‎–‎ UK (ICONEA ), in Beirut&amp;nbsp;‎–‎ Lebanon (CERMAA ) and in  Paris ‎–‎ France (PLM).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;ICONEA (International Conference of Near-Eastern Archaeomusicology) specialises in Near and Middle-eastern archaeomusicology.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;CERMAA (CEntre de Recherches sur les Musiques Arabes et Apparentées) is dedicated to research on &lt;em&gt;maq&lt;em&gt;ā&lt;/em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt; music and modality.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;PLM (Patrimoines et Langages Musicaux) is a professional research  group of musicologists, most of them being also musicians, working at  Sorbonne Université in the realm of history of music, ethnomusicology,  music analysis and/or theory of music.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;In 2011, ICONEA and CERMAA merged and launched a new periodical of  Near and Middle-Eastern music research, in the widest sense of the term,  under the name of &amp;nbsp;NEMO-Online (Near-Eastern Musicology Online). PLM  joined NEMO-Online&amp;nbsp;as an associate research group in January 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;h1 class="posttitle"&gt;&lt;a href="http://nemo-online.org/volumes/current-issue"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Current issue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;div class="postdata fix"&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Theme: ‘Questioning Modality’ – “La modalité en question”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div class="entry fix"&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;The theme for the forthcoming issue of NEMO-Online (VOL. 1) is ”&lt;strong&gt;Questioning&amp;nbsp;Modality’&lt;/strong&gt; or, “&lt;strong&gt;La modalité en question&lt;/strong&gt;“. Contributions welcome in English, German, French and Arabic. Please email by end of November 2011 to &lt;a href="mailto:abeyhom@nemo-online.org"&gt;Amine Beyhom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Click&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://nemo-online.org/guidelinesnormes" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for guidelines&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Please read the discussion below, in English or in French, as well as &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://nemo-online.org/archives/15" target="_blank"&gt;recent postings&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href="http://nemo-online.org/archives/8" target="_blank"&gt;French&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href="http://nemo-online.org/transliteration-and-style-sheets" target="_blank"&gt;referencing guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. Please download the &lt;a href="http://nemo-online.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/NEMO-Arabic-transliteration.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;transliteration guidelines for the Arabic language&lt;/a&gt; prior to sending your paper.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussion (English) :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Winnington-Ingram’s definition (&lt;em&gt;Mode in Ancient Greek Music&lt;/em&gt;, Cambridge University Press 1936) is a classic:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mode is essentially a question of the internal  relationships of notes within a scale, especially of the predominance of  one of them over the others as a tonic, its predominance being  established in any or all of a number of ways: e.g., frequent  recurrence, its appearance in a prominent position as the first note or  the last, the delaying of its expected occurrence by some kind of  embellishment.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Other definitions, mostly influenced by Ancient Greek philosophy or by Indian music &lt;em&gt;ragas&lt;/em&gt;,  introduce the concept of ‘ethos’, or may emphasize &amp;nbsp;internal balance  between the pitches of&amp;nbsp; the scale. There is also much confusion about  the perception of “mode” and “&lt;em&gt;maq&lt;em&gt;ā&lt;/em&gt;m&lt;/em&gt;“, or with any  other terms, for a particular culture, a melodic construction the  characteristics of which being akin to Winnington-Ingram’s definition.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;However, a series of disturbing questions are raised: does mode really exist (&lt;em&gt;Harold Powers, ‘&lt;/em&gt;Is mode real? Pietro Aron, the octenary system, and polyphony,’&lt;em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;1992)  ? Is mode an intellectual construct of the West (Harold Powers,  ‘Modality as a European cultural construct,’ 1992) similar to the  construction of &amp;nbsp;’Folk Music’&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;versus ‘&lt;/em&gt;Art Music”‘ (Matthew GELBART, &lt;em&gt;The Invention of ‘Folk Music’ and ‘Art Music’&lt;/em&gt;,  Cambridge University Press, 2007) ? Can the term ‘mode’ have a single  definition, from Ancient to Contemporary Music, from Scotland and  Brittany to Iran, India and the Arabian Peninsula ? Is tonality related  to modality, and how can they be defined ? And what is the role, if any,  of formulation &amp;nbsp;in modal construction ?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Technical problems arise, such as mode &lt;em&gt;versus &lt;/em&gt;pentatonism;  defining its boundaries; where does it begin, where does it end, and  does mode influence the music or reciprocally whenever they meet ? Is  mode relevant to non octavial scales and to the construction of scales  with &lt;em&gt;genera&lt;/em&gt; ? Are modality and temperament compatible ?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Although modality is widely used in musical discussions, no definition is yet satisfactory.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;This first issue will concentrate on non Western mediaeval or  polyphonic modality, including papers dealing with the modality of  Western Folk music.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussion (French) :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;La définition du mode par Winnington-Ingram (&lt;em&gt;Mode in Ancient Greek Music&lt;/em&gt;, Cambridge University Press 1936) est considérée comme un classique :&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Mode is essentially a question of the internal  relationships of notes within a scale, especially of the predominance of  one of them over the others as a tonic, its predominance being  established in any or all of a number of ways: e.g., frequent  recurrence, its appearance in a prominent position as the first note or  the last, the delaying of its expected occurrence by some kind of  embellishment.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;D’autres définitions, peut-être influencées par les descriptions de  musiques de l’Inde ou encore par la philosophie grecque, intègrent le  concept de l’”éthos” dans cette définition, ou peuvent insister sur un  équilibre interne entre les degrés de l’échelle ; par ailleurs,  certaines conceptions confondent “mode” avec “&lt;em&gt;maqām&lt;/em&gt;” ou avec  tout autre terme se rapportant à une musique dont les caractéristiques  sont proches de celles décrites par Winnington-Ingram.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Ces définitions appellent plusieurs questionnements, dont ceux concernant l’existence même de la modalité (&lt;em&gt;Harold Powers, &lt;/em&gt;“Is mode real? Pietro Aron, the octenary system, and polyphony,”&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;1992)  et son introduction dans la réflexion sur la musique (Harold Powers,  “Modality as a European cultural construct,” 1992), avec un parallélisme  possible, sinon probable, entre cette construction et celle du concept  de musique “folk”, en opposant celle-ci à la musique dite “d’art”  (Matthew GELBART, &lt;em&gt;The Invention of “Folk Music” and “Art Music”&lt;/em&gt;, Cambridge University Press, 2007).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;D’autres questions peuvent être posées : peut-on se contenter d’une  définition unique du mode, notamment pour des musiques s’échelonnant de  l’Antiquité jusqu’à nos jours, et se déployant dans une aire  géographique qui va de l’Écosse et de la Bretagne jusqu’à l’Iran, l’Inde  et la Péninsule arabique ? La “tonalité” est-elle liée à la “modalité”,  et comment ? La modalité influence-t-elle d’autres musiques, et  est-elle influencée par elles, et comment ? Quel est le rôle de la  formularité dans la modalité ? Des &lt;em&gt;maqām &lt;/em&gt;supposés être  pentatoniques, ou basés sur une structure pentatonique, peuvent-ils être  des “modes” ? Peut-on toujours parler de modalité dans le cas de  structures non-octaviantes, ou encore basées sur des constructions  scalaires en genres ? Modalité et tempérament sont-ils compatibles ?  etc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Toutes ces questions montrent que les concepts de “mode” et de “modalité”, bien que largement répandus, sont encore à préciser.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Le premier numéro se concentrera sur la modalité hors Occident  médiéval ou polyphonique, mais incluant les musiques traditionnelles  européennes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="color: #703407;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;See the full &lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html"&gt;List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4139787167517093555/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/02/forthcoming-open-access-journal-nemo.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4139787167517093555"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4139787167517093555"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/02/forthcoming-open-access-journal-nemo.html"
         title="Forthcoming Open Access Journal: NEMO-Online Near-Eastern Musicology Online"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
