<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-906595561497374778</id>
   <published>2012-04-01T06:29:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-04-01T06:32:06.668-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Nubia"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Sudan"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="papyrology"/>
   <title type="text">Database of Medieval Nubian Texts</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href="http://www.dbmnt.uw.edu.pl/"&gt;Database of Medieval Nubian Texts (DBMNT)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;This website is the result of four years of research on the subject  “Chronological systems of Christian Nubia”, concluded with a monograph  under this very title (G. Ochała, &lt;em&gt;Chronological Systems of Christian Nubia&lt;/em&gt; [= &lt;em&gt;The Journal of Juristic Papyrology Supplement Series&lt;/em&gt; 16], Warsaw 2011). The present database is an integral part of the book  and, although the database can, should, and hopefully will exist on its  own, the book is at least difficult to use without the database. This  is because the written sources analysed in the monograph are essentially  referred to, for the sake of convenience, by their catalogue numbers,  given to them arbitrarily while preparing an offline version of the  DBMNT and preserved in the online one.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Of course, this does not preclude the utilising of the database without reading the &lt;em&gt;CSCN&lt;/em&gt;.  And to those who do so, I owe a few words of introduction: The DBMNT,  at the present stage of development, collects 733 texts of medieval  Nubian provenance (with a few exceptions of Egyptian Nubian texts) that  contain any signs of counting time by the inhabitants of the middle Nile  Valley. The assemblage is dated between the sixth and the fifteenth  centuries, roughly a millennium in which three Christian kingdoms  existed on this territory: Nobadia, Makuria, and Alwa. It has long been  known that in Christian Nubia several different dating methods were  employed, yet the only one that has so far drawn scholars’ more detailed  attention is the Nubian lunar calendar (Bagnall – Worp 1986; &lt;em&gt;CSBE&lt;/em&gt;,  pp. 313–314). Apart from general statements on the types of the  chronological systems used and detailed commentaries on dates of  particular texts, the whole issue has never been studied  comprehensively.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Nubians used as many as five annual dating methods (the Era of  Diocletian/the Martyrs, the indictional system, the so-called Christian  eras, the Era of the Saracens/the Hegira, and reganl years) and two  calendrical systems (the Egyptian solar calendar and a lunar calendar).  There are also attestations of the names of the weekdays used in  Christian Nubia as well as some traces of a liturgical calendar of the  Nubian Church. All known texts, both published and yet unpublished but  somehow available to me, attesting to the use of the above-listed  chronological systems have been carefully collected and analysed and are  now presented to the user.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Due to the state of publication and/or inaccessibility of  particular sources, some of the fields in the DBMNT must remain empty,  especially those concerning physical description. However, the database  is not, by its nature, a closed structure and it is to be hoped that in  time such objects will be located, described, and photographed, so that  the missing information could be supplemented. It is also my intention  to conduct further work on the DBMNT to develop it into a fully  operational database collecting the whole corpus of the medieval Nubian  written sources, not only the specimens containing dating lemmata. In  both these tasks, supplementing the existing records and adding new  ones, the collaboration of other scholars is important and in fact much  desired. Therefore, at a certain stage of development, willing  contributors will be granted access to editing the DBMNT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;It is also worth mentioning here that the DBMNT is paralleled by  another project connected with digitizing the Nubian written sources.  This is the so-called Nubian SoSOL, a division of Son of Suda On Line, a  modern papyrological platform designed to bring together the existing  papyrological digital resources in the framework of the project  Integrating Digital Papyrology (&lt;a href="http://idp.atlantides.org/trac/idp/wiki/"&gt;http://idp.atlantides.org/trac/idp/wiki/&lt;/a&gt;).  The Nubian SoSOL has been initiated by Giovanni R. Ruffini (Fairfield  University) with my collaboration and will contain transcriptions of all  medieval Nubian textual finds. The DBMNT will be linked to the Nubian  SoSOL as the latter will develop.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The DBMNT is modelled on other online papyrological databases and  the user familiar with these tools will have no problems with using it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The bibliographical references are given according to ‘A Guide to  the Texts of Medieval Nubia’ by Grzegorz Ochała and Giovanni R. Ruffini,  available online at &lt;a href="http://www.medievalnubia.info/dev/index.php/Guide_to_the_Texts"&gt;www.medievalnubia.info&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="signature"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Grzegorz Ochała&lt;br /&gt;Department of Papyrology&lt;br /&gt;Institute of Archaeology&lt;br /&gt;University of Warsaw&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/906595561497374778/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/04/database-of-medieval-nubian-texts.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/906595561497374778"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/906595561497374778"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/04/database-of-medieval-nubian-texts.html"
         title="Database of Medieval Nubian Texts"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
