<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6993282477788827973</id>
   <published>2013-11-10T09:05:00.006-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-11-10T09:25:57.769-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">The Palestine Exploration Fund flickr Photostream</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.flickr.com/people/palestineexplorationfund/"><span class="character-name-holder">The Palestine  Exploration Fund flickr Photostream</span></a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span class="character-name-holder"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The PEF was founded in 1865 and is the oldest organization in the world  created specifically for the study of the Levant, the southern portion  of which was conventionally known as ‘Palestine’. The PEF is a major  bridge and information resource for the public and academic community.<br /><br />It publishes an internationally respected journal, the Palestine  Exploration Quarterly, and brings the latest archaeological results and  research to the public in a series of regular lectures. The PEF promotes  ongoing research through annual grants to scholars across the world.<br /><br />The PEF archives hold over 40,000 photographs of Palestine, Jordan and  Syria taken from 1850 onwards. The PEF collections also include  archaeological artefacts, natural history specimens, maps, manuscripts,  and paintings. Our unparalleled library attracts scholars from around  the world. These facilities are available to our members for research,  study, and publication purposes.<br /><br />The photos shown here are low resolution files from our digital picture  library, with a particular focus on our collection of 19th century  photographs. If you would like to reproduce any of these at high  resolution, please contact our curator for reproduction fees which help  fund our charitable work.  <br /><br />You are free to use any of the low-res images and metadata presented  here online or for teaching and research, but please let us know if you  intend to do so by contacting: execsec@pef.org.uk. Please include in  your caption: "Courtesy of the Palestine Exploration Fund". <br /><br />You can join us for an annual subscription of £36 (£18 for students) or  £54 for a joint membership, which gives you access to the library and  collection, lectures and 3 journals published annually. A number of PEF  and PEF related publications feature the photographic collection. Visit  the PEF website for more information.<br /><br />Acknowledgments: the PEF wishes to thank the following people  contributed to the digitisation and gathering of information on these  images over the years: Rupert Chapman, Felicity Cobbing, Lydia Collins,  Shimon Gibson and Pamela Magrill.  <br /><br />PEF website editors: Jack Green and Dan Pett</span></span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">And see AWOL's list of <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/11/institutional-flickr-photostreams.html">Institutional flickr Photostreams</a> </div><span class="character-name-holder"><br /></span>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6993282477788827973/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/11/the-palestine-exploration-fund-flickr.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6993282477788827973"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6993282477788827973"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/11/the-palestine-exploration-fund-flickr.html"
         title="The Palestine Exploration Fund flickr Photostream"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
