<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8678167188248820030</id>
   <published>2010-12-03T16:49:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2010-12-03T16:52:36.577-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Soon to be entirely online: Journals of the British School at Athens</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: small;">A few weeks ago Cambridge University Press <a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/jsp/cjo/common/newslink.jsp?newsid=3408&amp;url=http://journals.cambridge.org/images/fileUpload/images/PBSR_AND_BSA__press_release.pdf">announced</a> that the journals of the British Schools at Athens and Rome were joining Cambridge University Press.&nbsp; While it is not open access, it is worthy of note since the complete runs of these journals are now available online and widely licensed from CUP and JSTOR (see below):</span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Cambridge University Press has announced that it will become the new home of <a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=ATH"><i><b>The Annual of the British School at Athens</b></i></a> (BSA) and the <a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=ROM"><i><b>Papers of the British School at Rome</b></i></a> (PBSR) from January 2011. This is the second consecutive year the Cambridge list has seen expansion and is recognition of the Press’s reputation as one of the foremost publishers of classical scholarship in the world.</span><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><br /><i>The Annual of the British School at Athens</i> publishes accounts of the School's projects as well as articles on a wide range of Hellenic subjects spanning a variety of disciplines from art to archaeometry and covering Greece throughout history. It is the School’s major publication and one of the most important journals in the field. BSA will publish its 106th volume with Cambridge in 2011.</span><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><br /><i>Papers of the British School at Rome</i> is one of the most highly-regarded journals covering the archaeology, history and art history of Italy and other parts of the Mediterranean area up to modern times. It is edited by senior academics from the British School at Rome’s international pool of affiliated scholars, and is the School’s major publication. PBSR will publish its 79th volume with Cambridge in 2011.</span> </blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Both journals will be available in print and electronic formats, providing online access to current content for the<br />first time. As well as publishing future issues, an online archive of all <i>BSA</i> and <i>PBSR</i> volumes will be available as part of the Cambridge Journals Digital Archive...</span> </span></blockquote>The collection also, of course, includes the Archaeological Reports (AR)<br /><br /><a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=ARE">Archaeological  Reports</a>&nbsp; (at Cambridge University Press)<br /><a href="http://www.jstor.org/action/showPublication?journalCode=archrepo">Archaeological Reports</a>&nbsp; (backlist at JSTOR)<br /><div style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;<img alt="Archaeological Reports" src="http://journals.cambridge.org/cover_images/ARE/ARE.jpg" title="Archaeological Reports" />                                                                    </div>ISSN: 0570-6084<br />EISSN: 2041-4102                                                 <br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Archaeological Reports</i> is published by the Society for the  Promotion of Hellenic Studies and the British School at Athens, for  their subscribers.  'Archaeology in Greece', compiled annually by the  Director of the British School at Athens, is the only account of recent  archaeological work in Greece published in English.  It is supplemented  each year by a regional report on archaeology and research from other  parts of the ancient Greek and Byzantine world: South Italy, Sicily,  Sardinia, Albania, Cyprus, Asia Minor and the Black Sea are covered  regularly.  New acquisitions to UK antiquities’ collections and their  conservation also feature.</span>&nbsp; </blockquote><br /><span style="font-size: small;">T</span>he BSA is also working in collaboration with the <span style="font-size: 100%;">École française d’Athènes</span> to jointly produce&nbsp; <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/11/archaeology-in-greece-onlinechronique.html">Archaeology in Greece Online /  Chronique des fouilles en ligne</a> entirely in  electronic format.&nbsp; Eventually AR will be incorporated into the online project (and indeed  much of the online material went into producing the paper AR), and from  this year on will be up-to-date online, putting in new entries throughout the year as they are produced and completed.<br /><br /><br /><a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayJournal?jid=ATH">Annual of the British School at Athens</a>&nbsp;  (at Cambridge University Press)<br /><a href="http://www.jstor.org/action/showPublication?journalCode=annubritschoathe">Annual of the British School at Athens</a>&nbsp; (backlist at JSTOR)<br /><div style="text-align: center;"><b><b> <img alt="Annual of the British School at Athens" src="http://journals.cambridge.org/cover_images/ATH/ATH.jpg" title="Annual of the British School at Athens" />                                                                    </b></b></div><b><b>                               </b></b>ISSN: 0068-2454<br />EISSN: 2045-2403                                                 <br /><b><b></b></b><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Annual of the British School at Athens</i>, publishes accounts  of the School's projects as well as articles on a wide range of Hellenic  subjects spanning a variety disciplines from art to archaeometry and  covering Greece throughout history. It is the School’s major publication  and one of the most important journals in the field. <i>BSA</i> will publish its 106th volume with Cambridge in 2011.&nbsp;</span><b><b>                                       </b></b></blockquote><div><br />And see also <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/06/ancient-world-in-jstor.html">The Ancient World in JSTOR</a> the full list of journals in JSTOR with substantial representation of the Ancient World.</div><div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /><a expr:id="data:post.url" expr:name="data:post.title" href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-create.g?blogID=5130549244386310434" onclick="return addthis_sendto()" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onmouseover="return addthis_open(this, &quot;&quot;, this.id, this.name);"><img alt="Bookmark and Share so Your Real Friends Know that You Know" height="16" src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif" style="border: 0pt none;" width="125" /></a></div><br /><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8678167188248820030/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/12/now-entirely-online-journals-of-british.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8678167188248820030"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8678167188248820030"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/12/now-entirely-online-journals-of-british.html"
         title="Soon to be entirely online: Journals of the British School at Athens"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
