<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6722662586229612944</id>
   <published>2012-12-20T15:43:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2012-12-20T15:43:52.852-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Art"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Statuary"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Reception"/>
   <title type="text">Monumenta rariora: The Reception of Antique Statuary in Collections of Engravin</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://mora.sns.it/">Monumenta rariora: The Reception of Antique Statuary in Collections of Engravings</a> <br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://mora.sns.it/res_frameset/testata_monumenta.jpg" class="decoded" height="23" src="http://mora.sns.it/res_frameset/testata_monumenta.jpg" width="400" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="n10">&nbsp;</span><span class="n10">Il progetto prevede la realizzazione di un corpus di        repertori di incisioni a stampa sulla statuaria antica la cui gestione informatizzata        permetta una fruizione ottimale e contestualizzata dei testi che lo costituiscono,        in genere di difficile reperimento.<br />      <br />      Il lavoro è stato strutturato su due fronti differenti ma correlati:        da una parte la considerazione dell'oggetto rappresentato da un punto di        vista archeologico e della sua storia collezionistica, dall'altra lo studio        dell'incisione finalizzato alla determinazione di vari rapporti intercorrenti        all'interno delle tradizioni culturali che afferiscono all'opera medesima.<br />      <br />      La creazione di una base di dati scientificamente sostenibile, rigorosa        e continuamente aggiornabile, si accompagna ad un sistema di utilizzo che        permette agevolmente l'intera fruizione e che fornisce all'utente la possibilità        di seguire dei personali "itinerari" di ricerca.                            </span></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="n10">The  project foresees the realization of a corpus of  engravings collections on ancient sculpture.  Its computerised  management permits  an optimal and contextualised  fruition of  the  texts  compiling it, which are generally very difficult to find.<br />        <br />      The work has been approached from two different angles which are  correlated: on one side, consideration of the represented object from an  archaeological point of view and the history of its collection, and on  the other, the study of the finalised engravings so as to determine the  various underlying  relationships within the cultural traditions  referring to the work itself.<br />      <br />      The creation of a scientifically sustainable data base, rigorous  and continuously up-datable, is accompanied by a user system  which  easily permits its entire fruition and gives the user the possibility of  following personal search" itineraries."&nbsp;                                 </span></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6722662586229612944/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/12/monumenta-rariora-reception-of-antique.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6722662586229612944"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6722662586229612944"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/12/monumenta-rariora-reception-of-antique.html"
         title="Monumenta rariora: The Reception of Antique Statuary in Collections of Engravin"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
