<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8810082865392574951</id>
   <published>2011-09-07T21:07:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-09-07T21:08:02.087-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">JSTOR News: Free Access to Early Journal Content and Serving “Unaffiliated” Users</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><div style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://about.jstor.org/news-events/news/jstor%E2%80%93free-access-early-journal-content">JSTOR–Free Access to Early Journal Content and Serving “Unaffiliated” Users</a></div><div class="node node-type-story clearfix" id="node-26908"><div style="text-align: left;">                </div><blockquote><div class="meta" style="text-align: left;">               <span class="submitted">          <strong> <span style="font-size: x-small;">SUBMITTED ON:</span></strong><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Wednesday, September 7, 2011 - 3:02am GMT        </span></span>                 </div><div>      </div></blockquote><div class="content"><blockquote><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Dear Library and Publisher Colleagues,</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;"> </div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">I  am writing to share exciting news:&nbsp; today, we are making journal  content on JSTOR published prior to 1923 in the United States and prior  to 1870 elsewhere, freely available to the public for reading and  downloading. This includes nearly 500,000 articles from more than 200  journals, representing approximately 6% of the total content on JSTOR.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;">  </div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">We  are taking this step as part of our continuous effort to provide the  widest possible access to the content on JSTOR while ensuring the  long-term preservation of this important material.&nbsp; To date, we have  primarily provided access to people through a growing base of libraries  and institutions. In 1995, only ten journals were digitized and  available to just a few universities.&nbsp; Today, millions of people from  more than 7,000 institutions in 153 countries have access to journals on  JSTOR through their universities, colleges, high schools, businesses,  research institutions, museums, historical societies, and public  libraries.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;">  </div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This constitutes remarkable progress and impact, but  there remain many people who are not affiliated with institutions who  want access to the knowledge preserved in JSTOR. We have taken a variety  of steps over the years to serve them. First, in 1999 we began  partnering with our publishers and scholarly societies to provide access  to their journals to their society members and other individuals  through what we call our Individual Access Program. More than 300  journals are accessible to individuals in this way today.&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, in  2006 we initiated another program–the Publisher Sales Service–to enable  publishers to sell their articles to the public through the JSTOR  platform. There are 762 journals that have articles for sale in this way  today, with prices set by each individual publisher. Third, in 2009 we  began partnering with universities and colleges to offer their alumni  access to content on JSTOR. There are 18 schools in this pilot program  today.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">While these efforts are serving some users, there is more  that can be done. About a year ago, we started working on a next set of  initiatives to test and provide additional forms of access to content on  JSTOR for individuals. These initiatives include: supporting publishers  who wish to test different price points for their articles that are  part of the Publisher Sales Service; working with our publishers to  experiment with a new capability for individuals to read some articles  online without charge if they register with us; and providing free  access for individuals to the early journal content available through  JSTOR. We are very excited about the potential for this next wave of  efforts. We are confident that they will result in broader access to  scholarship in the near term, and enable JSTOR and our publishers to  test and develop new models that meet the wider public’s needs in the  future.</span> </div></blockquote><blockquote><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">I hope you share our excitement about today’s  announcement. We look forward to continuing to work with you to further  access to individuals in the future. More information about the <a href="http://about.jstor.org/participate-jstor/individuals/early-journal-content">Early Journal Content</a> is available, including an <a href="http://about.jstor.org/participate-jstor/individuals/early-journal-content-faqs">FAQ</a>.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;"> </div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">On  a final note, I realize that some people may speculate that making the  Early Journal Content free to the public today is a direct response to  widely-publicized events over the summer involving an individual who was  indicted for downloading a substantial portion of content from JSTOR,  allegedly for the purpose of posting it to file sharing sites. While we  had been working on releasing the pre-1923/pre-1870 content before the  incident took place, it would be inaccurate to say that these events  have had no impact on our planning. We considered whether to delay or  accelerate this action, largely out of concern that people might draw  incorrect conclusions about our motivations. In the end, we decided to  press ahead with our plans to make the Early Journal Content available,  which we believe is in the best interest of our library and publisher  partners, and students, scholars, and researchers everywhere.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;"> </div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Please feel free to let me know if you have questions.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;"> </div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Sincerely,</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"> </div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Laura Brown<br />JSTOR Managing Director</span></div></blockquote></div></div><br />And see<span style="font-weight: bold;"> </span><span style="font-family: 'PrimaSans BT,Verdana,sans-serif';"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/06/ancient-world-in-jstor.html">The   Ancient World in JSTOR</a>: AWOL's full list of journals in JSTOR with   substantial coverage of the Ancient World.</span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8810082865392574951/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/jstor-news-free-access-to-early-journal.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8810082865392574951"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8810082865392574951"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/jstor-news-free-access-to-early-journal.html"
         title="JSTOR News: Free Access to Early Journal Content and Serving “Unaffiliated” Users"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
