<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3839745068287155043</id>
   <published>2011-12-08T11:01:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2011-12-08T15:57:12.249-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">ISAW Digital Programs Vision Statement</title>
   <content type="html">AWOL is a product of the &lt;a href="http://isaw.nyu.edu/library"&gt;Library of the Institute for the Study of the Ancient Word&lt;/a&gt;, in close association with the &lt;a href="http://isaw.nyu.edu/about/departments/digital-programs"&gt;ISAW Digital Programs Department&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp; ISAW Library fully endorses the following vision statement.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://isaw.nyu.edu/about/departments/digital-programs"&gt;Institute for the Study of the Ancient World Digital Programs Vision Statement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div id="content-core" style="font-family: inherit;"&gt;&lt;div class="" id="parent-fieldname-text"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Vision&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Unfettered access to ancient world information: any resource, any time, anywhere, anyone.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2&gt; &lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Mission&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Create key information resources for ancient studies, together with the platforms and communities that enable them.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;In order to shape and secure the future of innovative teaching and  research at ISAW and beyond, we work with others to nurture new and  important information resources for the ancient world, especially those  that connect and contextualize information across institutional,  methodological, and technological divides. ISAW takes a holistic,  interdisciplinary approach to ancient studies, eschewing the  geographically and linguistically bounded modes of scholarly inquiry and  communication that have dominated the field. Accordingly, &lt;a href="http://isaw.nyu.edu/about/departments/digital-programs/digital-programs-staff"&gt;the Digital Programs team&lt;/a&gt; builds infrastructure that bridges gaps in content and function while  handling the inherent diversity of languages, scripts, geography,  chronology, methodology, and the like. The resulting tools and data  further ISAW’s mission best when we create them in collaboration with  scholars, students and enthusiasts from both inside and outside the  Institute and empower them as creators, curators, and users. It is  becoming increasingly clear that without active and participatory user  communities, digital information is at risk of decay, loss, and  irrelevance. Moreover, quality and sustainability are undercut by  sequestration behind paywalls, idiosyncratic interfaces, proprietary  formats, and rigid editorial processes.  Therefore, we cultivate  empowered communities through partnership, openness, usable tools and an  embrace of the web with the belief that users will identify, invent,  contextualize, and promote better resources for the study of antiquity  than any single project or institutional team.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Digital Programs team has a role in everything from basic  information technology support and the management of the Institute’s  website to a range of &lt;a class="internal-link" href="http://isaw.nyu.edu/online-resources"&gt;online publication projects&lt;/a&gt; touching on historical geography, papyrology, epigraphy and more. Under the leadership of the &lt;a href="http://isaw.nyu.edu/people/staff/tom-elliott/"&gt;Associate Director for Digital Programs&lt;/a&gt;,  the team works closely with colleagues at ISAW and across NYU, as well  as with collaborators at a number of other institutions. Digital  Programs work is funded through a combination of ISAW funds and grants  from the &lt;a href="http://www.neh.gov/"&gt;National Endowment for the Humanities&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://mellon.org/"&gt;Andrew W. Mellon Foundation&lt;/a&gt; and other entities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3839745068287155043/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/12/isaw-digital-programs-vision-statement.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3839745068287155043"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3839745068287155043"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/12/isaw-digital-programs-vision-statement.html"
         title="ISAW Digital Programs Vision Statement"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
   <georss:featurename>Institute for the Study of the Ancient World, 15 E 84th St, New York, NY 10028, USA</georss:featurename>
   <georss:point>40.7799072 -73.9603815</georss:point>
   <georss:box>40.7678837 -73.9801225 40.791930699999995 -73.9406405</georss:box>
</entry>
