<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3634147189668231873</id>
   <published>2013-01-20T08:58:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-01-20T08:58:51.187-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New Open Access Journal: Open Journal of Archaeometry</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.pagepress.org/journals/index.php/arc/index">Open Journal of Archaeometry</a><br />eISSN: 2038-1956<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.pagepress.org/journals/public/arc_mini.jpg" class="decoded" height="200" src="http://www.pagepress.org/journals/public/arc_mini.jpg" width="141" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>The</strong><strong> Open Journal of Archaeometry </strong>is  a new, completely peer-reviewed, Open Access, international scientific  journal published by PAGEPress Publications, Pavia, Italy. It is  dedicated to the publication of research articles, short communications  and review papers on every aspect of archaeometry.  </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Archaeometry,  also known as archaeological science, applies scientific techniques to  the analysis of archaeological materials. Research topics mainly  comprise the following disciplines and analyzing techniques:</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><ul class="unIndentedList"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> physical and chemical dating methods, e.g. <sup>14</sup>C and luminescence dating, which provide archaeologists with numerical and relative chronologies</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> analyses of artifacts, concerning provenance, technology and types of use</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> environmental approaches, which provide information on past changes in landscape, climate, flora, and fauna</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> anthropological studies dealing with diet, nutrition, health, and pathology of people</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> mathematical methods for data treatment including the role of computers  in handling, analyzing, and modeling the vast sources of data</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">  remote-sensing and geophysical-survey applications, and conservation  sciences involving the study of decay processes and the development of  new methods of conservation</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">We cannot yet offer you a  journal with a long history and reputation, but we can guarantee fast  and high quality services for authors and publication online within 3  weeks of the acceptance date. To ensure publication precedence for  authors, and to provide a lasting record of scientific discussion, the  articles are permanently archived and fully citable.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">With respect  to the goals of the Budapest Open Access Initiative, Open Access to  scientific and scholarly literature means to us "its free availability  on the public internet, permitting any users to read, download, copy,  distribute, print, search, or link to the full texts of these articles.  The only constraint on reproduction and distribution, and the only role  for copyright in this domain, should be to give authors control over the  integrity of their work and the right to be properly acknowledged and  cited". The more, we believe that:</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><ul class="unIndentedList"><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Articles that are available by Open Access are likely to be read and cited more often than those not Open Access</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Publicly-funded research should be made available to be read and used without access barriers</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"> It is beneficial for the general public to have access to published scientific article</span>s</li></ul></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: #333333; line-height: 25px;">See the full&nbsp;</span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color: #333333; line-height: 25px;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html" style="color: #5588aa; text-decoration: none;">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></span></div><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3634147189668231873/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/01/new-open-access-journal-open-journal-of.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3634147189668231873"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3634147189668231873"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/01/new-open-access-journal-open-journal-of.html"
         title="New Open Access Journal: Open Journal of Archaeometry"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
