<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6662916165749059457</id>
   <published>2013-02-19T14:57:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-02-19T14:57:39.023-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Iraq"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Assyria"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">The Central Palace of Tiglath-pileser III at Nimrud and the Polish Center of Mediterranean Archaeology’s Excavation (1974-1976): A Digital Publication</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.learningsites.com/CPalace_Nimrud/CP_html-pgs/CPalace_genl_html/CPalace_frame-layout.html">The Central Palace of Tiglath-pileser III at Nimrud and the Polish Center of Mediterranean Archaeology’s Excavation (1974-1976): A Digital Publication</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">The  Polish Centre of Mediterranean Archaeology returned to re-excavate the  site of the Central Palace of Tiglath-pileser III (744-727 BCE) at <a href="http://www.learningsites.com/Support_pages/Support_graphics/NearEast_500m-map01.GIF" rel="lightbox" title="Map of the Near East">Nimrud</a> (ancient Kalhu) near the city of Mosul in northeastern Iraq in 1974,  because the Palace was the least known and least understood of the  buildings on <a href="http://www.learningsites.com/CPalace_Nimrud/CP_images/Drawings/Nimrud_citadel-plan_RPS-1992_4Website01.gif" rel="lightbox" title="Plan of the Nimrud citadel">Nimrud's citadel</a>.&nbsp;  It was hoped that new excavations would elucidate this poorly preserved  Palace with more up-to-date excavation techniques and new finds.&nbsp; The  excavation was supposed to make the Central Palace a source for the  study of the life and times of this important ancient Assyrian king.&nbsp;  Many fragments of Assyrian bas-relief, not only those of Tiglath-pileser  III, were discovered, some re-excavated in the trenches of the previous  excavator, Austen Henry Layard. Then the field director, Janusz  Meuszynski, died in 1976, and the final reports were never completed.</span></span><br /><br />       <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">There  are too few examples of Tiglath-pileser’s bas-reliefs in the total  corpus of Assyrian bas-relief to allow the results of the Polish project  to remain unpublished.&nbsp; The Polish finds are an extremely valuable  resource.&nbsp; An additional and disturbing fact is that individual  bas-relief sculptures (some with inscriptions) have been appearing on  the antiquities market, looted from the site museum storerooms at  Nimrud.&nbsp; Some of the bas-reliefs have been broken up into pieces to  obscure their origin and in order to obtain more money from several  rather than from the one original fragment.&nbsp; Many of the better examples  of bas-relief from this excavation are now on the international art  market as a result of illicit activities (theft) at Nimrud subsequent to  the Gulf War of 1991 (there is increasing anxiety among scholars --  expressed in a <a href="http://www.learningsites.com/Support_pages/addinfo.htm#Archaeology%20Channel">2003 interview</a> -- that war in Iraq will lead to further destruction of key monuments, like those at Nimrud).</span></span><br /><br />       <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">What  we know of Tiglath-pileser’s Palace is that many of the themes of  earlier and later sculpture are to be found on its wall decoration.&nbsp;  And, there are new motifs and the syntax of the sculpture, the way  scenes were portrayed, the placement of the vignettes of individual  parts of scenes on the faces of the slabs, and details of the garment  decorations have their own character and style.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />       <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Richard  Sobolewski and (the late) Samuel Paley were to publish the results of  the excavation in digital format with top plans, photographs, and  comparative material from museums and Layard’s archives.&nbsp; Learning Sites  will finish the publication.  The digital format will allow the reader  to access all the relevant data through appropriate links from  interactive 3D computer models of the remains and in reconstructed  panels of the wall decorations.&nbsp; Fragments of bas-relief and  inscriptions from the periods of Ashur-nasir-pal II and Shalmaneser III  discovered during the course of the excavation will also be incorporated  into this publication, as well as the scant remains of the  post-Assyrian buildings built on the Central Palace site.&nbsp; The corpus of  photographs of the Polish Center's excavation will be available  permanently on this Website.&nbsp; The final computer model and the  publication will be prepared, marketed, and distributed by Learning  Sites, Inc., in collaboration with scholars from around the world.</span></span><br /><br />       <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">These  Webpages will be where the computer visualizations of the remains,  photographs, drawings, descriptions, and analyses will be collocated en  route to their full publication.&nbsp; Material here will expand and change  as the project progresses.&nbsp; From the <b>Index</b> above you may access the various pages of text and images.<br />               &nbsp;</span></span><br />                                                         <br /><center>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #000099;">The  research and compilation of the manuscript for this final publication  were made possible through a generous grant from The Shelby White - Leon  Levy Program for Archaeological Publications (<a href="http://www.fas.harvard.edu/%7esemitic/white_levy_program.html" target="NewWindow">http://www.fas.harvard.edu/~semitic/white_levy_program.html</a>),&nbsp;</span></span></span>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #000099;">and&nbsp;</span></span></span>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #000099;">the generosity of the Polish Centre of Mediterranean Archaeology,&nbsp;</span></span></span>            <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #000099;">the UB Foundation, and&nbsp;</span><span style="color: #000099;">individual supporters.</span></span></span></center></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6662916165749059457/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/02/the-central-palace-of-tiglath-pileser.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6662916165749059457"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6662916165749059457"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/02/the-central-palace-of-tiglath-pileser.html"
         title="The Central Palace of Tiglath-pileser III at Nimrud and the Polish Center of Mediterranean Archaeology’s Excavation (1974-1976): A Digital Publication"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
