<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-17205310452854456</id>
   <published>2012-06-08T09:15:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-06-08T09:15:26.651-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Image database of the Museum of Antiquities and the Plaster-cast Collection of the Leipzig University</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/drupal/?q=node/209">Image database of the Museum of Antiquities and the Plaster-cast Collection of the Leipzig University</a><br />Prof. Dr. Hans-Ulrich Cain, Prof. Dr. Reinhard Förtsch<br /><div class="content"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Museum_of_Antiquities_of_the_University_of_Leipzig">Museum of Antiquities of the Leipzig University</a>, which was founded in  1840, is an archaeological teaching collection that contains plaster  casts and originals of ancient art from the Mediterranean area. As  academic collections usually do, it consists of an extensive assortment  of ancient minor arts objects aiming to give a representative and  systematic cross section of ancient art. The collection mainly contains  Greek and Etruscan vases, terracottas, statuettes and bronze objects as  well as other minor artworks. Large sized sculpture is available to  teaching and science mainly in form of plaster-casts of important works  of statuary and architectural sculpture. Originals are only represented  by a few portrait heads and some fragments of statues and attic grave  reliefs.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In the past few years, along with the publication of the collection’s  holdings, a project has been initiated in close cooperation with the  CoDArchLab of the Cologne University to set up an image-database. In the  course of a photo campaign the CoDArchLab documented the exhibited and  archived monuments of ancient sculpture and made them available to the  public via Arachne, some of these for the first time. After this the  integration of the approximately 700 reproductions of ancient  sculptures, that were preserved after World War II or newly acquired  since the reconstruction of the plaster-cast collection in 1999, began.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The next step is to record and gradually transfer the original  collection focus of the Museum of Antiquities, which evolved in a  historical process in the 19th and early 20th century, into Arachne: the  so-called minor arts. The digital capture and photographic  documentation serve as a basis for the further analysis and processing  of the objects from the Leipzig collection. Their integration into  Arachne as a central object-database of classical studies is to make  them available to archaeologists and students for free worldwide online  research.</span><br /><br /><div class="einsprung"><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/arachne/index.php?view%5Blayout%5D=sammlungen_item&amp;view%5Bcaller%5D%5Bproject%5D=209&amp;search%5Bconstraints%5D%5Bsammlungen%5D%5BsearchSeriennummer%5D=1005591&amp;view%5Bactive_tab%5D=KontextbrowserDiv">to the collection of the Museum of Antiquities</a></span></div><div class="einsprung"><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/arachne/index.php?view%5Blayout%5D=search_result_category&amp;view%5Bcaller%5D%5Bproject%5D=209&amp;view%5Bcategory%5D=objekt&amp;search%5Bdata%5D=PICS&amp;search%5Bconstraints%5D%5Bobjekt%5D%5BsearchAufbewahrungObjekt%5D=Antikenmuseum+Universit%C3%A4t+Leipzig+Deutschlan">to the individual objects of the Museum of Antiquities</a></span></div><div class="einsprung"><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/arachne/index.php?view%5Blayout%5D=sammlungen_item&amp;search%5Bconstraints%5D%5Bsammlungen%5D%5BsearchSeriennummer%5D=1005701&amp;view%5Bcaller%5D%5Bproject%5D=209&amp;view%5Bactive_tab%5D=KontextbrowserDiv">to the Plaster-cast Collection of the Museum of Antiquities</a></span></div></blockquote><br /></div><br /><br /><div><a href="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/drupal/"><img alt="Arachne" src="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/template/images/logo.gif" /></a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/17205310452854456/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/06/image-database-of-museum-of-antiquities.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/17205310452854456"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/17205310452854456"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/06/image-database-of-museum-of-antiquities.html"
         title="Image database of the Museum of Antiquities and the Plaster-cast Collection of the Leipzig University"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
