<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5228379313202117233</id>
   <published>2013-09-09T08:30:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-09-09T08:55:45.871-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Cuneiform"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Iraq"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Mesopotamia"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Assyria"/>
   <title type="text">State Archives of Assyria Online</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">[First posted in AWOL 1 July 2010. Updated 9 September 2013] </span><br /><br /><a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/saao">State Archives of Assyria Online (SAAo)</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">State Archives of Assyria Online (SAAo) is an open-access web  resource that aims to make the rich Neo-Assyrian materials found in the  royal archives of Nineveh, and elsewhere, more widely accessible. </span></blockquote><blockquote> <span style="font-size: x-small;"> Based on an existing ASCII text database created by Simo Parpola and his  team at the University of Helsinki, the online transliterations and  translations are those of the standard editions in the series "State  Archives of Assyria". All of the <a href="http://www.helsinki.fi/science/saa/saa.html#Published">published volumes</a> are accessible online, in addition to volume 2 of the companion series  "State Archives of Assyria Studies", the edition of the Eponym Lists and  Chronicles. The web presentation and linguistic annotation are carried  out using <a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/">tools and standards</a>developed by Steve Tinney (University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia).</span><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The state correspondence of king Sargon II (published in volumes 1,  5, 15 and 17) was the first chunk of the SAAo materials to have been  "lemmatised", providing glossaries and interactive translation  facilities which allow the user to check and question the translations  in detail and make the corpus fully searchable, in order to facilitate  and encourage an active understanding of the primary sources. This is  the work of a team headed by Karen Radner (University College London)  and funded by the British Arts and Humanities Research Council. The  research project "Mechanisms of Communication in an Ancient Empire: The  Correspondence between the King of Assyria and his Magnates in the 8th  Century BC" (AH/F016581/1; 2008-2013) also included the preparation of a  new edition of the Nimrud Letters, parts of the state correspondence of  Tiglath-pileser III and Sargon, by Mikko Luukko (volume 19), which was  published simultaneously in print and online in March 2013. </span></blockquote><blockquote> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Other parts of the SAAo materials are being made available in the  same manner. During his time at UCL, Mikko Luukko lemmatised the  prophecies (volume 9) and part of the royal correspondence of the 7th  century BC (volumes 13 and 16). Melanie Groß, as part of the research  project "Royal Institutional Households in First Millennium BC  Mesopotamia" (Fonds zur Förderung der wissenschaftlichen Forschung, S  10802-G18; 2009-2011) headed by Heather D. Baker (University of Vienna),  lemmatised the private legal documents (volumes 6 and 14). - As of  March 2013, volumes 1, 5-6, 9, 13-17 and 19 have been lemmatised.</span><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Online portals provide context and explanatory materials for SAAo. Hence, the website <a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/saao/knpp/">"Knowledge and Power in the Neo-Assyrian Empire"</a>, created by Radner, Eleanor Robson  (University of Cambridge) and Tinney with funding from the British  Higher Education Academy, is dedicated to the 7th century letters,  queries and reports exchanged between kings Esarhaddon and Assurbanipal  and their scholarly advisors; the companion corpus is  <a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/saao/knpp/corpus/">http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/saao/knpp/corpus/</a>.  Another such portal, "Assyrian Empire Builders" is devoted to the 8th  century political correspondence as part of the UCL research project,  with a companion corpus at <a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/saao/aebp/corpus">Assyrian Empire Builders</a>.  Further portals are planned.</span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/saao/corpus">State Archives of Assyria Volumes Online</a></div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/saao">State Archives of Assyria  Online (SAAo)</a> is a component of <a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/index.html">Oracc</a></div><div><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=116259103207720939" id="data:post.url" name="data:post.title" onclick="return addthis_sendto()" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onmouseover="'return"></a><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5228379313202117233/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/07/state-archives-of-assyria-online-saao.html#comment-form"
         title="5 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5228379313202117233"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5228379313202117233"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/07/state-archives-of-assyria-online-saao.html"
         title="State Archives of Assyria Online"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
