<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8023918866722937289</id>
   <published>2011-06-09T14:57:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-06-10T12:43:08.254-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal:  Museum Anthropology Review</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://scholarworks.iu.edu/journals/index.php/mar/index">Museum Anthropology Review</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Museum Anthropology Review</i> (MAR) is an open access journal whose  purpose is the wide dissemination of articles, reviews, essays, and  other content advancing the field of material culture and museum  studies, broadly conceived.<br /><br />While centered on the concerns of museum anthropology, </span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Museum Anthropology Review</i>  is a highly interdisciplinary journal that embraces work being done in  numerous fields concerned with the role of museums in social life and  with the study of material culture, past and present. Since its founding  in February 2007, the journal has published smart, significant work by  scholars--both junior and well established--working in folklore studies,  vernacular architecture studies, archaeology, linguistic anthropology,  religious studies, museum studies, history, art history, and  ethnomusicology, in addition to cultural anthropology. It is hoped that  the journal can promote cross-disciplinary dialogue between all of these  fields and others with which they share an interest in material culture  and the multifaceted work of museums. The journal is committed to an  international perspective and to rigorous scholarship, as well as to  presenting work that can improve professional practice in museums and  further the theoretical, empirical and methodological development of  material culture studies.<br /><br />As an open access journal, </span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Museum Anthropology Review</i> is committed to the development of new approaches to scholarly communication. Like many other open access journals, <i>Museum Anthropology Review</i>  seeks to rewrite the terms under which scholarship is made available in  a era of dramatic technological change, breathtaking media  consolidation, accelerating corporate enclosure of scholarship and  scholarly publishing, deep financial strain in research libraries, and  demands by diverse publics for access to knowledge and interpretive work  that has often been pursued with public support and that takes, in  anthropology and folklore studies especially, the life of local  communities as its object.<br /><br />In addition to peer-reviewed research articles, </span> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Museum Anthropology Review</i>  also publishes shorter contributions intended to stimulate debate,  promote improved professional practice, and disseminate information on  new developments within the field. Authors considering submission of  such essays are encouraged to contact the editor to discuss the scope  and form of their submissions. Books, catalogs, exhibitions, online  exhibitions, websites, and other media of interest to the field are  reviewed regularly in <i>Museum Anthropology Review</i>. Such reviews  are typically solicited by the editorial team, but suggestions of  materials appropriate for review are especially welcome. Scholars  interested in being called upon to serve as reviewers may contact the  editor. Authors, curators and other interested parties are encouraged to  forward to the editor’s attention press releases and other publicity  materials produced by museums staging or hosting special exhibitions.  These, together with publisher’s catalogs and direct correspondence, all  assist the editors in identifying materials suitable for review in the  journal.</span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><br /><br />See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-edit.g?blogID=116259103207720939&amp;postID=8993497198722463004" id="data:post.url" name="data:post.title" onclick="return addthis_sendto()" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onmouseover="'return"><img alt="Bookmark and  Share so Your Real Friends Know that You Know" height="16" src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif" style="border: 0pt none;" width="125" /></a><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8023918866722937289/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/06/open-access-journal-museum-anthropology.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8023918866722937289"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8023918866722937289"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/06/open-access-journal-museum-anthropology.html"
         title="Open Access Journal:  Museum Anthropology Review"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
