<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8201936426642676601</id>
   <published>2009-09-16T10:32:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2009-09-16T10:34:52.091-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Eleven additional volumes online at the Oriental Institute</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/news/">On September 15, 2009</a>, The Oriental Institute published digital editions of eleven more volumes of Egyptological scholarship:<br /><h4></h4><blockquote><h4>As part of its Electronic Publications Initiative and with the generous support of Misty and Lewis Gruber, the Oriental Institute Publications Office announces the Adobe Portable Document Format (PDF) publication of:</h4> <ul><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip116.html">OIP 116. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Luxor Temple, Volume 2: The Facade, Portals, Upper Register Scenes, Columns, Marginalia, and Statuary in the Colonnade Hall. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1998.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip103.html">OIP 103. The Temple of Khonsu, Volume 2: Scenes and Inscriptions in the Court and the First Hypostyle Hall. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1981.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip100.html">OIP 100. The Temple of Khonsu, Volume I: Scenes of King Herihor in the Court. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1979.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip83.html">OIP 83. Medinet Habu, Volume V. The Temple Proper, Part I: The Portico, the Treasury, and Chapels Adjoining the First Hypostyle Hall with Marginal Material from the Forecourts. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1957.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip74.html">OIP 74. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Karnak, Volume III. The Bubastite Portal. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1954.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip56.html">OIP 56. Key Plans Showing Locations of Theban Temple Decorations. By Harold Hayden Nelson. Originally published in 1941.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip51.html">OIP 51. Medinet Habu, Volume 4. Festival Scenes of Ramses III. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1940.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip39.html">OIP 39. The Mastaba of Mereruka, Part II: Chamber A 11-13, Doorjambs and Inscriptions of Chambers A 1-21, Tomb Chamber, and Exterior. By the Sakkarah Expedition. Originally published in 1938.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip36.html">OIP 36. Medinet Habu Graffiti: Facsimiles. Edited by William F. Edgerton. Originally published in 1937.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip23.html">OIP 23. Medinet Habu, Volume III. The Calendar, the “Slaughterhouse,” and Minor Records of Ramses III. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1934.</a></li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip8.html">OIP 8. Medinet Habu, Volume I. Earlier Historical Records of Ramses III. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1930.</a></li></ul></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8201936426642676601/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/09/eleven-additional-volumes-online-at.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8201936426642676601"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8201936426642676601"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/09/eleven-additional-volumes-online-at.html"
         title="Eleven additional volumes online at the Oriental Institute"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
