<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4285366443208944523</id>
   <published>2009-12-04T09:50:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2011-10-01T19:40:17.127-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">3 More Open Access Journals</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.waspress.co.uk/journals/beforefarming/">Before Farming, the archaeology and anthropology of hunter-gatherers</a><br />ISSN 1476-4261 online<br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;">Welcome to Before Farming, the journal designed for archaeologists and anthropologists researching hunter-gatherers past and present.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;">The online journal is quarterly, published by the Western Academic &amp; Specialist Press.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;">Each year a paperback volume is published. This is a compilation of the previous year's online issues. Because it is not always possible to transfer all elements of the online version directly to print this volume is not an exact reproduction of the online version of the journal.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;">The first two online issues of Before Farming are free to view and download. Please note that although the format of these two issues is similar to later issues of the journal the title and scope of Before Farming has since changed. Formerly concerned with "the archaeology of Old World hunter-gatherers" the journal is now expanded to encompass "the archaeology and anthropology of hunter-gatherers" with no geographical or temporal restrictions. Please bear this in mind when perusing these issues.</span></blockquote><a href="http://www.saudiaramcoworld.com/">Saudi Aramco World</a><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;">Saudi Aramco, the oil company born as an international enterprise 75 years ago, distributes <i>Saudi Aramco World</i> to increase cross-cultural understanding. The bimonthly magazine's goal is to broaden knowledge of the cultures, history and geography of the Arab and Muslim worlds and their connections with the West. <i>Saudi Aramco World</i> is distributed without charge, upon request, to interested readers worldwide.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;">In print, <i>Saudi Aramco World</i> is published six times a year: January/February (JF); March/April (MA); May/June (MJ); July/August (JA); September/October (SO) and November/December (ND). From its launch in 1949 until the May/June 2000 issue, the magazine's name was <i>Aramco World.</i> The July/August 2000 issue was the first to carry the name <i>Saudi Aramco World</i> .</span></blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span><br /><a href="http://www.studiajudaica.pl/%20">Studia Judaica</a><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;">In 1995 a suggestion was made to establish the Polish  Association for Jewish Studies, which would have as its main  goal the consolidation and integration of scholars and  institutions involved in Jewish Studies. In February 1996  the Polish Association for Jewish Studies (PAJS) was registered  in Cracow. Statutory aims of PAJS are the promotion and  popularization of scholarly research on Jewish history and  culture, with particular attention to the history of the  Jews in Poland, and the development of cooperation with  Polish and foreign institutions and associations. </span></blockquote><br /><br />See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4285366443208944523/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/12/3-more-open-access-journals.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4285366443208944523"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4285366443208944523"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/12/3-more-open-access-journals.html"
         title="3 More Open Access Journals"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
