<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2990602540753475620</id>
   <published>2010-07-29T11:35:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2010-07-29T11:35:57.643-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal:  Annales d’Université „Valahia” Târgoviste. Section d’Archéologie et d’Histoire</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.annalesfsu.ro/">Annales d’Université „Valahia” Târgoviste. Section d’Archéologie et d’Histoire</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span lang="FR">The    magazine <b>Annales d’Université „Valahia” Târgovişte. </b></span><b>   Section d’Archéologie et d’Histoire</b> &nbsp;has appeared since 1999,    representing an opportunity to valorize the research work of the    academic staff from the History-Archeology Department, and also a chance    to valorize the research work of the young teaching staff who carry out    their activity at the Research Centers accredited by CNCSIS – <i>   „Preistorie, arheologie interdisciplinară şi conservarea patrimoniului    cultural mobil” </i>(Prehistory, Interdisciplinary Archeology and    Conservation of the Movable Cultural Patrimony) and<i> Centrul de    Cercetare al Istoriei Relaţiilor Internaţionale „Grigore Gafencu”</i>    (The “Grigore Gafencu” Center for the Research of the History of the    International Relations)<i>. </i>For objective (especially financial)    reasons, in order to maintain our quality standards, from the moment    when the Annals of “Valahia” University began to appear on sections,    sometimes we have published the results of two years of researches in a    single tome, trying to preserve the continuity of the publication.    Beginning with 2008, the magazine will appear with two annual issues.    The themes have remained constant throughout the issues that were    published so far in the domain of history and archeology, always    covering all the historical periods – prehistory and archeology, history    and archeology of the Middle Ages, modern and contemporary history. The    structure of our magazine maintained its classical form: Articles and    studies; Notes and Debates; Reviews. The standards of quality have been    ensured by the presence in the Publishing Team and Advisory Board of the    most representative personalities in the domain of research for each    historical period, from Romania and abroad, in the sense that each    contribution was submitted to the appreciation of the members of the    magazine’s Publishing Team and Advisory Board by means of specialized    reviews. The articles and studies published in the <b>Annales    d’Université „Valahia” Târgovişte, Section d’Archéologie et d’Histoire</b>    have been published integrally in a language of large international    circulation (English, French, German, Italian), having a permanent    scientific impact, in the sense that they have often been quoted in the    studies of our colleagues from Romania and abroad. At the same time, <b>   Annales d’Université Valahia Targoviste, Section d’Archéologie et    d’Histoire </b>have been included in several international databases.    The magazine is remarkable for its extremely original contributions in    the domain of prehistoric archeology, produced by a school that has been    acknowledged in its domain and whose results have been appreciated not    just nationally but also internationally, given the fact that it has    carried out many research programs in collaboration with numerous    universities from Europe, like those from Liège, Bordeaux I,    Aix-en-Provence, the Musée de l’Homme and the Institute of Human    Paleontology from Paris, Erlanger and Köln University from Germany etc.    The results of such researches have often been the topic of articles    included in the <b>Annales d’Université „Valahia” Targoviste, Section    d’Archéologie et d’Histoire</b>. At the same time, in this magazine can    be found studies of many of our colleagues from other universities from    Romania and abroad. The magazine is present in the libraries of many    universities from Europe and the U.S.A., in most of the universities    from Romania where there is the specialization History and in the    libraries of history museums, and of other institutions with which we    have had a permanent exchange, which has led to the improvement of the    patrimony of publications of “Valahia” University Târgovişte. </span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><br /><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div><br /><div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-create.g?blogID=116259103207720939" id="data:post.url" name="data:post.title" onclick="return addthis_sendto()" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onmouseover="'return"><img alt="Bookmark and Share so Your Real Friends Know that You Know" height="16" src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif" style="border: 0pt none;" width="125" /></a></div><br /><br /><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2990602540753475620/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/07/open-access-journal-annales-duniversite.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2990602540753475620"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2990602540753475620"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/07/open-access-journal-annales-duniversite.html"
         title="Open Access Journal:  Annales d’Université „Valahia” Târgoviste. Section d’Archéologie et d’Histoire"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
