<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4635477682790409160</id>
   <published>2010-02-12T09:48:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2010-02-12T09:58:47.738-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">ASCSA Digital Library</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://ascsa.net/">The American School of Classical Studies at Athens Digital Library</a><br />[And see the February 12, 2010 <a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/news/newsDetails/agora-and-corinth-partner-for-online-excavation-databases/">press release</a>]<blockquote><span style="font-size:85%;">Since 1881 the American School has amassed a large collection of both published and unpublished information. This includes books, journals, photographs, notebooks, personal papers, maps, and scientific data sets. More and more of these resources are now in electronic form. This page provides a central point of access to the major digital resources of the American School of Classical Studies at Athens. </span>       <p><span style="font-size:85%;"> The digital library currently provides access to the archaeological data from the Athenian Agora and Corinth together with a selection of photographs from the Alison Frantz Collection. You can use the index of categories to the left [see below] to browse this data, or search using the toolbar above. Material which has been published is made completely available to the public. Material which is unpublished is only available to researchers who have already obtained the necessary permission to study the material in person. </span></p>       <p>      <span style="font-size:85%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=collection%3AAgora" title="The Athenian Agora Excavations">Athenian Agora Excavations</a><br />Excavations in the Athenian Agora are formally published through the Athenian Agora monograph series and articles in Hesperia, the journal of the American School. A number of digital resources are also made available free-of-charge for teaching and resource purposes. With the support of the Packard Humanities Institute (PHI) the Agora excavation have been involved over the last decade in an ambitious program of digitizing older materials and experimenting with the use of new technology to record continuing excavations. The Excavations Databases provide a valuable research tool for scholars far beyond the Stoa of Attalos. </span>      </p>       <p>      <span style="font-size:85%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=collection%3ACorinth" title="Corinth Excavations">Corinth Excavations</a><br />The archive from nearly continuous excavation spanning three centuries is vast and this digital library provides on-line access to a significant portion of it. Excavation journals, photographs and architectural drawings contained herein document not only the history and archaeology of Ancient Corinth, but reveal much about the modern village, its inhabitants and the excavators. Using day journal diaries, archaeologists began recording finds, monuments and excavation, as well as their daily life in Greece. Often their thoughts and personalities are evident on the pages. More recent notebooks are more ‘objective’ and standardized but offer no less to the interested reader. Photographs, including an extensive collection of glass plate negatives, focused on deep excavation trenches, ancient monuments, and magnificent objects, but also shed light on the workmen and the changing landscape of Ancient Corinth. The collection of drawings includes maps, monuments and archaeological renderings, and provides glimpses into ancient topography, architecture and construction. The scanning and cataloguing of a quarter million digital objects was made possible by the Greek Ministry of Culture and the Third Information Society program of the European Union. </span>      </p>       <p>      <span style="font-size:85%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=collection%3AFrantz" title="Alison Frantz Photographic Collection">Alison Frantz Photographic Collection</a><br />The Alison Frantz Photographic Collection contains images by the photographer and archaeologist Alison Frantz (1903 - 1995). The photographs mainly depict Archaic and Classical sculpture, Greek archaeological sites and various finds. The collection was created between the late 1940’s and the early 1970’s. The images have illustrated numerous publications, among them: Korai, Greek Archaic Maidens (Gisela M. A. Richter, 1968); The Archaic Gravestones of Attica (Gisela M. A. Richter, 1961); Olympia, The Sculptures of the Temple of Zeus (Bernard Ashmole and Nicholas Yalouris, 1967) and The Parthenon Frieze (Martin Robertson and Alison Frantz, 1975). </span>      </p></blockquote><div id="index">             <div class="links">           <div class="linkGroup"></div><blockquote><div class="linkGroup"><span style="font-size:78%;">BROWSE       </span><div class="link"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research">All items</a> <span class="count">(302,710)</span></span></div><div class="link"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=;t=publication">Publications</a> <span class="count">(72)</span></span></div><div class="link"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=;t=report">Reports</a> <span class="count">(12)</span></span></div><div class="link"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=;t=notebook">Notebooks</a> <span class="count">(415)</span></span></div><div class="link"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=;t=context">Contexts</a> <span class="count">(22,776)</span></span></div><div class="link"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=;t=object">Objects</a> <span class="count">(100,958)</span></span></div><div class="link"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=;t=drawing">Plans and Drawings</a> <span class="count">(7,173)</span></span></div><div class="link"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?q=;t=image">Images</a> <span class="count">(125,104)</span></span></div>      </div>        <div class="linkGroup"><span style="font-size:78%;">PLOT       </span><div class="link"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/research?v=map">Map</a></span></div>             </div>          <div class="linkGroup"><span style="font-size:78%;">HELP</span><div class="linkFlush"><span style="font-size:78%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/advanced?q=&amp;t=&amp;sort=&amp;pid=">Advanced Search</a></span></div></div></blockquote>             </div>          </div>See also:<a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/open-access-publications-publications.html"><span style="font-weight: bold;"> </span>Open Access Publications:  Publications of the American School of Classical Studies at Athens</a><br /><br /><a title="data:post.title" url="data:post.url" class="addthis_button"><img src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/v2/lg-share-en.gif" alt="Bookmark and Share" style="border: 0pt none ;" height="16" width="125" /></a><br /><h3 class="post-title entry-title"></h3>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4635477682790409160/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/02/ascsa-digital-library.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4635477682790409160"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4635477682790409160"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/02/ascsa-digital-library.html"
         title="ASCSA Digital Library"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
