<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6850741691341843389</id>
   <published>2013-08-14T18:37:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-08-14T18:37:12.469-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Just Announced: The J. Paul Getty Trust Open Content Program</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.getty.edu/about/opencontent.html">The J. Paul Getty Trust Open Content Program</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.getty.edu/global/graphics/header/trust-header.jpg" class="decoded" height="41" src="http://www.getty.edu/global/graphics/header/trust-header.jpg" width="640" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Getty makes available, without charge, all available digital  images to which the Getty holds the rights or that are in the public  domain to be used for any purpose. No permission is required. <br /><br /> Please see the related <a href="http://news.getty.edu/press-materials/press-releases/getty-open-content-images.htm">press release</a> and Getty president and CEO Jim Cuno's <a href="http://blogs.getty.edu/iris/open-content-an-idea-whose-time-has-come/">announcement on <em>The Getty Iris</em></a> for additional information.</span>        <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Why Open Content?</strong><br /><br />The Getty adopted the Open Content Program because we recognized the  need to share images of works of art in an unrestricted manner, freely,  so that all those who create or appreciate art—scholars, artists, art  lovers, and entrepreneurs—will have greater access to high-quality  digital images for their studies and projects. Art inspires us, and  imagination and creativity lead to artistic expressions that expand  knowledge and understanding. The Getty sincerely hopes that people will  use the open content images for a wide range of activities and that they  will share the fruits of their labors with others.</span><br />         <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Access to Open Content Images</strong><br /><br /> Initially, the images available through the Open Content Program are of  works in the J. Paul Getty Museum's collections. Over time, images from  the Getty Research Institute and the Getty Conservation Institute will  be added. Museum images can be found on the <a href="http://www.getty.edu/art/">Museum's Collection webpages</a> or on the <a href="http://search.getty.edu/gateway/landing">Getty Search Gateway</a>.  Those available as open content images are identified with a "Download"  link. Images provided are JPEG files at a minimum of 300 DPI. See the <a href="http://www.getty.edu/about/oc_printing_guidelines.pdf">Guidelines for Successful Printing (PDF)</a> for more information on file format. <br /><br />If you need new photography, resizing, or color correction, you can request those services by <a href="http://www.getty.edu/legal/image_request/index.html">Contacting Museum Rights &amp; Reproductions</a>. A <a href="http://www.getty.edu/legal/image_request/fees_schedule.pdf">fee (PDF)</a> will be charged for this service.  </span><br />         <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Public Domain and Rights</strong><br /><br /> Open content images are digital surrogates of works of art that are in  the Getty's collections and in the public domain, for which we hold all  rights, or for which we are not aware of any rights restrictions. Rights  restrictions are based on copyright, trademark, privacy and publicity  laws, and contractual obligations. If an image you want is not  designated as an open content image, it is because one or more of the  above identified legal rights restricts our ability to make that content  available under this program. While the Getty reviews the metadata  about each picture before making it available as an open content image,  there may be some underlying rights that were unknown to us. For that  reason, we strongly recommend that users consider the possibility that  rights of third parties may be involved, and permission for those rights  may need to be obtained by the user for the proposed use.</span><br />         <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Fair Use</strong><br /><br /> Open content images can be used for any purpose without first seeking  permission from the Getty. Images of many other works in the collections  are also on our website in varying formats. The Getty supports fair use  of images when the applicable legal criteria are met. For more  information on use of digital images of works in the Getty's  collections, please refer to the Getty's <a href="http://www.getty.edu/legal/copyright.html">Terms of Use</a>.  </span><br /></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6850741691341843389/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/just-announced-j-paul-getty-trust-open.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6850741691341843389"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6850741691341843389"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/just-announced-j-paul-getty-trust-open.html"
         title="Just Announced: The J. Paul Getty Trust Open Content Program"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
