<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8309055129781908681</id>
   <published>2011-10-06T13:12:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-10-06T13:28:53.687-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Virtual Amarna Project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/amarna_leap_2011/">The Virtual Amarna Project</a><br /><img alt="Wooden Head from Amarna" src="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/amarna_leap_2011/images/intro_image.jpg" style="float: right; margin-left: 6px;" /> <br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The ancient Egyptian city of Amarna. was the short-lived capital  built by the Pharaoh Akhenaten and abandoned shortly after his death (c.  1332 BCE). It is of particular significance as it represents both the  location of the first major society dedicated to the cult of a single  god as well as an important city that was occupied for a relatively  brief period and then abandoned. It is thus simultaneously the key to a  chapter in the history of religious experience and to a fuller  understanding of what it was like to be an ancient Egyptian. More  information on Amarna can be found in Kemp 1977; 1995; 2002 and 2005.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The objects in the archive have been recovered over the various  seasons of fieldwork. The digitisation of the materials was performed as  part of the Virtual Amarna Project funded by the Amarna Trust. </span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">More information on Amarna can be found at <a href="http://www.amarnaproject.com/">http://www.amarnaproject.com/</a>.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The datasets in this section of the archive resulted from the 3D  digitization of the objects using a Konica Minolta Vivid 9i system,  Technical details on the process are provided in the associated Internet  Archaeology article (Limp et al 2011, see below). Comprehensive  metadata on the objects follow that specified in the new <a href="http://guides.archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/g2gp/LaserScan_Toc">Laser Scanning Guide to Good Practice</a>. Data formats provided in the archive are:  </span><br /><ol><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Images - these are standard digital photographs provided as jpg files.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">3D PDF files - 3D PDF is an Adobe Acrobat file format and files in  this format can be read by the free Adobe Acrobat Reader software  (versions 8.1 and later).</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Meshes (obj) - Meshes are the result of the conversion of a point  cloud into a triangulated mesh - with the texture (that is color imager)  applied to the resulting triangulated facets. The mesh format is  immediately usable by many software products including most animation  and visualization software. Additionally the obj format can be viewed  using a number of free 'viewers' that allow detailed manipulations,  measurement and other operations. The Guides to Good Practice Laser  Scanning Guide (<a href="http://guides.archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/g2gp/LaserScan_3-5">Section 3.5</a>) provides information on a number of these viewers.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Point clouds - there are the digital data in a standard ASCII format  where each point is represented by X,Y and Z and color readings. Most  point cloud software can import this data format.</span></li></ol></blockquote><ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">There is detailed information on the procedures necessary to access  and utilize these data in Limp et al (2011, see below) Section 10.2</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">This digital archive was undertaken in conjunction with an electronic  publication through the Linking Electronic Archives and Publications II (<a href="http://intarch.ac.uk/leap/index.html">LEAP II</a>) project, funded by the <a href="http://www.mellon.org/">Andrew W. Mellon Foundation</a>.  The corresponding article is 'Developing a 3-D Digital Heritage  Ecosystem: from object to representation and the role of a virtual  museum in the 21st century' (2011) by Fred Limp, Angie Payne, Katie  Simon, Snow Winters and Jack Cothren, which can be found in <a href="http://intarch.ac.uk/journal/issue30/limp_index.html">Internet Archaeology 30</a>.</span></ul><br /><ul class="dlMenu"><li> <span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/amarna_leap_2011/index.cfm?CFID=3048&amp;CFTOKEN=F6DA2F77-731D-4799-A1EACEEADDF0AB65"> Introduction</a></span>	</li><li> <span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/amarna_leap_2011/overview.cfm?CFID=3048&amp;CFTOKEN=F6DA2F77-731D-4799-A1EACEEADDF0AB65"> Overview</a></span>	</li><li> <span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/amarna_leap_2011/downloads.cfm?CFID=3048&amp;CFTOKEN=F6DA2F77-731D-4799-A1EACEEADDF0AB65"> Downloads</a></span>		</li></ul>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8309055129781908681/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/10/virtual-amarna-project.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8309055129781908681"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8309055129781908681"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/10/virtual-amarna-project.html"
         title="Virtual Amarna Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
