<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1951081787697621645</id>
   <published>2012-07-09T11:45:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-07-09T11:45:50.399-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Bible"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Religion"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Theological Studies</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.ts.mu.edu/">Theological Studies</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Theological Studies</b> is a quarterly journal of theology,   published under the auspices of the Jesuits in the USA. Located at Marquette   University, in Milwaukee, Wisconsin, it is under the general editorship of David G. Schultenover, SJ,   in concert with its <a href="http://www.ts.mu.edu/about/editorial.html">editorial consultants</a>. Its   book review editor is R. Daniel Kendall, S.J., of the University of San Francisco.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp;Founded and sponsored by the Society of Jesus in the United States of America, <i>Theological Studies</i> is a Catholic scholarly journal that serves the Church and its mission  by promoting a deeper understanding of the Christian faith through the  publication of research in theological disciples.  Through refereed  articles and reviews of noteworthy books, the journal aims to recover  and to help make accessible the riches of the theological tradition, and  to present significant developments in current theology.  It is  published quarterly in English for an international readership.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>Theological Studies</em> is now making past articles as well   as book reviews available for individual download, after the item has been in   print publication for <strong>five full years</strong> (e.g., those published in   2006 are available for download beginning in the year 2012). Some notes:</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Visitors are welcome to make single copies of articles from   <em>Theological Studies</em>. Those who want multiple copies (for classroom    use, for example) must get the necessary permission from Copyright Clearance    Center and pay the royalty fee. To do this click on the icon:   <a href="http://www.copyright.com/ccc/openurl.do?ourl_company=Theological%20Studies&amp;issn=0040-5639&amp;WT.mc_id=pub_Theological%20Studies">  <img alt="Go to CCC website" class="style1" height="15" src="http://www.ts.mu.edu/content/image001.gif" width="101" /></a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">     If you download only a single copy of an article for personal use, we request a    small user’s fee to cover administrative costs of putting our past    content online. To make your contribution, please click the “Donate” button on the left-hand side of this page.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Visitors will experience the search features best when they have  the latest version of Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, or Chrome (all  of which employ JavaScript and AJAX).</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">The articles have been rendered in Adobe Acrobat's text format, so  that users can select and copy text from the PDF files (i.e., they have  all been OCR'ed).</span></li></ul><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ts.mu.edu/content/searchArticles.html">Go to download articles.</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <a href="http://www.ts.mu.edu/content/searchArticles.html">search page</a> provides a dynamic search feature that allows the visitor to find PDF  versions of past articles by entering in an author's name, a title of a  past article (or a partial title or keyword) or a volume number. Note:  the search feature does not allow a search by year of appearance, but  since TS has been in continual publication since 1940 (with its volume  1), the simple mathematical formula (Year of Publication) - 1939 =  Volume number will allow the user to enter the correct volume number for  the known year of publication (e.g., a year of publication in 2000,  minus 1939, will result in the correct volume of 61).</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ts.mu.edu/content/r_all.html">Go to book reviews and shorter notices</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Clicking on the PDF link for a given issue of the journal will take  you to the reviews and notices for that issue. These you can then page  through and/or search by typing word(s) into the search box on the menu  bar in Adobe Acrobat (or your PDF reader, such as Preview on the Mac).</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://onlinedigeditions.com/publication/login.php?i=&amp;m=21441&amp;l=1&amp;p=">Access to the Most Recent Issues (for individual paid subscribers only)</a></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">If you are a current individual subscriber to Theological Studies  you can access your currently subscribed issue and articles by following  <a href="http://onlinedigeditions.com/publication/login.php?i=&amp;m=21441&amp;l=1&amp;p=">this link.</a></span></blockquote><br /><br /><br /><div style="text-align: center;">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1951081787697621645/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/open-access-journal-theological-studies.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1951081787697621645"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1951081787697621645"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/open-access-journal-theological-studies.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Theological Studies"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
