<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-928786205992273288</id>
   <published>2013-05-15T10:00:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-05-15T10:15:53.352-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Romania"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Dacia: Revue d'Archeologie et d'Histoire Ancienne</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.cimec.ro/Arheologie/dacia_eng.htm">Dacia: Revue d'archéologie et d'histoire ancienne</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In 1924 under the signature of Vasile Pârvan as director and fonder was issued the first number of the <i>"Dacia - Recherches et découvertes archéologiques en Roumanie", </i>the  first journal with articles about ancient history and archaeology,  written in foreign languages. The Vasile Pârvan's dream was to make in  this journal a forum for archaeological debates and for presentations of  the newest archaeological discoveries all over Romania. From the  beginning the use of the foreign languages and the quality standards  imposed to the published materials have turned the name of DACIA in a  brand well known everywhere in the archaeological circles. Unfortunately  the evolution of the journal is under the sign of many interruptions.  The old series founded by Vasile Pârvan in 1924 ends with the XI-XII  issues published in 1948. The journal renewed his existence in 1957 at  the celebration of 65 years from the birth of Vasile Pârvan with a new  series. Since then till now were published 49 issues from this Dacia New  Series.</span>  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />  &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Every single number of the new series has in wide lines the same  structure as the old series, containing studies, research reports,  annual archaeological chronicles, abstracts, book reviews and book  presentations. Through the year great personalities of the Romanian  archaeology such as: <b>Vasile Pârvan, Ioan Andrieşescu, Ion Nestor,  Vladimir Dumitrescu, Martin Roska, Dorin Popescu, Gh.I. Brătianu, Vasile  Christescu, Theophile Sauciuc-Săveanu, Gh. Ştefan, P. Nicorescu, C.S.  Nicolăescu-Plopşor, Eugen Comşa, D.M. Pippidi, Radu Vulpe, Grigore  Florescu</b>, <b>Dumitru Berciu, Constantin Daicoviciu, Ion Barnea, K. Horedt, I.I. Russu, Bucur Mitrea </b>and much more then thishave signed the articles.<span class="style1"><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/null" id="2" name="2"></a></span> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><div align="center" class="Subtitlu"><span style="font-size: x-small;">About the project of bringing  up-to-date the index of DACIA and also about the digitalisation of the  first series of the journal (1924-1948)</span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Starting from June 2006 began the improving process of the Dacia's  index. The web page was created in 2001, when was put on-line the index  made in a collaboration between the Institute of Archaeology from  Bucharest and cIMeC - The Institute for Cultural Memory. The database  contained all the titles belonging to the issues from 1924 to 1998. Now,  after the improving process the database contains 1333 recordings from  1924 till 2005. The search can be made by author, year or by title. We  intend to add in the near future the possibility of a more refined  search by epoch, locality and key words. <br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;We began also scanning and image processing for the first series of  Dacia containing twelve numbers which we published it entirely for free  on our web site. In this way this rare numbers of the journal will be  accessible, a useful tool for the students and specialists in the field  of archaeology. <br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;We hope that our project will be successful and well received by  the students, specialists and also other categories of public for us to  keep going on making the largest archaeological library on-line from  Romania.</span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.cimec.ro/scripts/dacia/selarticole.asp">Complete Index of Dacia Journal<br /><br /></a><a href="http://www.cimec.ro/Arheologie/dacia.digital/sumare/1924eng.html" target="_blank">Dacia Digitalised Collection</a> -  1924-1948&nbsp;</span><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;"><span><span class="titol"><span><span class="text"><span><span>See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></span></span></span></span> </span></div><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script><br /><br /><!-- AddThis Button END -->]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/928786205992273288/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/03/open-access-journal-info-dacia-revue.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/928786205992273288"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/928786205992273288"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/03/open-access-journal-info-dacia-revue.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Dacia: Revue d'Archeologie et d'Histoire Ancienne"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
