<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3759985855942045459</id>
   <published>2011-09-26T09:03:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-09-06T06:31:47.903-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">QuarryScapes: conservation of ancient stone quarry landscapes in the Eastern Mediterranean</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/"&gt;The QuarryScapes Project: conservation of ancient stone quarry landscapes in the Eastern Mediterranean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;img alt="http://www.quarryscapes.no/bannere/banner6.jpg" src="http://www.quarryscapes.no/bannere/banner6.jpg" /&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The spectacular monuments and cities of the ancient Near East are  testament to an industrial past where large-scale stone procurement  remains unsurpassed. Yet, stone quarries are forgotten as key  archaeological sites, rich in material remains of crucial significance  if we are to understand the social and technological practices of an age  when stone was quarried and transported &lt;i&gt;par excellence. &lt;/i&gt;Largely  invisible, undocumented and unprotected, these ancient quarry  landscapes are being destroyed from actions such as modern development  and quarrying.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The inspiration for the ‘QuarryScapes' project comes from the  necessity to put these ancient industrial landscapes on the map before  it is too late and to raise awareness of their research potential across  a broad spectrum of audiences, from archaeological researchers to the  interested public. The ‘QuarryScapes' project drew together  professionals from academic and other institutions in Egypt, Jordan,  Turkey, UK, Belgium, Italy and Norway to focus specifically on  documentation, conservation and heritage management of these fragile  quarry landscapes within the first collaborative and innovative project  of its kind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Publications - QuarryScapes dissemination &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Quarryscapes deliverables&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;(Can be downloaded below. For printed copies, please contact biblioteket@ngu.no)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 4, Work Package 4: Characterisation of complex  quarry landscapes; an example from the West Bank Quarries, Aswan. 275  pp, ISBN 978-82-7385-118-4. Edited by: Elizabeth Bloxam, Tom Heldal, Per  Storemyr. Authors: Elizabeth Bloxam, Tom Heldal, Per Storemyr, Adel  Kelany, Patrick Degryse, Reidulv Bøe, Axel Müller. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del4_Report_LR.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del4_MAP1.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;mapsheet 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del4_map2.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;mapsheet 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 5, Work Package 4: The assessment of significance  of ancient quarry landscapes - problems and possible solutions. The case  of the Aswan West Bank. 26 pp, ISBN &lt;a class="libx-autolink" href="http://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/primo_library/libweb/action/search.do?fn=go&amp;amp;ct=search&amp;amp;vid=NYU&amp;amp;mode=Basic&amp;amp;indx=0&amp;amp;dum=true&amp;amp;vl%28freeText0%29=8273851192&amp;amp;undefined=all_items&amp;amp;vl%281UIStartWith0%29=contains&amp;amp;vl%28212921975UI0%29=isbn&amp;amp;scps=scope:%28NS%29,scope:%28CU%29,scope:%28%22BHS%22%29,scope:%28NYU%29,scope:%28%22NYSID%22%29,scope:%28%22NYHS%22%29,scope:%28GEN%29,scope:%28%22NYUAD%22%29" style="border-bottom: 1px dotted;" title="libx-autolink"&gt;978-82-7385-119-2&lt;/a&gt;. Author: Elizabeth Bloxam. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del5_report.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 1, Work Package 1: Landscape and provenance and  conservation of stone sources from selected archaeological sites in  Jordan, 175 pp, ISBN 978-82-7385-26-0 Edited by: Nizar Abu-Jaber and  Ziad Al Saad Authors: Nizar Abu-Jaber, Ziad Al Saad, Mohammed Al Qudah,  Nihad Smadi and Abeer Al Zoubi. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/del1_report.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 2, Work Package 2: Inventory of Ancient quarry  landscapes in Turkey: their characteristics, production and state of  conservation. 29 pp, Edited by: Emine Caner Saltik. Authors: Emine N.  Caner-Saltık, K. Göze Akoğlu, Evin Caner-Özler, Kemal Erdoğan, Alp  Güney, Sinan Sülüner, Tamer Topal, Ayşe Tavukçuoğlu, V. Toprak, A.G.  Turkmenoglu, M. C. Ustunkaya  Taliye Yaşar.  &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del2_report.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 3, Work Package 3: The Sagalassos quarry landscape: bringing quarries in context, 84 pp, ISBN &lt;a class="libx-autolink" href="http://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/primo_library/libweb/action/search.do?fn=go&amp;amp;ct=search&amp;amp;vid=NYU&amp;amp;mode=Basic&amp;amp;indx=0&amp;amp;dum=true&amp;amp;vl%28freeText0%29=8273851222&amp;amp;undefined=all_items&amp;amp;vl%281UIStartWith0%29=contains&amp;amp;vl%28212921975UI0%29=isbn&amp;amp;scps=scope:%28NS%29,scope:%28CU%29,scope:%28%22BHS%22%29,scope:%28NYU%29,scope:%28%22NYSID%22%29,scope:%28%22NYHS%22%29,scope:%28GEN%29,scope:%28%22NYUAD%22%29" style="border-bottom: 1px dotted;" title="libx-autolink"&gt;978-82-7385-122-2&lt;/a&gt; Edited by: Patrick Degryse Authors: Patrick Degryse, Tom Heldal,  Elizabeth Bloxam, Per Storemyr, Marc Waelkens, E. Trogh, Hannelore  Vanhaverbeke, Jeroen Poblome, Philippe Muchez. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_DEL3_report_WP3.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 6, Work Package 5: Risk Assessment and Monitoring of Ancient Egyptian Quarry Landscapes, 207 pp, ISBN &lt;a class="libx-autolink" href="http://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/primo_library/libweb/action/search.do?fn=go&amp;amp;ct=search&amp;amp;vid=NYU&amp;amp;mode=Basic&amp;amp;indx=0&amp;amp;dum=true&amp;amp;vl%28freeText0%29=8273851257&amp;amp;undefined=all_items&amp;amp;vl%281UIStartWith0%29=contains&amp;amp;vl%28212921975UI0%29=isbn&amp;amp;scps=scope:%28NS%29,scope:%28CU%29,scope:%28%22BHS%22%29,scope:%28NYU%29,scope:%28%22NYSID%22%29,scope:%28%22NYHS%22%29,scope:%28GEN%29,scope:%28%22NYUAD%22%29" style="border-bottom: 1px dotted;" title="libx-autolink"&gt;978-82-7385-125-3&lt;/a&gt; Editors: Per Storemyr, Elizabeth Bloxam, Tom Heldal Authors: Per  Storemyr, Elizabeth Bloxam, Tom Heldal, Adel Kelany, James A. Harrell,  Rawda Yousri, El Shaimaa Fathy. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_Del6_report_SMALL.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 7, Work Package 6:&amp;nbsp;Site Management Concepts for Widan el Faras, Northern Fayoum, Egypt. 40 pp + appendices, ISBN 978-82-7385-135-4 Prepared by NSCE with the close collaboration with Naguib Amin. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_Del7_wp6_report.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 8, Work Package 7: GIS Products for Management of  Ancient Stone Quarry Landscapes: three Egyptian Site Maps, 20 pp and 7  maps, ISBN &lt;a class="libx-autolink" href="http://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/primo_library/libweb/action/search.do?fn=go&amp;amp;ct=search&amp;amp;vid=NYU&amp;amp;mode=Basic&amp;amp;indx=0&amp;amp;dum=true&amp;amp;vl%28freeText0%29=8273851230&amp;amp;undefined=all_items&amp;amp;vl%281UIStartWith0%29=contains&amp;amp;vl%28212921975UI0%29=isbn&amp;amp;scps=scope:%28NS%29,scope:%28CU%29,scope:%28%22BHS%22%29,scope:%28NYU%29,scope:%28%22NYSID%22%29,scope:%28%22NYHS%22%29,scope:%28GEN%29,scope:%28%22NYUAD%22%29" style="border-bottom: 1px dotted;" title="ISBN not found"&gt;978-82-7385-123-9&lt;/a&gt; Edited by: Naguib Amin, Rawda Yousri, Sara Kayser Authors: Elshimaa  Fathy, Marwa Sadek, Rabab Abd-el-Kader, Rawda Yosuri, Sara Kayser. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_Del8_report.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 9, Work Package 7: Map of Ancient Egyptian Stone Quarries, 26 pp /6 maps, ISBN &lt;a class="libx-autolink" href="http://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/primo_library/libweb/action/search.do?fn=go&amp;amp;ct=search&amp;amp;vid=NYU&amp;amp;mode=Basic&amp;amp;indx=0&amp;amp;dum=true&amp;amp;vl%28freeText0%29=8273851338&amp;amp;undefined=all_items&amp;amp;vl%281UIStartWith0%29=contains&amp;amp;vl%28212921975UI0%29=isbn&amp;amp;scps=scope:%28NS%29,scope:%28CU%29,scope:%28%22BHS%22%29,scope:%28NYU%29,scope:%28%22NYSID%22%29,scope:%28%22NYHS%22%29,scope:%28GEN%29,scope:%28%22NYUAD%22%29" style="border-bottom: 1px dotted;" title="libx-autolink"&gt;978-82-7385-133-8&lt;/a&gt; Edited by: Naguib Amin, Azza Shawarby, Rawda Yousri, Sara Kayser  Authors: Elshimaa Fathy, Marwa Sadek, Rawda Yousri, Sara Kayser. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del9_wp7_report.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable No 10, Work Package 8: Identifying heritage values and  character-defining elements of ancient quarry landscapes in the Eastern  Mediterranean: an integrated analysis. 161 pp, ISBN 978-82-7385-134-6  Authors: Elizabeth Bloxam and Tom Heldal. Contributions from: Turkey:  Emine N. Caner-Saltık, K. Göze Akoğlu, Evin Caner-Özler, Kemal  Erdoğan,Alp Güney, Sinan Sülüner, Tamer Topal, Ayşe Tavukçuoğlu, V.  Toprak, A.G.Turkmenoglu, M. C. Ustunkaya Taliye Yaşar Jordan: Nizar  Abu-Jaber, Ziad Al Saad, Mohammed Al Qudah, Nihad Smadi and Abeer Al  Zoubi Egypt: Naguib Amin, Adel Kelany, Rawda Yousri, Sara Kayser,  Elshimaa Fathy, Marwa Sadek, Rabab Abd-el-Kader Belgium: Patrick  Degryse, Marc Waelkens, E. Trogh, Hannelore Vanhaverbeke, Jeroen  Poblome, Philippe Muchez Norway: Per Storemyr, Reidulv Bøe, Axel Müller  Italy: Lorenzo Lazzarini. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del10_wp8_reportH.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Delivery No 11, Work Package 9: QuarryScapes guide to ancient  stone quarry landscapes: documentation, interpretation, and statement of  significance. 85 pp, ISBN Compiled by: Tom Heldal and Elizabeth Bloxam  Contributions from: Turkey: Emine N. Caner-Saltık, K. Göze Akoğlu, Evin  Caner-Özler, Kemal Erdoğan, Alp Güney, Sinan Sülüner, Tamer Topal, Ayşe  Tavukçuoğlu, V. Toprak, A. G. Turkmenoglu, M. C. Ustunkaya Taliye Yaşar  Jordan: Nizar Abu-Jaber, Ziad Al Saad, Mohammed Al Qudah, Nihad Smadi  and Abeer Al Zoubi Egypt: Naguib Amin, Adel Kelany, Rawda Yousri, Sara  Kayser, Elshimaa Fathy, Marwa Sadek, Rabab Abd-el-Kader Belgium: Patrick  Degryse, Marc Waelkens, E. Trogh, Hannelore Vanhaverbeke, Jeroen  Poblome, Philippe Muchez Norway: Per Storemyr, Reidulv Bøe, Axel Müller  Italy: Lorenzo Lazzarini. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del11_wp9.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report &lt;/a&gt;or follow &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/guide_content_text.php"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; for the web version.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable 12:&amp;nbsp;QuarryScapes workshop proceedings – abstracts and  extended abstracts. Edited by Patrick Degryse, Tom Heldal and Elizabeth  Bloxam. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del12_wp9.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Deliverable 13: QuarryScapes Atlas of Ancient Stone Quarry Landscapes. &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/text/publications/QS_del13_atlas.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Download report version&lt;/a&gt; or follow &lt;a href="http://www.quarryscapes.no/atlas_text.php"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Journals and book chapters &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Abu-Jaber, N., al Saad, Z. and al Qudah, M. (accepted):  Geomorphological and geological constraints on the development of Early  Bronze chert industries at the northern rim of the Al Jafr Basin,  Southern Jordan. &lt;i&gt;Mediterranean Archaeology and Archaemetry&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, E. (2007): Who were the pharaohs' quarrymen? &lt;i&gt;Archaeology International &lt;/i&gt;, 9: 23-7.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, E. (in press) ‘Mapping ancient quarry landscapes’. Egyptian Archaeology 34.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, E. and Heldal, T. 2007: The Industrial Landscape of The  Northern Faiyum Desert as a World Heritage Site: Modelling 'Outstanding  Universal Value' of 3rd Millennium BC Stone Quarrying in Egypt. &lt;i&gt;World Archaeology &lt;/i&gt;Vol 39 No3: 305-323&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;P. Degryse, Ph. Muchez, M. Waelkens (2007) Geology and archaeology  of late Hellenistic limestone quarries at Sagalassos. MARMORA, 2, 9-20.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;P. Degryse, M. Waelkens, P. Vandevelde, Ph. Muchez, W. Viaene  (2008) Weathering of limestone in the historical buildings of  Sagalassos, in:  P. Degryse, M. Waelkens (eds.) Sagalassos VI, Geo- and  Bio-Archaeology at Sagalassos and in its Territory, Leuven University  Press, 215-227.   &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;P. Degryse, T. Heldal, E. Bloxam, P. Storemyr, M. Waelkens, Ph.  Muchez (2008) The Sagalassos quarry landscape: bringing quarries in  context, in: P. Degryse, M. Waelkens (eds.) Sagalassos VI, Geo- and  Bio-Archaeology at Sagalassos and in its Territory, Leuven University  Press, 261-290.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Heldal, T., Bloxam, E., Storemyr , P. 2007: Unravelling ancient  stone quarry landscapes in the Eastern Mediterranean: three Egyptian  case studies. In &lt;i&gt;Broadening Horizons: Multidisciplinary Approaches to Landscape Study&lt;/i&gt;, eds Bart Ooghe and Geert Verhoeven, Newcastle: Cambridge Scholars Press, 90-112 &lt;a href="http://www.broadeninghorizons.ugent.be/indexUK.htm" target="_blank"&gt;Abstract online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P. (2008): Prehistoric geometric rock art at Gharb Aswan, Upper Egypt. Sahara, 19, 61-76 &lt;a href="http://www.saharajournal.com/19/pages/abs_19.html#p61"&gt;Abstract online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P., Kelany, A., Negm, M. A., Tohami, A. (2008). More  "Lascaux along the Nile"? Possible Late Palaeolithic rock art in Wadi  Abu Subeira, Upper Egypt. Sahara, 19, 155-158  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P. (in press): A Prehistoric Geometric Rock Art Landscape by the First Nile Cataract. Archéo-Nil, 19 (2009)  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P., Bloxam, E., Heldal, T. &amp;amp; Kelany, A. (in press):  The Aswan West Bank ancient quarry landscape: Stone procurement,  hunting, desert travel and rock-art from the Palaeolithic to the Roman  period. Papers from the conference: The First Cataract: One region –  Various Perspectives. Berlin, September 2-5, 2007. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P., Bloxam, E., Heldal, T. &amp;amp; Kelany, A. (in press):  Ancient Desert and Quarry Roads on the West Bank of the Nile in the  First Cataract Region. Desert Road Archaeology, edited by Heiko Riemer  and Frank Förster. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Conferences &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P., Bloxam, E., Heldal, T. and Kelany, A.: ‘Conservation of Ancient Stone Quarry Landscapes in Egypt' in &lt;i&gt;Prehistoric Mines and Quarries: a Transatlantic Perspective &lt;/i&gt;. Papers from the Society for American Archaeology, 71 st Annual Meeting, April 26-April 30 2007, San Juan, Puerto Rico.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, E., Heldal, T. &amp;amp; Storemyr, P. (2005): QuarryScapes:  conservation of ancient stone quarry landscapes in the Eastern  Mediterranean. &lt;i&gt;British Egyptology Congress, &lt;/i&gt;Cambridge, 24-25 September.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, E., Heldal, T. &amp;amp; Storemyr, P. (2006): Late Palaeolithic Origins of a Grinding Stone Industry at Aswan, Egypt. &lt;i&gt;Society for American Archaeology, 71 st Annual Meeting &lt;/i&gt;, April 26-April 30, San Juan, Puerto Rico (presentation and abstract in proceedings)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, E., Storemyr, P., Heldal, T. &amp;amp; Kelany, A. (2006): "The  myth of control": Re-assessing the role of the Egyptian state in  ancient quarrying. &lt;i&gt;ASMOSIA 8 &lt;/i&gt;, Aix-en-Provence, June 2006. Presentation and abstract in "Book of Abstracts". &lt;a href="http://www.mmsh.univ-aix.fr/CCJ/textes/actualite/asmosia8/RESUMES%20ABSTRACTS/PROGRAMME%20WEB/BLOXAM.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Abstract online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Degryse, P., Bloxam, E., Heldal, T., Storemyr, P. &amp;amp; Waelkens,  M. (2006): Quarries in the landscape : a survey of the area of  Sagalassos (SW Turkey). &lt;i&gt;ASMOSIA 8 &lt;/i&gt;, Aix-en-Provence, June 2006. Presentation and abstract in "Book of Abstracts". &lt;a href="http://www.mmsh.univ-aix.fr/CCJ/textes/actualite/asmosia8/RESUMES%20ABSTRACTS/PROGRAMME%20WEB/ASMOSIA8_ABSTRACT_DEGRYSE.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Abstract online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Heldal, T., Bloxam, E. &amp;amp; Storemyr, P. (2006): New evidence for the use of fire in ancient quarrying. &lt;i&gt;Society for American Archaeology, 71 st Annual Meeting &lt;/i&gt;, April 26-April 30, San Juan, Puerto Rico (presentation and abstract in proceedings)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Heldal, T., Bloxam, E., Storemyr, P. &amp;amp; Kelany, A. (2006):  Interpreting a physical stone quarry landscape; the case of the Aswan  West Bank quarries, Egypt. &lt;i&gt;ASMOSIA 8 &lt;/i&gt;, Aix-en-Provence, June 2006. Presentation and abstract in "Book of Abstracts". &lt;a href="http://www.mmsh.univ-aix.fr/CCJ/textes/actualite/asmosia8/RESUMES%20ABSTRACTS/PROGRAMME%20WEB/Heldal_Asmosia2006.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Abstract online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Kelany, A. (2006): Marks of quarry workers at the Unfinished Obelisk Quarry, Aswan, Egypt. &lt;i&gt;ASMOSIA 8 &lt;/i&gt;, Aix-en-Provence, June 2006. Presentation and abstract in "Book of Abstracts". &lt;a href="http://www.mmsh.univ-aix.fr/ccj/textes/actualite/asmosia8/RESUMES%20ABSTRACTS/PROGRAMME%20WEB/KELANY-MARKS%20OF%20QUARRY%20WORKERS%20AT%20THE%20UNFINISHED%20OBELISK%20QUARRY.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Abstract online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P., Bloxam, E., Heldal, T. &amp;amp; Kelany, A. (2006):  Difficulties in preserving an extensive ancient stone quarry landscape:  The Aswan West Bank Quarries (Upper Egypt). &lt;i&gt;ASMOSIA 8 &lt;/i&gt;, Aix-en-Provence, June 2006. Presentation and abstract in "Book of Abstracts". &lt;a href="http://www.mmsh.univ-aix.fr/CCJ/textes/actualite/asmosia8/RESUMES%20ABSTRACTS/PROGRAMME%20WEB/STOREMYR-ASMOSIA8_Abstract_Storemyr.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Abstract online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P., Heldal, T. &amp;amp; Bloxam, E. (2006): QuarryScapes:  Conservation of Ancient Stone Quarry Landscapes in the Eastern  Mediterranean. &lt;i&gt;Society for American Archaeology, 71 st Annual Meeting &lt;/i&gt;, April 26-April 30, San Juan, Puerto Rico (presentation and abstract in proceedings)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, E. (2007) ‘The West Bank Aswan ancient quarry landscape:  raising the significance and value of an invisible archaeological site  under threat’. &lt;i&gt;British Museum International Egyptological Colloquium&lt;/i&gt;, 11-13 July.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Heldal T.,&amp;nbsp; Bloxam, E, Degryse, P, Storemyr, P. &amp;amp; Kelany, A.  (2007): Connecting quarries with stone. The significance of the Old  Kingdom gypsum quarries at Umm es-Sawan, Northern Faiyum, Egypt.  Norwegian Geological Society Winter Conference, Stavanger, January&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P., Bloxam, E., Heldal, T. and Kelany, A. (2007):  Quarries and areas of rock-art, raw materials of the region. Conference:  &lt;i&gt;The First Cataract: One region - Various Perspectives&lt;/i&gt;, Berlin, September 2-5, 2007&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P., Bloxam, E., Heldal, T. and Kelany, A. (2007): Stone procurement and rock-art at the West Bank of Aswan, Egypt, &lt;i&gt;Implement Petrology Group Conference&lt;/i&gt;, Department of Archaeology, University of York, UK, September 6th-11th 2007. &lt;a href="http://www.implementpetrology.org/conferences/2007/abstracts.html#storemyr"&gt;Abstract online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Amin, N. (2007): presentation at A special presentation for the (Institut de Sciences de l'Homme) in France in April 2007&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, Elizabeth 2008: Multidisciplinary approaches to the  investigation of ancient quarries in Egypt: Enhancing our understanding  of ancient quarrying in antiquity. 33&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; International Geological Congress, Oslo, Norway, 6 - 16 August 2008&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, E. 2008: Landscape transformation and millstone quarrying  in Egypt and Norway: multi-discplinary approaches to assessing the  significance of utilitarian production. 9&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Nordic Conference on the Application of Scientific Methods in Archaeology (SMIA IX) Trondheim, Norway, 11-14 September 2008&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Heldal, Tom 2008: A geological approach to ancient stone quarry landscapes. 33&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; International Geological Congress, Oslo, Norway, 6 - 16 August 2008&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Degryse, Patrick 2008: The Sagalassos quarry landscape: Bringing ancient quarries in context. 33&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; International Geological Congress, Oslo, Norway, 6 - 16 August 2008&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;TV-programmes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;History Channel (2006): Ramses' Egyptian Empire, Series: Lost Worlds,&lt;br /&gt;   episode no. 3, originally broadcasted Monday July 24 (contribution to  the programme by QuarryScape's Adel Kelany, Elizabeth Bloxam and Per  Storemyr on the ancient quarries in Aswan)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;International newsletters &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;‘Digging Diary’ &lt;i&gt;Egyptian Archaeology&lt;/i&gt; Bulletin of the Egypt Exploration Society, No. 32 Spring 2008, pp. 28.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;'News and Notes: Quarryscapes' &lt;i&gt;Egyptian Archaeology &lt;/i&gt;Bulletin of the Egypt Exploration Society, No. 29: 8 Autumn 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Heldal, T. (2006): Research summary: QuarryScapes — EU project on ancient quarries. &lt;i&gt;ASMOSIA Newsletter &lt;/i&gt;, Vol. 16, Issue 2, Fall 2005/Winter 2006. &lt;a href="http://www.eeescience.utoledo.edu/asmosia" target="_blank"&gt;Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Newspaper articles, Web news and Public lectures &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Kalliomaeki, A. (2007): EAIS and QuarryScapes. Public lecture.  House of Sciences / University of Helsinki, Finland, Organised by the  Egyptological Society of Finland, 23.1.2007. Audience: 49&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Storemyr, P. (2007): Aegyptische Steinbrueche und ihre Bedeutung  zu Zeiten der Roemer. Public Lecture attached to the special exhibition  "Wege des Steines", Vindonissa Museum, Brugg, Switzerland, 28.1.2007.  Audience: ca. 55 [English translation of title: Ancient Egyptian  Quarries and Their significance in the Roman Period]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;EAIS presentation of QuarryScapes and Egyptian Quarries. &lt;a href="http://www.eais.org.eg/index.pl/quarryscapes"&gt;Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Fayoum's ancient quarry under threat. Feature article by Nadja Tomoum. &lt;i&gt;Al-Ahram Weekly &lt;/i&gt;(Cairo), April 2006. &lt;a href="http://weekly.ahram.org.eg/print/2006/788/hr1.htm" target="_blank"&gt;Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Egyptian Antiquities Information system – EAIS Newsletter,  December 2005: QuarryScapes field school in Aswan. Conservation of  ancient stone quarry landscapes in Egypt. &lt;a href="http://www.eais.org.eg/index.pl/newsletter" target="_blank"&gt;Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Egyptian Antiquities Information system – EAIS Newsletter, March 2006: QuarryScapes Kick-Off 30 Jan – 01 Feb 2006. &lt;a href="http://www.eais.org.eg/index.pl/newsletter" target="_blank"&gt;Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Bloxam, E., Storemyr, P. &amp;amp; Heldal, T. (2005): QuarryScapes:  conservation of ancient stone quarry landscapes in the Eastern  Mediterranean. &lt;i&gt;EES-Lecture, Egypt Exploration Society &lt;/i&gt;, Cairo, 7 November 2005&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Presentation of the work at Sagalassos at "Archaeology's interactive dig". &lt;a href="http://www.archaeology.org/interactive/sagalassos/field06/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;Online&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;        </content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3759985855942045459/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/quarryscapes.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3759985855942045459"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3759985855942045459"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/quarryscapes.html"
         title="QuarryScapes: conservation of ancient stone quarry landscapes in the Eastern Mediterranean"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
