<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8547989732737377968</id>
   <published>2011-12-01T09:05:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2011-12-01T10:09:06.905-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Papyrological Navigatior Updates</title>
   <content type="html">Posted today on &lt;a href="http://lists.hum.ku.dk/pipermail/papy/2011-December/000702.html"&gt;papy&lt;/a&gt;, and on&lt;a href="http://digitalpapyrology.blogspot.com/http://digitalpapyrology.blogspot.com/2011/12/papyriinfo-updates.html"&gt; Digital Papyrology:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Colleagues:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I write with some IDP updates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(1) By now you will have noticed that we have rolled out the new search &lt;br /&gt;interface. This is an entirely new way of doing search and will take &lt;br /&gt;some getting used to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A crude test scenario:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Go to &lt;a href="http://papyri.info/search"&gt;http://papyri.info/search&lt;/a&gt; . The search screen is divided into two &lt;br /&gt;parts. Search results appear on the right and search filters appear on &lt;br /&gt;the left.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The primary difference between the old and the new is that rather than &lt;br /&gt;coming up with a single search query that aims to give you exactly what &lt;br /&gt;you want, it is now possible to begin with a more open-ended search and &lt;br /&gt;successively narrow and expand it until you reach a desired end.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;So, let's say your class is interested in literacy. Run an initial &lt;br /&gt;search for #αγραμματ: enter #αγραμματ in the search box or select &lt;br /&gt;"Convert from betacode as you type" and enter #agrammat (by the way, &lt;br /&gt;this is a good option if you want to run searches from your smartphone, &lt;br /&gt;which probably does not have Unicode Greek); click 'Search'. This will &lt;br /&gt;give you words beginning with αγραμματ (# indicates a boundary; you will &lt;br /&gt;not find διαγρραμματ)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You get 446 hits--too many to show your class. You select (toward the &lt;br /&gt;bottom) "Show only records with images from:" / "Papyri.info" and click &lt;br /&gt;'Go'. This will narrow your found set down to the 16 texts that contain &lt;br /&gt;a word beginning with αγραμματ and are known (via APIS) to Papyri.info. &lt;br /&gt;But there must be more: HGV knows about a great many links to other &lt;br /&gt;sites (external to papyri.info). So, you select "Other sites" and 'Go'. &lt;br /&gt;Now you have 221 records for which some digital image is known, whether &lt;br /&gt;via APIS or HGV. Add "Print publications" and you will see that &lt;br /&gt;papyri.info knows of a total of 337 texts that have *some* image &lt;br /&gt;associated with them, whether digital or print.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Your class is working on texts from the first 2 centuries CE. So, you &lt;br /&gt;set "Date on or after" at "1 CE" and "Date on or before" to "200 CE" and &lt;br /&gt;click Go. That's 45 hits. The classroom where you are teaching has &lt;br /&gt;digital projection, but no access to books. So, you *remove* the "Print &lt;br /&gt;images exist" filter by clicking it away from the top of the right side &lt;br /&gt;of your screen. That's 28 hits; you can actually look at several of &lt;br /&gt;these in class.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A student asks how many of these were written on behalf of a man or a &lt;br /&gt;woman. Well, it wouldn't be a foolproof test, but you can now add &lt;br /&gt;another Greek search as an additional filter. So, enter "υπερ αυτης" (as &lt;br /&gt;"Word/Phrase search", which assumes that the strings that you enter are &lt;br /&gt;complete words) or "υπερ# #αυτης" (as "Substring search", which assumes &lt;br /&gt;that the strings you enter are fragments, unless you indicate a boundary &lt;br /&gt;with #). Now we have 9 hits.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Not all of the students in the class have strong Greek; so, you also set &lt;br /&gt;"Translation language" to "English" and you are down to 3 hits. Note: &lt;br /&gt;these filters are defined by what is in the system, so that if 5 of &lt;br /&gt;these texts had been translated into, say, Italian, you would have found &lt;br /&gt;that as one of your filter options. At the moment, most of the &lt;br /&gt;translations known to papyri.info come from APIS and so are in English.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;You may remove any of these filters by deselecting them (click the X &lt;br /&gt;next to each at the top of the window). Remember to remove all such &lt;br /&gt;queries before starting a completely *new* search (or click on the &lt;br /&gt;“Reset all” button.)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is a somewhat silly example, but it should give you the basic idea &lt;br /&gt;of how this new approach works and how it differs from the old. It takes &lt;br /&gt;some getting used to, but once all of the functionality is in place you &lt;br /&gt;will find that it is a much more powerful and flexible manner of searching.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Also, if you would like to track our progress toward implementing more &lt;br /&gt;complicated search functionality, you may feel free to look at the &lt;br /&gt;following Google Doc:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ajkz6D9lOd20dGtwczJSUXVhWUx6ZEJCUEhvR1lIYVE&amp;amp;hl=en_US#gid=0"&gt;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheet/ccc?key=0Ajkz6D9lOd20dGtwczJSUXVhWUx6ZEJCUEhvR1lIYVE&amp;amp;hl=en_US#gid=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is meant for our own internal use and so may not make perfect sense &lt;br /&gt;to you, but you should probably get the idea. Y = we expect this to work &lt;br /&gt;now. N = we expect this not to work now. dev = our test / development &lt;br /&gt;server. prodo = the production version of papyri.info, which you use. If &lt;br /&gt;your favorite search pattern is not there, and if you cannot achieve the &lt;br /&gt;same result with a combination of filters, we encourage you, please, to &lt;br /&gt;*send us an email*. If you don’t report an error or omission, there is a &lt;br /&gt;good chance we won’t know to correct it!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(2) You will have noted also that tens of thousands of ‘original’ &lt;br /&gt;readings now have diacriticals. So, where the scribe wrote αναδεχομε, we &lt;br /&gt;put the normalized “ἀναδέχομαι” in the text and now print “ἀναδέχομε &lt;br /&gt;papyrus” in the apparatus. Before the year is out we shall invert this &lt;br /&gt;practice, printing “ἀναδέχομε” in the text and “read ἀναδέχομαι” in the &lt;br /&gt;apparatus. This first step has been a bigger task than we had imagined, &lt;br /&gt;and we owe a great deal to the brilliant and devoted work of Faith &lt;br /&gt;Lawrence at the Department of Digital Humanities, King’s College London. &lt;br /&gt;A few thousand words still lack accents; please feel free to add such &lt;br /&gt;and submit them to us. Some small number or errors have been introduced &lt;br /&gt;along the way (outright mistakes, which will be clearly apparent as &lt;br /&gt;nonsense); we are hacking away at those, fixing as many of them as we &lt;br /&gt;can; but if you notice any please feel free to correct and submit, or &lt;br /&gt;else (if is seems to be a systematic kind of error) please just alert us &lt;br /&gt;by email.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(3) Note also that the process of adding accents and reversing the &lt;br /&gt;display-regime of regularizations was more difficult in the case of &lt;br /&gt;regularized words that wrapped from the end of one line to the beginning &lt;br /&gt;of the next. Many thousands of these we handled automatically; about &lt;br /&gt;6000 or so still need to be fixed. We think we are in position to have &lt;br /&gt;80-90% fixed in the next couple weeks. In the meantime, all lines &lt;br /&gt;affected by this are flagged with a bright red line number--you may have &lt;br /&gt;noticed this already. In all such lines you will see that chunks of &lt;br /&gt;words appear oddly at the end or beginning of an affected line; the &lt;br /&gt;apparatus entries for all such will look fine.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(4) The line-by-line commentary feature has a bug, which will create a &lt;br /&gt;dozen or so clones of some commentary entries...this is very &lt;br /&gt;frustrating. It should be fixed before the new year. Just don’t enter &lt;br /&gt;any commentary in the next few weeks!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(5) Frequent Papyrological Editor users will notice that we have &lt;br /&gt;radically overhauled our apparatus criticus capabilities.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* for BL corrections: &amp;lt;:αἱ τοῦ=BL 9.17|ed|Θίτου:&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;* for corrections proposed in journals/books: &amp;lt;:(διαγρ(άφου))=N. Gonis, &lt;br /&gt;ZPE 143 (2003) 150|ed|(διαγρ(αφῆς)):&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;* &lt;tt&gt;for corrections proposed direct to DDbDP: &amp;lt;:τοῦ=PN G. Claytor (CPR VI &lt;br /&gt;plate 35)|ed|:&amp;gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* we now support multiple regularizations: &amp;lt;:ἀνοίγεται (?)|ἀνοίεται &lt;br /&gt;(?)||reg||ἀ̣νύεται:&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;* we now support ‘regularizations’ by language (useful in multi-lingual &lt;br /&gt;texts for example): &amp;lt;:ἄρακος=grc|reg|ⲁⲣⲁⲕ:&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;* we now support combinations of all of the above, as the following &lt;br /&gt;*fictional* example illustrates:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;275a. &amp;lt;:στρ[ατηγὸς]=BL 15.2||ed||&lt;br /&gt;στρ[ατηλάτης]=J. Cowey, ZPE 150 (2020) 321-323|&lt;br /&gt;στρ[ατιώτης]=R. Ast, CdE 100 (2018) 13-15 (BL 14.5)|&lt;br /&gt;Συρ[ίων]=Original Edition:&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;* And we support extremely complicated combinations (including nesting &lt;br /&gt;of virtually every type of apparatus tag, as the following *fictional* &lt;br /&gt;example illustrates:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;75. &amp;lt;:&amp;lt;:στρ[ατηγὸς]|subst|&amp;lt;:σ.2[.?]|alt|γ.3[.?]:&amp;gt;:&amp;gt;=BL 19.2||ed||&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;:&amp;lt;:στρ[ατηλάτης]|reg|ξ̣τ̣ρ[ατηλάτης]:&amp;gt;|alt|.1γρ[.?]:&amp;gt;=J. Cowey, ZPE 200 &lt;br /&gt;(2020) 321-323|&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;:&amp;lt;:στρ[ατιώτης]|alt|στρ[ατηγία]:&amp;gt;|reg|στυ̣ρ[ατ][.?]:&amp;gt;=R. Ast, CdE 100 &lt;br /&gt;(2018) 13-15 (BL 14.5)|&lt;br /&gt;&amp;lt;:Συρ[ίων](?)|reg|&amp;lt;:&amp;lt;:Σο̣υ̣ρ[ίων]||alt||Συ̣υ̣ρ[ίων]|Σω̣υ̣ρ[ίων]:&amp;gt;|subst|Σ.2ρ[ίων]:&amp;gt;:&amp;gt;=Original &lt;br /&gt;Edition:&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This means:&lt;br /&gt;(i) at line 275 the DDbDP prints στρ[ατηγὸς], which the scribe himself &lt;br /&gt;corrected from either "σ . . [ca.?]" or "γ . . . [ca.?]", and which is &lt;br /&gt;recorded in BL vol.19 p.2&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(ii) previously, Cowey had argued (in ZPE 200) for correcting the text &lt;br /&gt;to either στρ[ατηλάτης], which is a modern regularization of &lt;br /&gt;ξ̣τ̣ρ[ατηλάτης], or to ". γρ[ca.?]"&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(iii) before Cowey, Ast had suggested (in CdÉ 100) that the papyrus &lt;br /&gt;reads στυ̣ρ[ατ- ca.?], which should be regularized either to στρ[ατιώτης] &lt;br /&gt;or to στρ[ατηγία]; this was subsequently picked up by BL 14.5&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(iv) The original editors of the papyrus thought that the scribe had &lt;br /&gt;originally written "Σ . . ρ[ίων]", and then corrected it to either &lt;br /&gt;Σο̣υ̣ρ[ίων] or Συ̣υ̣ρ[ίων] or Σω̣υ̣ρ[ίων], any one of which should perhaps be &lt;br /&gt;regularized to Συρ[ίων]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The PN will display στρ[ατηγὸς] in the text and in the app: 275. corr. &lt;br /&gt;ex σ ̣ ̣[ -ca.?- ] (or γ ̣ ̣ ̣[ -ca.?- ]) BL 19.2 : ξ̣τ̣ρ[ατηλάτης] (l. &lt;br /&gt;στρ[ατηλάτης]) (or ̣γρ[ -ca.?- ]) J. Cowey, ZPE 200 (2020) 321-323 : &lt;br /&gt;στυ̣ρ[ατ -ca.?- ] (l. στρ[ατιώτης (or στρ[ατηγία])) R. Ast, CdE 100 &lt;br /&gt;(2018) 13-15 (BL 14.5) : Σο̣υ̣ρ[ίων] (or Συ̣υ̣ρ[ίων] or Σω̣υ̣ρ[ίων]) (corr. ex &lt;br /&gt;Σ ̣ ̣ρ[ίων]) (l. Συρ[ίων]) Original Edition. This is not *precisely* what &lt;br /&gt;you expect to find in a print publication, but it is full, clear, and &lt;br /&gt;quite unambiguous.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This is, we think, a huge achievement and a great good; we have Gabby &lt;br /&gt;Bodard at King’s College and Jon Fox at the University of Kentucky to thank!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Leiden+ Documentation page should now reflect most/all of these &lt;br /&gt;improvements: (&lt;a href="http://papyri.info/editor/documentation?docotype=text"&gt;http://papyri.info/editor/documentation?docotype=text&lt;/a&gt;); &lt;br /&gt;please let us know if we have missed something. Also, please note that &lt;br /&gt;the Apparatus “Helpers” (for BL, Editorial, and SoSOL) are now buggy as &lt;br /&gt;a result of the changes but should be fixed before the new year. In the &lt;br /&gt;meantime, enter apparatus entries by hand.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(6) I shall also mention just briefly that thanks to the extraordinary &lt;br /&gt;generosity and collegiality of our colleagues in Brussels, Alain Martin, &lt;br /&gt;Paul Heilporn, and Alain Delattre, we have begun a process of surfacing &lt;br /&gt;Bibliographie Papyrologique data via the PN. Our Heidelberg colleagues &lt;br /&gt;James Cowey and Carmen Lanz did an amazing amount of work to make this &lt;br /&gt;happen. You will see that there are still many bugs in the conversion of &lt;br /&gt;the BP records to structured XML, but we are getting there one step at a &lt;br /&gt;time. From the navigation bar at the top of the PN select Search / &lt;br /&gt;Bibliography. This will take you to a very *simple* search screen, where &lt;br /&gt;you may enter, for example, “Hombert” (no quotation marks) &lt;br /&gt;(&lt;a href="http://papyri.info/bibliosearch?q=Hombert"&gt;http://papyri.info/bibliosearch?q=Hombert&lt;/a&gt;); or you may constrain the &lt;br /&gt;search by BP fields. So, if you enter “author:Hombert; &lt;br /&gt;title:bibliographie; date:1932” (no quotation marks) you will get 2 &lt;br /&gt;records &lt;br /&gt;(&lt;a href="http://papyri.info/bibliosearch?q=author%3AHombert%3B+title%3Abibliographie%3B+date%3A1932+"&gt;http://papyri.info/bibliosearch?q=author%3AHombert%3B+title%3Abibliographie%3B+date%3A1932+&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;br /&gt;This works also for BP subject codes; so, for example, “index:146” will &lt;br /&gt;find 1106 records concerning Archives. The FileMaker version of the BP &lt;br /&gt;remains much more flexible, powerful, and manipulable, for those users &lt;br /&gt;who are so inclined. In the next few weeks we shall be able to link from &lt;br /&gt;BP records to DDbDP texts and from DDbDP texts to BP records. This is &lt;br /&gt;only a start; we expect this service to improve dramatically over the &lt;br /&gt;coming months, soon with the ability to add/correct records, and submit &lt;br /&gt;them for review by the BP editorial team.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This message is already far too long. So, enough for now.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As always, please feel free to send questions, comments, complaints to &lt;br /&gt;Josh Sosin &amp;lt;&lt;a href="http://lists.hum.ku.dk/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/papy"&gt;jds15 at duke.edu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;, Rodney Ast &amp;lt;&lt;a href="http://lists.hum.ku.dk/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/papy"&gt;ast at uni-heidelberg.de&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;, and &lt;br /&gt;James Cowey &amp;lt;&lt;a href="http://lists.hum.ku.dk/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/papy"&gt;james.cowey at urz.uni-heidelberg.de&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;; same, with regard to PN &lt;br /&gt;performance to Hugh Cayless &amp;lt;&lt;a href="http://lists.hum.ku.dk/cgi-bin/mailman/listinfo/papy"&gt;hugh.cayless at nyu.edu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;All best,&lt;br /&gt;Rodney Ast&lt;br /&gt;James Cowey&lt;br /&gt;Josh Sosin&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8547989732737377968/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/12/papyrological-navigatior-updates.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8547989732737377968"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8547989732737377968"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/12/papyrological-navigatior-updates.html"
         title="Papyrological Navigatior Updates"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
