<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6738841839259111335</id>
   <published>2013-05-21T09:15:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-05-21T09:15:10.087-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Rome"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="numismatics"/>
   <title type="text">Severan Database Project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/">Severan Database Project</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/images/3.jpg" class="decoded" height="54" src="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/images/3.jpg" width="320" />&nbsp;</blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div id="tpl_leftCol">   <div class="mainMenu"><ul><li><a href="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/">Home</a></li><li><a class="current" href="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/databases/">Databases</a></li><li><a href="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/researchers/">Researchers</a></li><li><a href="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/publications/">Publications</a></li></ul></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/spc/">Severan Provincial Coinage</a>: <br />Author: Julie Langford </span></h2><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This database anticipates Volume V of the ongoing series Roman  Provincial Coinage.  It contains records of coins minted from twelve  cities in Asia Minor from the reigns of Septimius Severus, Caracalla,  Macrinus, Elagabalus and Severus Alexander.  The data was mined from  volumes of the Sylloge Nummorum Graecorum found at the American  Numismatic Society and the Hunterian Museum in Glasglow, Scotland.  A  team of five undergraduate researchers at the University of South  Florida under the direction of Prof. Julie Langford compiled and keyed  in this data.  While these entries have been proofed, there are some  issues of consistency that are still being ironed out, mostly in terms  of Greek inscriptions.  Please notify Julie Langford  (jlangfor@cas.usf.edu) in case of any errors or omissions.  Since this  is an ongoing project, we welcome collaboration to expand the cities or  the volumes of the SNG consulted. </span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Researchers at the University of South Florida are employing this  database in order to explore issues such as the reception of Severan  imperial propaganda, the maintenance of civic identity and the  competition between cities, especially in terms of Neokoroi. </span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The database is searchable by keywords, citation and Greek legends. It  allows researchers to view the catalogs of several coin cabinets at a  glance.  When used in conjunction with published volumes of Roman  Provincial Coinage and RPC Online, the database can be used to create an  overview of a city’s numismatic history.  </span></blockquote><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/coins/">Severan Hoard Analysis</a><br />Author: Clare Rowan</span></h2><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This database was constructed as part of the research conducted for my  doctorate, Under Divine Auspices: Patron Deities and the Visualisation  of Power in the Severan Period. The research was funded by an Australian  Postgraduate Award, and was completed at Macquarie University, which  houses the Australian Centre for Ancient Numismatic Studies. Given the  potential of the information contained in the database for future  research, it was decided to make the database available online, at the  same address as the Severan provincial coinage project. <br /><br />The database contains fifty-seven silver hoards ranging in date from AD  198 to c. AD 270.  Hoards with a terminus post quem well after the  Severan period are included since it could take some time for coins to  reach a peak in circulation. The paucity of gold and aes hoards  containing Severan material meant that these metals were not included.  There are two displays available to the user: one provides a listing of  all Severan types found within a particular hoard, and the other  provides a summary of all Severan coin types found in the entire sample  (all the hoards considered together).  Consequently, it is possible to  get a one-click overview of the relative frequency of each Severan type,  as well as to trace in what hoard each type occurs. The publication  details of each hoard are provided, as well as an indication of its  geographic locality. For the latter, the established A-E lettering  system is used (A = Britain, B = West Continent, C = Italy and Africa, D  = Danubian regions, E = the East).  These particular divisions may not  reveal divergences in coinage circulation as efficiently as other  groupings (for example between central and peripheral regions, or  military and non-military areas), but in the interests of continuity and  to facilitate comparisons with other modern work, the A-E scheme is  employed here.   <br /><br />For hoards that were published using Cohen's catalogue, the Cohen-RIC  concordance was used to convert the data (Chantraine, H. and Alföldi, M.  R.-. (1978). Cohen - RIC - Konkordanz. Bonn.)  Coins in a hoard that  possessed no ready RIC reference, or were illegible, are tallied at the  end. Illegible coins of Julia Domna are included in the total of Domna  types struck under Severus, and illegible coins of Caracalla are  included in the total of coins struck during his sole rule.  This  decision was made since most of Domna's coins were struck under Severus,  and most of Caracalla's types come from his sole reign; consequently,  there is a higher chance that illegible types come from these periods.  No coins of Elagabalus' wife Annia Faustina were found in any of the  hoards consulted, and consequently she does not figure at all in the  database. Occasionally the data also includes subtypes listed in the RIC  (e.g. RIC 8b); these are indicated by letters in the entry (e.g. 3 aab =  3 examples of this type were found in the hoard, 2 of subtype a, and  one of subtype b). <br /><br />The database is not intended to give an absolute indication of coins  struck under the Severans, but only a suggestion of relative frequency.  Occasionally the totals of coinage struck for each Severan emperor will  differ slightly from the original publication, particularly for those  hoards that were published by Cohen number.  This reflects the fact that  some issues listed in Cohen's catalogue were later attributed to  different emperors (for instance deification issues of Severus,  attributed to Severus by Cohen, were placed with Caracalla's issues by  Mattingly). Very occasionally, a discrepancy reflects a miscalculation  in the original publication. Any errors or omissions may be gratefully  brought to the attention of the author (clare.rowan@students.mq.edu.au),  but any such instances will not fundamentally alter the image of  Severan coinage contained within the database. </span></blockquote><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://web3.forest.usf.edu/main/other/severan/jdi/">Julia Domna Inscriptions</a><br />Author: Julie Langford </span></h2><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> This ongoing project aims to collect all inscriptions in which the  Severan Empress Julia Domna is mentioned.  A team of undergraduate  researchers at the University of South Florida under the direction of  Professor Julie Langford began the database with references to the 460  inscriptions published in Erich Kettenhofen’s Die syrischen Augustae in  der historischen Überlieferung published in Bonn by Rudolf Habelt in  1979.  They gathered these and then mined L’Annee Epigraphique for any  other references to Julia Domna.  Also employed in collecting these  inscriptions were two invaluable online databases, the Packard  Humanities Institute (http://epigraphy.packhum.org/inscriptions/) and  the Epigraphische Datenbank Clauss-Slaby (http://www.manfredclauss.de/).   </span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">This database is being used by Julie Langford and graduate researchers  at the University of South Florida to answer questions such as how,  where and when the Empress was celebrated, whether she was honored in  her own right or in conjunction with her male relatives, and how various  populations responded to imperial propaganda concerning the Empress. </span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">This database will continue to grow as new inscriptions are published.   Please call any errors or omissions to the attention of Prof. Julie  Langford (jlangfor@cas.usf.edu).   </span><br /></blockquote></blockquote><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6738841839259111335/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/05/severan-database-project.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6738841839259111335"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6738841839259111335"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/05/severan-database-project.html"
         title="Severan Database Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
