<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9198104256890785540</id>
   <published>2013-02-20T16:30:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-02-20T16:27:51.722-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: ArchAtlas Journal</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="color: #0000ee; font-size: xx-small;">[First<span style="color: #0000ee;"> posted in AWOL 11 February 2010. Updated 20 February 2013]</span></span><span style="font-size: xx-small;"> </span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/journal/journal.php">ArchAtlas Journal</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="logo">ArchAtlas</span> Journal provides a vehicle for  presenting case studies on archaeological problems and ideas in a  graphical form. Our articles are <i>visual essays</i>, many of which originated as presentation papers at conferences. In addition, the papers from our themed <span class="logo">ArchAtlas</span> workshops, based at the Department of Archaeology, University of Sheffield, are published in the journal.</span></blockquote><blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Visual Essays</span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">2012</span><br /><table border="0" cellpadding="2"> <tbody><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/occpaper/Ferrand.php"><img alt="Geospatial Analysis of Aguadas" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/aguadas.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Ezgi Akpinar Ferrand, Benjamin Thomas III, Nicholas P. Dunning,  Southern Connecticut State University, University of Cincinnati       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/occpaper/Ferrand.php"><cite>Geovisualization and Analysis of <i>Agudas</i>: Natural or Human-made Ponds in the Southern Maya Lowlands<cite></cite></cite></a> (June 2012)       <br />Water has been a principal concern for Maya people inhabiting  much of the Yucatan Peninsula for millennia.  As a result, studies of  water management in the Maya region contribute significantly to our  understanding of ancient Maya civilization and its environmental  adaptations. <i>Aguadas</i>, water storage ponds of varying size, have  been an understudied aspect of Maya water management systems.  Recognizing the origins and functions of aguadas provides a more  complete picture of ancient Maya water management strategies.  In this  study, we analyze <i>aguadas</i> geovisually and geospatially in the southern Maya lowlands.       </span></td>      </tr></tbody></table><table border="0" style="width: 100%px;"><tbody><tr><td class="ltblueback"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2010</span></td></tr></tbody></table><table border="0" cellpadding="2"> <tbody><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-massa.php"><img alt="Networks of interaction in Early Bronze Age Anatolia" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/works09-massa.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Michele Massa, Institute of Archaeology, University College, London       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-massa.php"><cite>Networks of interaction in Early Bronze Age Anatolia<cite></cite></cite></a> (Nov. 2010)       <br />Research carried out in Turkey over the last few decades seems  to indicate that the Early Bronze Age in west and central Anatolia was a  period in which new socio-political structures emerged whose mature  development is reflected in the territorial entities of the Old Assyrian  period. From the second half of the third millennium, we have evidence  of social stratification both at the intra-site and inter-site level,  accompanied by a wealth of prestige goods and public structures  displayed in settlement and funerary contexts. This phenomenon is also  paralleled by the rapid growth of long-distance relations both within  Anatolia and with surrounding regions, at least partially triggered by  the rise in metal demand of local and foreign elites.        </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-whitfield.php"><img alt="Mapping the Silk Road" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/works09-whitfield.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Susan Whitfield, Victoria Swift, Alastair Morrison &amp; Sam Vanschaik, British Library (IDP)       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-whitfield.php"><cite>IDP: Mapping of archaeological sites uncovered in the early twentieth century along the Silk Road<cite></cite></cite></a> (Nov. 2010)       <br />Little was known of the remarkable heritage of the Silk Road  until explorers and archaeologists of the early twentieth century  uncovered the ruins of ancient cities in the desert sands, revealing  astonishing sculptures, murals and manuscripts. One of the most notable  discoveries was the Buddhist cave library near the oasis town of  Dunhuang on the edge of the Gobi desert in western China. The cave had  been sealed and hidden at the end of the first millennium AD and only  re-discovered in 1900. Forty thousand manuscripts, paintings and printed  documents on paper and silk were found in the cave itself. Tens of  thousands more items were excavated from other Silk Road archaeological  sites. These unique items have fascinating stories to tell of life on  this great trade route from 100 BC to AD 1400. Yet most were dispersed  to institutions worldwide in the early 1900s, making access difficult.    The size and scope of the collections, as well as their fragility and  limited access, has meant that, while they constitute a primary research  resource for the history and literature of the region, many of the  manuscripts in particular have yet to be studied in detail.  The <a href="http://www.archatlas.org/journal/%E2%80%99http://idp.bl.uk/idp.a4d%E2%80%99" target="’_blank’">International Dunhuang Project</a> aims to reunite this material by making it freely available online.   One part of this project includes the mapping of archaeological sites,  and the digitisation of data from archaeological data collected by Aurel  Stein and other researchers, using tools such as Google Earth to help  users to better understand the history of the Tarim Basin and its  cultures.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-wordsworth.php"><img alt="Trade networks in the Karakum" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/works09-wordsworth.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Paul D. Wordsworth, Institute of Archaeology, University College, London       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-wordsworth.php"><cite>Traversing the Karakum: Approaches to defining trade networks through the desert landscapes of Medieval Central Asia<cite></cite></cite></a> (Oct. 2010)       <br />In our imagination of the 'Silk Routes', we envisage  travellers, traders and intellectuals traversing vast continents for the  purpose of exchanging rare and precious items. The archaeological study  of these routes has usually focused on transmitted artefacts and ideas,  as opposed to the means and methods by which they were carried. The  resultant void of knowledge concerning the infrastructure of the Silk  Roads, and the nature of the settlements that shaped and were shaped by  them, presents a challenge to archaeologists from both a methodological  and theoretical perspective.        </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="The 5th Dynasty Byblos Ship" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/works09-gallagher.jpg" width="150" /></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   John Gallagher, Oxford University       <br /><cite class="orange">The 5th Dynasty Byblos Ship: seaborne communication and exchange in the East Mediterranean in the mid-3rd millennium BC</cite> (March 2010)       <br />A consideration of the 5th Dynasty Byblos-ship and the  probable limitations to Egyptian sail-and-oar technology of the mid-3rd  millennium BC.  The suggested limitations to this technology are used to  shed light on how and where it was possible to voyage in the mid-3rd  millennium East Mediterranean basin.  The long-established and rarely  scrutinised notion in Aegean archaeology that the sea facilitated direct  contact between the Aegean and neighbouring regions of the East  Mediterranean basin (the north African coast, Egyptian delta, and  Levantine littoral) from deep in prehistory is argued to be mistaken.   Instead, it is suggested, the Aegean archipelago and its sail-less boats  were a world remote from the African and Levantine seaboards until some  point after the mid-3rd millennium BC.  [Abstract only]       </span></td>      </tr></tbody></table><table border="0" style="width: 100%px;"><tbody><tr><td class="ltblueback"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2009</span></td></tr></tbody></table><table border="0" cellpadding="2"> <tbody><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-akar.php"><img alt="Levant Harbour Towns in the Middle Bronze Age" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/works09-akar.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Murat Akar, Universitá degli Studi Firenze (Florence)       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-akar.php"><cite>The  Role of Harbour Towns in the Re-Urbanization of the Northern Levant in  the Middle Bronze Age: Perspectives from Cilicia and the Amuq Plain of  Hatay<cite></cite></cite></a> (Dec. 2009)       <br />Trading connections and routes play a very important part in  the development (or re-development) of urban centres in the Middle  Bronze Age Levant. This is particularly clear in the regions of Cilicia  and the Amuq Plain in the Hatay, in the north-east corner of the East  Mediterranean, where at the beginning of the Middle Bronze Age we have  evidence of large-scale public buildings and fortification systems which  represent the revival of complex political and economic structures,  following a collapse at the end of the Early Bronze Age. A key role in  this is played by harbour towns on the Cilician and Levantine coasts,  which have an important part in the articulation and exploitation of  maritime and inland routes connecting different zones and their  resources. This in turn leads, by the beginning of the Late Bronze Age,  to the formation of a symbiotic network of semi-dependent kingdoms which  link these different inland and coastal zones in a single interactive  socio-economic system.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-tavernari.php"><img alt="Roads &amp; caravanserais in Medieval Syria" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/works09-tavernari.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Cinzia Tavernari, University of La Sorbonne-Paris IV       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-tavernari.php"><cite>The CIERA program and activities: focus on the roads and wayside caravanserais in medieval Syria<cite></cite></cite></a> (Oct. 2009)       <br />New research is currently being carried out in order to  collect supplementary data, both historical and archaeological, on the  road networks of Medieval Bilād al-Šām and their related facilities.  Supported by the material evidence of caravanserais, the aim of the  research is to propose a reconstruction and a preliminary analysis of  the region's communication axis from the beginning of the Ayyubid period  till the end of the Mamluk. The preliminary character of the  reflections offered in this article will hopefully be pursued more  thoroughly in the completion of a larger project now in its final phase.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-wilkinson.php"><img alt="Pathways and Highways" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/works09-wilkinson.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Toby Wilkinson, University of Sheffield       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop09/works09-wilkinson.php"><cite>Pathways and highways: routes in Bronze Age Eurasia<cite></cite></cite></a> (Oct. 2009)       <br />This visual essay explores the possibility of delineating two  different types of routes, "pathways" and "highways", and the extent to  which archaeology can help to analyse them. The technologies of  cost-raster GIS analysis are introduced and applied to two case studies  in Eastern Anatolia and Western Central Asia, c. 3000-1000 BC. It is to  be hoped that the highlighted patterns, combined with a knowledge of  contemporary material transformations, will provide insights into the  processes of socio-economic change across these reconstructed networks  of interaction.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/occpaper/sat-usage.php"><img alt="Introduction to Remote Sensing data for Global Archaeology" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/sat-usage.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Toby Wilkinson, University of Sheffield       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/occpaper/sat-usage.php"><cite>Introduction to Remote Sensing data for Global Archaeology<cite></cite></cite></a> (July 2009)       <br />This document briefly introduces some of the key sources of  spatial data from remote sensing sources, and a few other data types  which have been particularly useful for archaeological research, and in  particular, in the construction of <span class="logo">ArchAtlas</span>.       </span></td>      </tr></tbody></table><table border="0" style="width: 100%px;"><tbody><tr><td class="ltblueback"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2007</span></td></tr></tbody></table><table border="0" cellpadding="2"> <tbody><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/TWilkinson07.php"><img alt="Ancient Near Eastern Route Systems" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/twilkinson07.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Tony J. Wilkinson, Department of Archaeology, University of Durham       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/TWilkinson07.php"><cite>Ancient Near Eastern Route Systems: From the Ground Up<cite></cite></cite></a> (Nov. 2007)       <br />A particularly common trace of ancient route systems on the  ground is the 'hollow way'. In the Middle East hollow ways, like their  counterparts in the UK and Europe, appear as long, usually straight  valleys. This paper examines the traces of these ancient route systems  in the Ancient Near East according to their pattern, processes of  formation, parallels elsewhere, and their function.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Philip07.php"><img alt="Unscrambling the " border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/philip07.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Graham Philip, Department of Archaeology, University of Durham       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Philip07.php"><cite>Unscrambling the 'Uplands': Satellite Imagery and the Homs Basalts<cite></cite></cite></a> (Oct. 2007)       <br />This presentation forms part of a a collaborative British-Syrian project called <cite>Settlement and Landscape Development in the Homs Region, Syria</cite>,  that seeks to compare human activity in adjacent but contrasting  landscapes in a typical part of western Syria. In this case we focus on  an upland landscape, where stone architecture is the expectation. In the  traditional literature, most discussion of such areas has concentrated  upon the evidence for activity of Graeco-Roman date - the Dead Cities of  the Limestone Massif on north-western Syria are an excellent example.  However, we have very little knowledge of the evidence for earlier  periods. This is, we suspect, because we have little idea of what we  should be looking for.        </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Petrie07.php"><img alt="Remote Sensing in Inaccessible Lands" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/petrie07.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Cameron Petrie, Department of Archaeology, University of Cambridge       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Petrie07.php"><cite>Remote Sensing in Inaccessible Lands: Plains and preservation along old routes between Pakistan and Afghanistan<cite></cite></cite></a> (Sept. 2007)       <br />The current political situation in many areas of Western and  Central Asia makes effective ground based archaeological research  virtually impossible. Whilst people are generally cognisant of the  situation in Iraq, this is also true for Afghanistan and parts of  Pakistan. Furthermore, since the mid-19th century, the mountainous  regions that comprise the eastern borderlands of modern Afghanistan,  along with the western parts of the North West Frontier Province (NWFP)  and the Tribal Areas of modern Pakistan have been difficult to access  for extended periods. However, with the widespread availability of free  or inexpensive satellite imagery, it is now possible to 'visit' these  regions by looking at them from space. The use of satellite imagery in  this way has a number of specific archaeological applications, including  the reconstruction of ancient routes, the remote detection of  archaeological sites and the assessment of site destruction and looting.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Ur07.php"><img alt="Agricultural and Pastoral Landscapes in the Near East" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/works_logo.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Jason Ur, Department of Anthropology, Harvard University       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Ur07.php"><cite>Agricultural and Pastoral Landscapes in the Near East: Case Studies using CORONA Satellite Photography <cite></cite></cite></a> (Sept. 2007)       <br />The Near East presents particular challenges to the study of  past landscapes. Remote sensing has been a part of archaeology for a  century, and aerial photographic coverage is now the ideal and standard  for field survey basemaps. Such coverge, however, is not globally  available. In the modern Middle East, for example, easy access to aerial  photography is often impossible to obtain. As a result, archaeologists  have turned to satellite imagery. Unfortunately, the resolution of  space-based imaging systems such as Landsat and SPOT is often too coarse  for archaeological features. To some extent, this issue has been solved  by the availability of commercial high-resolution imagery. However,  such imagery is expensive and documents the modern developed landscape.  Over the last decade, Near Eastern archaeologists employed a new  satellite resource that resolves many of these issues: the declassified  CORONA intelligence program.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Muehl07.php"><img alt="Mat Ashur - Land of Ashur" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/muehl07.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Simone Mühl, Institute of Pre- and Early History and Near Eastern Archaeology, Heidelberg       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Muehl07.php"><cite>Mat Ashur - Land of Ashur. The Plain of Makhmur, Iraq<cite></cite></cite></a> (Aug. 2007)       <br />This paper gives an introduction to the archaeology of the  Assyrian heartland where only a limited investigation outside of the big  centres has taken place in the field. With methods of landscape  archaeology and remote sensing techniques it is possible to survey a  wide area and integrate detected landscape features into an historical  framework and social and chronological contexts.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Menze07.php"><img alt="Quantitative approaches to the remote sensing of ancient settlements" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/menze07.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Björn Menze, Interdisciplinary Centre for Scientific Computing, University of Heidelberg       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Menze07.php"><cite>Quantitative approaches to the remote sensing of ancient settlements in the Near East using ASTER and SRTM data<cite></cite></cite></a> (July 2007)       <br /><i>Tells</i>, the characteristic settlement mounds of the Near  East, are visible remains of the first human settlement system. Often  piled up to considerable heights by the debris of millennia of  settlement activity, they provide characteristic physical signatures,  such as specific elevation profiles or soil changes, which – potentially  – can be detected in data available from space-borne sensors. Using  methods from pattern recognition and statistical learning, we  systematically evaluated digital elevation models and multispectral  imagery to provide means for a machine based detection and mapping of  these archaeologically relevant settlement sites.        </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Wilkinson.php"><img alt="Virtual globes, geotagging and global landscapes" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/wilkinson07.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Toby Wilkinson, British Institute at Ankara       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/workshop/Wilkinson.php"><cite>Virtual globes, geotagging and global landscapes: visualisation and database technologies in the age of the Internet<cite></cite></cite></a> (July 2007)       <br />This paper raises a series of broad issues about a particular set of new technologies which have become available for <cite>Mapping Human History from Space</cite>,  namely: virtual globes, such as Google Earth and NASA's WorldWind, and  their relationship to online archaeological datasets. First, some of  technical background to these visualisation programs is explained,  especially how they stand in relationship to previous GIS approaches.  Issues with the increasing trend within archaeology, to publish site  locations and other archaeological information using online databases  are raised; and the possibilities and problems for a global  archaeological atlas and the integration of multiple databases are  explored. Finally the paper touches on the possible future research  applications of initiatives which use novel visualisation and  integrative databases.        </span></td>      </tr></tbody></table><table border="0" style="width: 100%px;"><tbody><tr><td class="ltblueback"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2006</span></td></tr></tbody></table><table border="0" cellpadding="2"> <tbody><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Tellspotting/TellsMain.php"><img alt="Tellspotting" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/tellspotting.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Tellspotting/TellsMain.php"><cite>Tellspotting<cite></cite></cite></a> (2006)       <br />How do we know where sites are? In the arc from south-east  Europe to north-west India, early farming sites often form prominent  mounds (known from the Arabic term as <i>tell</i> settlements). Such  sites were often occupied over many millennia, and some of them grew  into major cities during the Bronze Age – though thereafter settlement  tended to shift to new locations away from the mounds. These early  settlement-mounds form characteristic features of the landscape, and in  fact are visible from space. Release of data from the Shuttle Radar  Topography Mission in 2000 has provided the opportunity to identify the  positions of many known archaeological sites of this type and to  recognise others. Tellspotting is now not only an agreeable hobby, but  has a high-tech methodology: an invaluable tool in reconstructing  settlement-history and a means of inventorizing these outstanding  sources of archaeological information.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/VRMLs/VRMLs.php"><img alt="Sites and Landscapes in 3D" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/VRMLS.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt and Francesco Menotti       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/VRMLs/VRMLs.php"><cite>Sites and Landscapes in 3D (VRML images)<cite></cite></cite></a> (2006)       <br />If we have elevation data (conventionally represented by  contour-lines) and satellite imagery, why not combine the two? This  allows a site to be represented not just in a vertical view, but as it  is seen from different viewpoints. Why not combine them all, so that it  can be examined from all angles, flown over, walked through? These are  some examples of famous areas and sites. A hint of the future, when such  representations will be routine.       </span></td>      </tr></tbody></table><table border="0" style="width: 100%px;"><tbody><tr><td class="ltblueback"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2005</span></td></tr></tbody></table><table border="0" cellpadding="2"> <tbody><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/CultureAreas/CultureAreas.php"><img alt="Culture Areas in Western Eurasia 20,000-3250BC" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/cultures.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/CultureAreas/CultureAreas.php"><cite>Culture Areas in Western Eurasia 20,000-3250BC<cite></cite></cite></a> (2005)       <br />Prehistoric archaeologists have some weird labels for their  material, naming cultural groups after the sites where they were first  recognised, or after their most characteristic artefacts. These make a  whole lot more sense when plotted on maps, period by period, so that  patterns of cultural similarity, and connection become apparent. Do  'cultures' exist? I don't know, but if archaeologists use them in their  everyday work, it makes sense to know where they are, or are thought to  be.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/EastWest/EastWest.php"><img alt="East-West Contacts in Eurasia" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/silkroad.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/EastWest/EastWest.php"><cite>East-West Contacts in Eurasia<cite></cite></cite></a> (2005)       <br />Connections between the eastern and western ends of Eurasia  began in the Bronze Age: China and the West co-evolved. A global  viewpoint shows how this happened, first across the forests of Siberia,  then by the steppes and oases of the Silk Road, then increasingly by  sea, via the Indian Ocean. This is a human story of cultural encounter,  exchange and creativity – and, ultimately, geo-economics.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/OriginsFarming/Farming.php"><img alt="The Origins of Farming in South-West Asia" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/originsoffarming.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/OriginsFarming/Farming.php"><cite>The Origins of Farming in South-West Asia<cite></cite></cite></a> (2005)       <br />Satellite images provide a convenient means of understanding  why early sites were chosen for settlement, and of visualising the  routes that linked them. These two factors (location amongst critical  resources, and position in wider networks) interacted with each other:  oases were occupied both because of their local advantages, and also  because they acted as stepping-stones on routes carrying desirable  materials over long distances. This presentation applies these arguments  to a critical problem in prehistoric archaeology: where precisely did  farming first emerge in western Asia?        </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Processes/ContagiousProcesses.php"><img alt="Contagious Processes" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/contagious.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Processes/ContagiousProcesses.php"><cite>Contagious Processes<cite></cite></cite></a> (2005)       <br />Archaeologists have long recognised (though in practice tend  to forget) the degree to which developments in one part of the world  were affected by things happening elsewhere. These animated maps of the  spread of farming and of urbanism are intended to show a fundamental  aspect of long-term human history: the underlying patterns of concentric  expansion which have characterised cultural change in the Holocene.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Portages/Portages.php"><img alt="Portages" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/portage.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Portages/Portages.php"><cite>Portages<cite></cite></cite></a> (2005)       <br />Early trading networks carried relatively small quantities of  valuable goods, often over considerable distances, both by land and  water. The relationship between overland transport and carriage by river  or sea helps to explain why trading centres rose to prominence at  certain key positions on these routes. With very small quantities of  goods, light vessels might be carried over short distances between  rivers; and even when the bulk of traded goods increased, it might still  be advantageous to carry the goods for short distances overland from  one port to another. Sites at such break-of-bulk points became major  nodes in the transport network. This presentation explores the changing  geometry of early trade-routes, and especially the interface between  land and sea.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/ObsidianRoutes/ObsidianRoutes.php"><img alt="The Obsidian Trade in the Near East, 14,000 to 6500 BC" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/obsidian.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/ObsidianRoutes/ObsidianRoutes.php"><cite>Obsidian Trade in the Near East, 14,000 to 6500 BC<cite></cite></cite></a> (2005)       <br />Obsidian, a black volcanic glass, was first recognized by  Colin Renfrew and his colleagues J.E. Dixon and J.R. Cann in the 1960s  as a uniquely sensitive indicator of prehistoric trade, both because of  the great desirability of this material before the use of metals, and  also because the trace-elements it contains are usually diagnostic of  individual sources. Based on data extracted from M.-C. Cauvin <i>et al.</i>, <cite>L'obsidienne au Proche et Moyen Orient: du volcan à l'outil</cite> (Oxford: BAR Int. Ser. 738), maps indicate the flows of material from two major source-areas.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Panoramas/Panoramas.php"><img alt="Panoramas" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/panoramas.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt and Toby Wilkinson       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Panoramas/Panoramas.php"><cite>Panoramas<cite></cite></cite></a> (2005)       <br />Understanding the setting of an archaeological site has two  components: an experience of its location, from a human standpoint  (standing, sitting, observing), and an appreciation of its position (on a  map, an aerial photograph, or a satellite image). The first gives a  situated view of the landscape, unlike the abstract, distanced view.  Panoramas thus offer a natural complement to the vertical or  near-vertical views which predominate on these web-pages.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Menze/MenzeTellspotting.php"><img alt="Virtual Survey: a semi-automated tellspotting algorithm" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/menze.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Björn Menze       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Menze/MenzeTellspotting.php"><cite>Virtual Survey: a semi-automated tellspotting algorithm<cite></cite></cite></a> (2005)       <br />Following the observation that prehistoric and early historic  settlement-mounds (tell settlements) in parts of the Near and Middle  East can be recognized in the SRTM 90m terrain model (Sherratt, <cite>Antiquity</cite> 2004) an algorithm has been developed to do this automatically, using current techniques of computer modeling.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Petrie/RoutesandPlains.php"><img alt="Exploring Routes and Plains in Southwest Iran" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/iran-routes2.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Cameron Petrie       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Petrie/RoutesandPlains.php"><cite>Exploring Routes and Plains in Southwest Iran<cite></cite></cite></a> (2005)       <br />Satellite imaging has given a new dimension to fieldwork in  the varied terrain of Southwestern Iran, where the Zagros mountains  separate the Mesopotamian lowlands from highland Iran, and whose  successive ridges enclose fertile intermontane valleys. These fertile  enclaves were often settled as early as the Neolithic, and have a  continuous history of occupation down to the present day. They gained a  historical importance as stepping stones on routes through the mountains  (both for transhumance and trade), and as nodal points in the formation  of political units.       </span></td>      </tr></tbody></table><table border="0" style="width: 100%px;"><tbody><tr><td class="ltblueback"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2004</span></td></tr></tbody></table><table border="0" cellpadding="2"><tbody><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/EnvironmentalChange/EnvironmentalChange.php"><img alt="Environmental Change: The evolution of Mesopotamia" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/envchange.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/EnvironmentalChange/EnvironmentalChange.php"><cite>Environmental Change: the evolution of Mesopotamia<cite></cite></cite></a> (2004)       <br />The areas that were occupied by early farmers and  town-dwellers were often very different from the landscapes that can be  seen in the same areas today. Some of the most important changes took  place in the great river basins where urban civilisation first emerged.  Southern Mesopotamia (Iraq), the land of the two rivers, has been  transformed over the last six thousand years by the changing  relationships between rivers, land and sea. Although the pattern has not  yet been reconstructed in detail, satellite imagery can be used to  outline the major processes of change, and to visualise what an  extraordinary landscape this was at the time of the first cities.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/project/introduction.php"><img alt="Why an electronic atlas of archaeology?" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/gulf-view-small.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/project/introduction.php"><cite>Why an electronic atlas of archaeology?<cite></cite></cite></a> (2004)       <br />When astronauts first took photographs of Earth from space, it  transformed traditional images of the planet. Here, for the first time,  were photographs of the world as it actually is. Systematic use of this  information was at first confined to military objectives, but nowadays  these images are familiar, as the backdrop to news items and weather  forecasts. Moreover, they are now available as continuous cover, and can  themselves be used as maps. <span class="logo">ArchAtlas</span> began  in Oxford in 2000, as a means of making available the kinds of images  and interpretations which are more easily disseminated through a website  than by conventional paper publication.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Trade/Trade.php"><img alt="Trade Routes: Growth of Global Trade" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/traderoutes.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/Trade/Trade.php"><cite>Trade Routes: the Growth of Global Trade<cite></cite></cite></a> (2004)       <br />One of the most evident features of the human past is the  growing scale of connections between areas, shown for instance by the  movement of materials (such as the <a href="http://www.archatlas.org/ObsidianRoutes/ObsidianRoutes.php">Obsidian Trade</a>).  Although the current phase of "globalisation" is unique in its range  and impact, it was preceded by many earlier episodes of expansion and  collapse. These maps reconstruct how such networks develop, and show how  they follow a logic reflecting both their own geometry and that of the  Earth's surface, and how they sometimes come to a catastrophic stop.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/SitesFromSatellites/SatSitesList.php"><img alt="Sites from Satellites" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/sitesfromsatellites.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/SitesFromSatellites/SatSitesList.php"><cite>Sites from Satellites<cite></cite></cite></a> (2004)       <br />The resolution of satellite-imagery in the public domain is  constantly improving. Although images with the resolution hitherto  obtainable by aerial photographs are still expensive, imagery with a  resolution of 15m or better is routinely available for most parts of the  world, thanks principally to NASA. For some areas, this is already  better than most maps. It is especially useful in areas with strong  vegetational contrasts depending on water-sources. Selected key sites  are presented here, as they can be seen from space.       </span></td>      </tr><tr>   <td valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/SouthAmerica/SouthAmerica.php"><img alt="Andean Civilizations: Peru, South America" border="0" src="http://www.archatlas.org/web/page-logos/andeanciv.jpg" width="150" /></a></span></td>   <td class="small" valign="top"><span style="font-size: x-small;">   Andrew Sherratt and Francesco Menotti       <br /><a href="http://www.archatlas.org/SouthAmerica/SouthAmerica.php"><cite>Andean Civilizations: Peru, South America (from Space)<cite></cite></cite></a> (2004)       <br />Few areas of the world include such spectacular environmental  contrasts as the Andean coast of South America, with its coastal deserts  and riverine oases, mountains and inter-montane valleys, and tropical  rainforest interior. This complexity underlay the formation of the New  World's indigenous civilisations, from the first temple-builders to the  Inka. These developments are usefully seen by satellite, which reveals  for instance the astonishing phenomenon of the Nazca lines – "seen" by  shamans in spirit-flight, long before the first satellite was launched.       </span></td></tr></tbody></table></blockquote><blockquote><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9198104256890785540/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/02/open-access-journal-archatlas-journal.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9198104256890785540"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9198104256890785540"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/02/open-access-journal-archatlas-journal.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: ArchAtlas Journal"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
