<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7335786283057649761</id>
   <published>2012-02-21T19:56:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-04-05T16:24:27.217-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Cairo Genizah Collection of the Bodleian libraries</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://genizah.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/home">Genizah:<span class="lang-en" lang="en"> Cairo Genizah Collection of the Bodleian libraries</span></a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div class="about"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The collection of Cairo Genizah fragments held at the  Bodleian Libraries is one of  major collections of its kind. Acquired  over the years since 1890 it consists of about 4,000 fragments. Skilful  selection ensured that the Bodleian Genizah holdings became one of the  most important collections worldwide, featuring Bible, Early Rabbinic  literature (Midrash, Mishnah and Talmud), numerous liturgical fragments  (Piyyutim and Selichot), many legal documents and letters, both personal  and commercial. Its significance lies particularly in the remarkable  size of many of the documents. The 4000 fragments comprise about 25,000  pages, amounting to over six pages per fragment, an average unparalleled  elsewhere. Some items consist of whole quires, thus deserving the  designation manuscripts rather than fragments. Talmud fragments of ten  pages or more are no exception in this collection: Tractate Berakhot is  represented with a manuscript of 32 pages (Ms. Heb. c. 17/32); of  tractate Sukkah 72 pages (Ms. Heb. e 51) are preserved  and for tractate  Sotah we have 160 pages (Ms. Heb. d. 20/2) at our disposal. An  exceptionally exciting example are the twenty pages of Maimonides’s  draft manuscript of his Mishneh Torah with corrections in 4 consecutive  stages in his own hand (Ms. Heb. d 32, fols.47a-56b).</span></div><div class="about"><br /></div><div class="about"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The online catalogue is based upon  the printed catalogue of the Hebrew manuscripts in the Bodleian Library  (second volume) by Adolf Neubauer and Arthur Ernst Cowley (1906) and the  typewritten catalogue of additional Genizah fragments by Arthur Ernst  Cowley (ca 1929).&nbsp;</span></div><div class="about"><br /></div><div class="about"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The classification of the fragments  by subject in the printed catalogue in line with the first volume of  Neubauer’s catalogue of Hebrew manuscripts at the Bodleian library is -  as mentioned in the introduction by Arthur Cowley - problematic.  Fragments from the  Cairo Genizah were collected by the Bodleian Library  in successive acquisitions, which after arrival were bound up in  volumes. As a consequence volumes often, despite a careful and focussed  acquisition policy, contain under one heading fragments on different  subjects. In the online catalogue all fragments of a volume can be  searched by subject. The printed catalogue includes 166 volumes, containing in all about  2,675 fragments. The typewritten catalogue consists of 58 volumes with  1094 fragments. It is to be noticed, however,  that the total number of  3769 fragments concerns those of which the Cairo Genizah provenance  explicitly is stated.  The digital access to the Bodleian Genizah  collection will facilitate the identification of a considerable number  of  fragments, whose provenance were hitherto unknown, but which  probably also found their way from Cairo to Oxford.  </span></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq">   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://genizah.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/home">Catalogue Home</a> |     <a href="http://genizah.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/browse">Browse</a> |     <a href="http://genizah.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/advanced">Search</a> |     <a href="http://genizah.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/about">About</a> |     <a href="http://genizah.bodleian.ox.ac.uk/help">Help</a></span>  </blockquote><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: small;">And see also <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/open-access-cairo-genizah-manuscripts.html">The Friedberg Genizah  Project (FGP)</a></span> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7335786283057649761/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/02/genizah-cairo-genizah-collection-of.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7335786283057649761"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7335786283057649761"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/02/genizah-cairo-genizah-collection-of.html"
         title="Cairo Genizah Collection of the Bodleian libraries"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
