<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-733108973032229477</id>
   <published>2011-07-29T07:20:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-02-02T11:46:39.387-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Publications:  Publications of the American School of Classical Studies at Athens</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[Many of the publications of the <a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php">American School of Classical Studies at Athens</a> are available online in open access formats.<br /><div style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Publications" border="0" src="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/images/uploads/pubheader.jpg" style="margin-right: -2px;" /></div><br /><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;">[Updated 29 September 2008 with the addition of links to digital versions of three more Gennadeion Monographs, the products of the ASCSA Digital Library project funded by the Operational Program "Information Society" of the 3rd Community Support Framework , and the series Corinth announced today by JSTOR]<br />[Updated 25 June 2009 with the addition of <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/06/open-access-bulletin-of-school-of.html">Bulletins of the School of Classical Studies at Athens</a>]<br /></span><span style="font-size: xx-small;">[</span><span style="font-size: xx-small;"> Updated 12 October, 2009: </span><span style="font-size: xx-small;">This posting originated on the<a href="http://ancientworldbloggers.blogspot.com/2008/05/awol-ancient-world-online-5.html"> Ancient World Bloggers Group (AWBG)</a>, but will be updated at this location from now on.  Updated 12 October, 2009 with the addition of the Histories of the American School of Classical Studies; updated 12 February, 2010, with the addition of <a href="http://ascsa.net/">Digital Library</a></span><span style="font-size: xx-small;">]<br />[Updated 20 June, 2010 with this link to<a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/06/open-access-enhancements-of-athenian.html"><span style="font-weight: bold;"> </span>Open  Access enhancements of Athenian Agora Publications]</a></span><br /><span style="font-size: 78%;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">[Updated 29 July 2011 with the inclusion of the&nbsp; <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/01/schliemann-diaries-online-at-ascsa.html">Schliemann Diaries</a> and other resources of&nbsp; ASCSA Archival collections]</span></span><br /><span style="font-size: 78%;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">[Updates 2 August 2011 with </span></span><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/08/open-access-content-and-enhancements-to.html">Open Access Content and Enhancements to Hesperi</a>a]</span><br /><span style="font-size: 78%;"><span style="font-size: xx-small;"> </span></span><br /><h3 class="post-title entry-title">   </h3><div class="post-header"></div><b><span style="font-size: 78%;"><br /></span></b><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><b><span style="font-size: 100%;">Histories of the American School of Classical Studies</span></b></div><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/archives/history-of-the-american-school-1882-1942-content-list">A History of the American School of Classical Studies at Athens, 1882-1942; an intercollegiate project</a>.<br />Author:<a href="http://www.worldcat.org/search?q=au%3ALouis+E+Lord&amp;qt=hot_author" title="Search for more by this author">Louis E Lord</a><br />Publisher: Cambridge: Pub. for the American School of Classical Studies at Athens [by] Harvard Univ. Press, 1947.<br />ISBN: 9780876619032 <br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/archives/history-of-the-american-school-1939-1980-content-list">A History of the American School of Classical Studies, 1939-1980</a><br />Author:  <a href="http://www.worldcat.org/search?q=au%3A%22Meritt%2C+Lucy+Shoe%2C%22&amp;qt=hot_author">Lucy Shoe Meritt</a><br />Publisher: Princeton, N.J. : American School of Classical Studies at Athens, 1984.<br />ISBN: 9780876619421<br /><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><b>ákou</b>e</div><br />The Newsletter of the School, ákoue, is published by the ASCSA Development Office and sent free of charge to staff, alumni and other friends of the School approximately twice a year. <a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/akoue-Online-Access">No. 47 (2003)and the following issues</a> are available.<br /><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><b>Annual Reports</b></div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: small;"><a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=jX8RAAAAYAAJ&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=%22Annual+Report+-+American+School+of+Classical+Studies+At+Athens%22&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=dHh7MeEjUi&amp;sig=W1_fO847nIWH6pXFHzJ7_Sb-rcI&amp;hl=en&amp;ei=pdZ4Td3dJ9Sz0QGt4ZXXAw&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=book_result&amp;ct=result&amp;resnum=1&amp;ved=0CBUQ6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false">Annual Report - American School of Classical Studies at Athens, Volumes 4-7</a></span><br /><span style="font-size: small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/news/ascsa-annual-report-now-available"><span style="font-size: small;">Annual Report - American School of Classical Studies at Athens,</span> 2006-2007 <span style="font-size: small;">through</span> 2007-2008</a> </span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/anrep2008-10PRINT.pdf">Annual Reports - American School of Classical Studies at Athens, 2008–2009 through 2009–2010</a></span></div><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/news/annual-reports-now-online">Annual Reports - American School of Classical Studies at Athens, 2010-2011 through 2011-2012 </a><br /><br /><br /><center><b>Agora Picture Books</b></center><br /><br />The primary purpose of the Agora Picture Book series is to enliven the experience of a visitor to the Athenian Agora, excavated by the American School since 1931. While drawing on the object and monuments that can be viewed on a visit to the site, these well-illustrated guides attempt to add some human color to the dry material remains. A number of the concise guides have become popular supplementary texts for undergraduate and graduate classes in classical civilization. Since 1998 the Picture Books have been published in color.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616017" title="Pots and Pans of Classical Athens">1: Pots and Pans of Classical Athens - by Brian A. Sparkes and Lucy Talcott</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616345" title="The Stoa of Attalos II in Athens">2: The Stoa of Attalos II in Athens - by Homer A. Thompson</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616031" title="Miniature Sculpture from the Athenian Agora">3: Miniature Sculpture from the Athenian Agora - by Dorothy B. Thompson</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616420" title="The Athenian Citizen">4: The Athenian Citizen: Democracy in the Athenian Agora - by Mabel Lang</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616055" title="Ancient Portraits from the Athenian Agora">5: Ancient Portraits from the Athenian Agora - by Evelyn B. Harrison</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616192" title="Amphoras and the Ancient Wine Trade">6: Amphoras and the Ancient Wine Trade - by Virginia R. Grace</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616079" title="The Middle Ages in the Athenian Agora">7: The Middle Ages in the Athenian Agora - by Alison Frantz</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616086" title="Garden Lore of Ancient Athens">8: Garden Lore of Ancient Athens - by Dorothy B. Thompson and Ralph E. Griswold</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616093" title="Lamps from the Athenian Agora">9: Lamps from the Athenian Agora - by Judith Perlzweig</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616109" title="Inscriptions from the Athenian Agora">10: Inscriptions from the Athenian Agora - by Benjamin D. Meritt</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616116" title="Waterworks in the Athenian Agora">11: Waterworks in the Athenian Agora - by Mabel Lang</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616352" title="An Ancient Shopping Center">12: An Ancient Shopping Center: The Athenian Agora - by Dorothy B. Thompson</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616130" title="Early Burials from the Agora Cemeteries">13: Early Burials from the Agora Cemeteries - by Sara A. Immerwahr</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616338" title="Graffiti in the Athenian Agora">14: Graffiti in the Athenian Agora - by Mabel Lang</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616154" title="Greek and Roman Coins in the Athenian Agora">15: Greek and Roman Coins in the Athenian Agora - by Fred S. Kleiner</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616437" title="The Athenian Agora">16: The Athenian Agora: A Short Guide to the Excavations - by John McK. Camp II</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9789607067012" title="The Athenian Agora">16: The Athenian Agora: A Short Guide to the Excavations (Modern Greek) - by John McK. Camp II</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616178" title="Socrates in the Agora">17: Socrates in the Agora - by Mabel Lang</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616185" title="Mediaeval and Modern Coins in the Athenain Agora">18: Mediaeval and Modern Coins in the Athenain Agora - by Fred S. Kleiner</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616239" title="Gods and Heroes in the Athenian Agora">19: Gods and Heroes in the Athenian Agora - by John McK. Camp II</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616246" title="Bronzeworkers in the Athenian Agora">20: Bronzeworkers in the Athenian Agora - by Carol C. Mattusch</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616260" title="Ancient Athenian Building Methods">21: Ancient Athenian Building Methods - by John McK. Camp II and William B. Dinsmoor Jr.</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616277" title="Birds of the Athenian Agora">22: Birds of the Athenian Agora - by Robert D. Lamberton and Susan I. Rotroff</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616376" title="Life, Death, and Litigation in the Athenian Agora">23: Life, Death, and Litigation in the Athenian Agora - by Mabel Lang</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616390" title="Horses and Horsemanship in the Athenian Agora">24: Horses and Horsemanship in the Athenian Agora - by John McK. Camp II</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616413" title="The Games at Athens">25: The Games at Athens - by Jenifer Neils and Stephen V. Tracy</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616444" title="Women in the Athenian Agora">26: Women in the Athenian Agora - by Susan I. Rotroff and Robert D. Lamberton</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616451" title="Marbleworkers in the Athenian Agora">27: Marbleworkers in the Athenian Agora - by Carol L. Lawton</a><br /><br /><br /><br /><center><b>ASCSA Digital Library</b><br /></center><br /><a href="http://www3.ascsa.edu.gr/media/corinth/corinth.html"><br /></a><a href="http://ascsa.net/">Digital Library</a><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/"></a></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;"><a href="http://ascsa.net/">The digital library [at http://ascsa.net] </a>currently provides access to the archaeological data from the Athenian Agora and Corinth together with a selection of photographs from the Alison Frantz Collection. You can use the index of categories to the left to browse this data, or search using the toolbar above. Material which has been published is made completely available to the public. Material which is unpublished is only available to researchers who have already obtained the necessary permission to study the material in person.</span></blockquote><br /><a href="http://www3.ascsa.edu.gr/media/corinth/corinth.html">Chronicle of Corinth Excavations</a><br />Camp, John McK., II; Mauzy, Craig (eds.). <a href="http://www3.ascsa.edu.gr/media/agora/agora.html">Agora Excavations</a><br />Davis, Jack L.; Vogeikoff, Natalia (eds.). <a href="http://www3.ascsa.edu.gr/Portals/0/final%20eng.pdf">The American School of Classical Studies at Athens: Links to the Past, Looking to the Future</a><br />Georgopoulou, Maria (ed.). <a href="http://www3.ascsa.edu.gr/media/gennadius/gennadius.html">Gennadius: The Vision and the Collection</a><br />Vogeikoff-Brogan, Natalia; Vassilis Spanos (eds.). <a href="http://www3.ascsa.edu.gr/media/thompson/thompson.html">Greece in the '20s &amp; '30s: Through the Lense of Dorothy Burr Thompson</a><br /><br /><br /><center><b>Athenian Agora Guide Books</b></center><br /><br />The Athenian Agora: A Short Guide in Color<br />By John McK.Camp II<br />This colorful overview is intended primarily for visitors to the site, but also provides a useful introduction to the visible remains. After a brief history of the Agora, the principal monuments are described, and then the reader is taken on a counterclockwise tour around the site. The author is the current Director of Excavations at the Athenian Agora, and this guide therefore presents the most up-to-date information available. 48pp (Excavations of the Athenian Agora, Picture Book 16, revised 2003) ISBN: 0-87661-643-0<br /><br /><a href="http://www.agathe.gr/Texts/pdfs/PB16_English.pdf">Download English Version PDF (5.8 MB)</a><br /><br /><a href="http://www.agathe.gr/Texts/pdfs/PB16_Greek.pdf">Download Greek Version PDF (4.4 MB)</a><br /><br /><br /><center><b>The Athenian Agora: A Guide to the Excavation and Museum</b></center><br />This new edition of the Agora guide takes account of the important recent excavations which have taken place since 1976, the year of publication of the third edition. In addition, this version has been directed specifically toward those actually visiting the site: it is somewhat more compact than its predecessor and the illustrations have been chosen to help the visitor recreate the site in his mind's eye. (American School of Classical Studies at Athens, 1990) ISBN: 960-7067-00-2<br /><br /><a href="http://www.agathe.gr/cgi-bin/text?lookup=siteguide;id=contents">View Online Version</a><br /><br /><br /><center><b>Corinth Notes</b></center><br />These brief guides present concise descriptions of interesting discoveries at the site of Corinth, excavated by the American School since 1896. The existing numbers in the series focus on the Sanctuary of Demeter and Kore, the center of a healing cult situated on the lower slopes of the Acrocorinth mountain, and on the Asklepieion.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616703" title="Cure and Cult in Ancient Corinth">1: Cure and Cult in Ancient Corinth - by Mabel Lang</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616710" title="Demeter and Persephone in Ancient Corinth">2: Demeter and Persephone in Ancient Corinth - by Ronald S. Stroud</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876616710" title="Demeter and Persephone in Ancient Corinth"><br /></a><br /><br /><center><b>Gennadeion Monographs</b></center><br />The Gennadius Library (known as “the Gennadeion") contains a large collection of volumes on various aspects of post-classical Greek culture and history. The Library’s archives are the repository of many more important photographs, manuscripts, documents, and special collections. The Gennadeion Monographs series exists to publish studies related to the collections of the library.<br /><br /><br />Four volumes of this series are available online:<br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876614013"><br />The Venetians in Athens, 1687-1688, from the Istoria of Cristoforo Ivanovich</a> - edited by James Morton Paton<br /><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876614020">Schliemann's First Visit to America</a> - edited by Shirley H. Weber<br /><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876614037">Chapters on Mediaeval and Renaissance Visitors to Greek Lands</a> - by James Morton Paton<br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876614051" title="The Campaign of the Falieri and Piraeus in the Year 1827">The Campaign of the Falieri and Piraeus in the Year 1827 - edited by C. W. J. Eliot</a><br /><br /><br /><center><b>Isthmia (ISSN 0362-8108)</b></center><br />Situated on the most direct route from the Peloponnese to central Greece and Attica, as well as from Corinth to the Saronic Gulf, the panhellenic sanctuary at Isthmia preserves evidence of cult practices from at least the 7th century B.C. A Doric Temple of Poseidon was built ca. 465 B.C. and then rebuilt after a fire around 75 years later. The site was the center of a cult to the local boy-hero Palaimon in the Roman period and continued to function as a sanctuary into at least the 3rd century A.D. Its abandoned buildings were used as a quarry to build a set of Late Roman fortifications to defend the Isthmus. This series publishes excavations by both the University of Chicago and Ohio State University.<br /><br />Two volumes of this series are available online:<br /><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876619346" title="Sculpture I">IV: Sculpture I: 1952-1967 - by Mary C. Sturgeon</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876619377" title="The Metal Objects, 1952-1989">VII: The Metal Objects, 1952-1989 - by Isabelle K. Raubitschek</a><br /><br /><br /><center><b>Keos</b></center><br />Excavations on the Cycladic island of Keos revealed a number of prehistoric sites, including the site of Ayia Irini on a peninsula at the northwest end. This site was occupied from Neolithic to Roman times, flourishing particularly in the Bronze Age when it was the location of a sanctuary. A large number of near lifesize figures were discovered there during excavations in the 1960s by the University of Cincinnati. This series is no longer published by ASCSA. Other volumes have been published by Philipp von Zabern Verlag.<br /><br /><br />One volume of this series is available online:<br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876617014" title="Kephala">I: Kephala: A Late Neolithic Settlement and Cemetery - by John E. Coleman</a><br /><br /><br /><center><b>Lerna</b></center><br />Lerna, on the shore of the Gulf of Argos, is one of the most important prehistoric sites in Greece, having been occupied with few interruptions over a period of some 5,000 years, from the 6th to the 1st millennium B.C. A simple Neolithic village became a more complex settlement in the Early Helladic period when the massive House of the Tiles was built. Destroyed by fire at the end of the period, it was covered by a tumulus in the Middle Helladic period. This series presents the results of excavations by John L. Caskey from 1952 to 1958.<br /><br />All  volumes of this series are available online.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876613016">I: The Fauna - by Nils-Gustaf Gejvall</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876613023" title="The People">II: The People - by J. Lawrence Angel</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876613030" title="The Pottery of Lerna IV">III: The Pottery of Lerna IV - by Jeremy B. Rutter</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876613047" title="The Architecture, Stratification, and Pottery of Lerna III">IV: The Architecture, Stratification, and Pottery of Lerna III - by Martha H. Wiencke</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876613054" title="The Neolithic Pottery from Lerna">V: The Neolithic Pottery from Lerna - by K. D. Vitelli</a><br /><br /><br /><center><b>Propylaia</b></center><br />These volumes present the definitive account of one of the masterpieces of Greek architecture, the grand entrance to the Athenian Akropolis designed in the 5th century B.C. by the architect Mnesikles. Written by a father and son team over a period of 80 years, the two books present a complete overview of the development of one of the monuments of western civilization. No further volumes are planned.<br /><br />One volume of this series is available online:<br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876619414" title="The Propylaia to the Athenian Akropolis II: The Classical Building">II: The Propylaia to the Athenian Akropolis II: The Classical Building - by William B. Dinsmoor and William B. Dinsmoor Jr., edited by Anastasia Norre Dinsmoor</a><br /><br /><br /><center><b>The Temple of Apollo Bassitas</b></center><br />High in the mountains of Arcadia, the Temple of Apollo Epikourios at Bassae was built and rebuilt a number of times during the Archaic and Classical periods. According to the Roman traveler Pausanias, the architect was Iktinos, who was also responsible for building the Parthenon in Athens. Although the accuracy of this statement is uncertain, the temple remains one of the most spectacular and well preserved in Greece. This four-volume series, including large-scale plans, is based on a detailed study by University of Minnesota researchers. The series is complete.<br /><br />All but the folio volume of plans are available online:<br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876619469" title="The Temple of Apollo Bassitas I: The Architecture">I: The Temple of Apollo Bassitas I: The Architecture - by Frederick A. Cooper</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876619476" title="The Temple of Apollo Bassitas II: The Sculpture">II: The Temple of Apollo Bassitas II: The Sculpture - by Brian C. Madigan</a><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/book/?i=9780876619483" title="The Temple of Apollo Bassitas III: The Architecture: Illustrations">III: The Temple of Apollo Bassitas III: The Architecture: Illustrations - by Frederick A. Cooper</a><br /><br />Some other publications of the ASCSA have been made available elsewhere:<br /><br />Weber, Shirley Howard, 1883- / [1953] <a href="http://name.umdl.umich.edu/AFG5902.0001.001">Voyages and travels in Greece, the Near East, and adjacent regions, made previous to the year 1801; being a part of a larger catalogue of works on geography, cartography, voyages and travels, in the Gennadius Library in Athens</a>, in the <a href="http://quod.lib.umich.edu/b/bosnia/">Travels in Southeastern Europe</a> collection at the University of Michigan Library.<br /><br /><a href="http://quod.lib.umich.edu/cgi/t/text/text-idx?c=moa;idno=ACD4670">Papers of the American School of Classical Studies at Athens.</a><br />Archaeological Institute of America., American School of Classical Studies at Athens. Boston: Cupples, Upham and co. [etc.], 1885-97, at the <a href="http://quod.lib.umich.edu/m/moa/">Making of America (MOA)</a> collection at the University of Michigan Library.<br /><ul><li><a href="http://www.archive.org/details/bulletinschoolc02amergoog">Bulletin of the School of Classical Studies at Athens I (1883)</a> [REPORT OF WILLIAM W. GOODWIN, PROFESSOR IN HARVARD COLLEGE, Director of the School in 1882-1883].</li><li><a href="http://www.archive.org/details/bulletinschoolc01amergoog">Bulletin of the School of Classical Studies at Athens II (1885)</a> [MEMOIR OF LEWIS R. PACKARD, PROFESSOR IN YALE COLLEGE, Director of the School in 1883-1884. With the Resolutions of the Committee, and a Report on the School for 1883-1884].</li><li><a href="http://www.archive.org/details/bulletinschoolc03amergoog">Bulletin of the School of Classical Studies at Athens IV (1895)</a> [REPORT OF JOHN WILLIAMS WHITE. Ph.D., Professor in Harvard University, Professor of the Greek Language and Literature at the School in 1893-94.].</li><li><a href="http://www.archive.org/details/bulletinschoolc00amergoog">Bulletin of the School of Classical Studies at Athens V (1902)</a> [THE FIRST TWENTY YEARS OF THE AMERICAN SCHOOL OP CLASSICAL STUDIES AT ATHENS, THOMAS D. SEYMOUR, LL.D.].</li></ul>The journal <a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/Hesperia/">Hesperia</a>, the series <a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/browse-by-series/hesperia-supplements">Hesperia Supplements</a> and the series <a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/browse-by-series/the-athenian-agora">Athenian Agora</a> and <a href="http://www.jstor.org/action/showPublication?journalCode=coriresuexca">Corinth </a>are available to institutional or individual licensees from JSTOR.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/News/newsDetails/hesperia-provides-open-access-to-more-than-1500-articles">Hesperia Open Access</a><br /><br /><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/open-access">Open Access Content from ASCSA Publications</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">On occasion, the ASCSA Publications Office will post an article from <i>Hesperia</i>, a book chapter, or other material here for visitors to freely download and use:</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Celebrating 75 Years of <i>Hesperia</i>,” <i>Hesperia</i> 76 (2007), pp. 1-20, by Tracey Cullen.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/Celebrating75YearsOfHesperiaHesp76_1_1-20.pdf">Download the PDF</a> (2 MB)</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">“The Birth of <i>Hesperia</i>: A View from the Archives,” <i>Hesperia</i> 76 (2007), pp. 21-35, by Jack L. Davis.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/TheBirthOfHesperiaHesp76_1_21-35.pdf">Download the PDF</a> (1 MB)</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Byzantium and the Avant-Garde: Excavations at Corinth, 1920s-1930s,” <i>Hesperia</i> 76 (2007), pp. 391-442, by Kostis Kourelis.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/ByzantiumAndTheAvantGardeHesp76_2_391-442.pdf">Download the PDF</a> (1 MB)</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">“An Archer from the Palace of Nestor: A New Wall-Painting Fragment in the Chora Museum,” <i>Hesperia</i> 77 (2008), pp. 363-397, by Hariclia Brecoulaki, Jack L. Davis, Caroline Zaitoun, and Sharon R. Stocker.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/AnArcherFromThePalaceOfNestorHesp77_2_363-397.pdf">Download the PDF</a> (6 MB)</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Supplementary Images of the Archer Fragment: Addendum to ‘An Archer from the Palace of Nestor’,” <i>Hesperia</i> 77 (2008), by Hariclia Brecoulaki et al.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/SupplementaryImagesOfTheArcherFragmentHesp77_2.pdf">Download the PDF</a> (1 MB)</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Hunting the <i>Eschata</i>: An Imagined Persian Empire on the Lekythos of Xenophantos,” <i>Hesperia</i> 78 (2009), pp. 455-480, by Hallie M. Franks.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/HuntingtheEschataHesp78_4_455-480.pdf">Download the PDF</a> (2 MB)</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Stone Age Seafaring in the Mediterranean: Evidence from the Plakias  Region for Lower Palaeolithic and Mesolithic Habitation of Crete,” <i>Hesperia</i> 79 (2010), pp. 145-190, by Thomas F. Strasser, Eleni Panagopoulou,  Curtis N. Runnels, Priscilla M. Murray, Nicholas Thompson, Panayiotis  Karkanas, Floyd W. McCoy, and Karl W. Wegmann.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/StoneAgeSeafaringintheMedHesp79_2_145-190.pdf">Download the PDF</a> (5 MB)</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Catalogue of Late Helladic IIIA2 Pottery from Tsoungiza”, an  appendix to “A Deposit of Late Helladic IIIA2 Pottery from Tsoungiza,” <i>Hesperia</i> 80.2 (2011), pp. 171-228, by Patrick M. Thomas.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/TsoungizaLHIIIA2PotteryCatalogue.pdf">Download the PDF</a> (266 kb)</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Catalogue of Late Helladic IIIA2 Pottery from Tsoungiza”, an  appendix to “A Deposit of Late Helladic IIIA2 Pottery from Tsoungiza,” <i>Hesperia</i> 80.2 (2011), pp. 171-228, by Patrick M. Thomas.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/pdf/uploads/TsoungizaLHIIIA2PotteryCatalogue.html">Access the Catalogue</a></span></blockquote><br /><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/01/schliemann-diaries-online-at-ascsa.html">Heinrich Schliemann' Diaries</a> are now online in facsimile at ASCSA.&nbsp; So also are lareg numbers of documents and finding aids in the <a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/Archives/">ASCSA Archives</a> in the Gennadius and Blegen Libraries.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/58310456@N04/">ASCSA Athens Photostream on flickr</a> ]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/733108973032229477/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/open-access-publications-publications.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/733108973032229477"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/733108973032229477"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/open-access-publications-publications.html"
         title="Open Access Publications:  Publications of the American School of Classical Studies at Athens"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
