<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2520778259496445472</id>
   <published>2013-11-25T11:12:00.002-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-11-25T11:12:25.555-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New Open Access Journal (and call for papers on Cultural heritage): Middle East - Topics &amp; Arguments</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://meta-journal.net/index">Middle East - Topics &amp; Arguments</a><br />ISSN: 2196-629X<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Middle East – Topics &amp; Arguments is a unique platform for  innovative research on the Middle East combining disciplinary and  interdisciplinary approaches. Articles critically reevaluate established  scholarly traditions and think beyond entrenched disciplinary  boundaries. By bringing together well-known academics and young scholars  with international backgrounds, a broad range of perspectives will  ensure lively debates.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />Middle East – Topics and Arguments  wants to encourage interdisciplinary discussion on two levels: Firstly,  between social sciences and humanities in the field of Middle Eastern  studies, and secondly, between Middle Eastern studies and the systematic  disciplines. We thereby aim at integrating regional academic discourse  into a global setting. We hope to ensure trans-regional comparability,  thus leaving behind the notion of cultural and religious exceptionalism  which has for a long been connected with Middle Eastern studies.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Each  issue of Middle East – Topics &amp; Arguments focuses on one main  topic. This allows for perspectives from different disciplines, such as:</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /><strong>cultural studies</strong><br /><strong>literary studies</strong><br /><strong>linguistics</strong><br /><strong>history</strong><br /><strong>political science</strong><br /><strong>sociology</strong><br /><strong>anthropology</strong><br /><strong>economics</strong><br /><strong>ancient studies</strong></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2><a href="http://meta-journal.net/announcement/view/6"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Call for Papers #3</span></a></h2><div id="content">   <table id="announcementDescription" style="width: 100%px;">	<tbody><tr>		<td><span style="font-size: x-small;">"Cultural heritage" is commonly associated with buildings,  monuments and other historical relics (such as, for example, the  pyramids, the Ishtar Gate or the Nefertiti Bust), as well as with the  work of museums or other public institutions and organizations whose  duty it is to restore, preserve, and present them to the public.<br /><br />In  a wider sense, however, the term covers not only material artifacts but  also the intangible legacy of cultures such as customs, traditions,  religion, literature, sciences and languages. These are passed on from  generation to generation, often without their value as "cultural  heritage" being noticed, and it is only in exceptional situations—for  example, when their continued existence is in danger—that they are  recognized and treated as important elements of a community’s shared  history and that positive steps for their preservation are undertaken.<br /><br />Influenced  by the work of organizations like the UNESCO since the second half of  the 20th century, and the development of concepts like “world heritage”  (i.e. concepts that have no precedent in history), one might be tempted  to regard the preservation of cultural heritage as a modern invention;  but the awareness—inherent in the concept—that for the continuity of a  culture it is necessary to protect at least some of its specific  features, is in fact as old as mankind itself.<br /><br />Although the term  "cultural heritage" as such has a positive connotation, the treatment of  its central elements does not necessarily have to be positive: when  political or social situations change, there might also be a desire to  destroy them in order to eliminate remembrances of particular aspects of  the past.<br /><br />However, even without such radical change, the  perception of what constitutes a culture’s shared heritage, and whether  it is worthy of protection, may vary over the course of time. The  recognition and acceptance of a given thing (an object, a monument or a  custom) as a valuable part of cultural heritage is therefore always  closely connected with the definition of cultural identities as well as  with mechanisms of assessment and selection.<br /><br />Conceived with the  aim to highlight historical depth and to bridge the gap between ancient  and modern Near Eastern studies, the planned volume of META is dedicated  to the long history of "cultural heritage" and its treatment in the  Near and Middle East from the invention of writing (or even before)  until the modern era.<br /><br />Thereby, lines of tradition and continuity  (concerning, for example, languages, onomastics, religion, literature,  art and architecture) will be discussed, as well as breaks with  tradition, deliberate or accidental destruction of historical monuments  (by wars, dam building, illegal excavations, etc.), the rediscovery of  forgotten cultures (following excavations or the decipherment of ancient  texts), the preservation and presentation of cultural residues (in  museums and on archaeological sites), and the integration of previous  accomplishments into contemporary ideologies and political programs  (like Saddam Hussein’s affinity with Nebuchadnezzar II or the Shah of  Persia’s "2500 year celebration of the Persian Empire").<br /><br />Further  topics could address the role of antiques as economic factors (tourism)  and issues of political negotiation (e.g., the granting of excavation  licenses or the request for return of archaeological artifacts), the  problem of dealing in antiques (including the discussion whether it is  legitimate to publish material of unknown provenance), the question of  who owns cultural heritage (e.g., the objects that came from the Near  and Middle East to Europe or North America during the late 19th and  early 20th centuries), and its artistic reception (both in Near Eastern  and Western traditions).<br /><br />In any case, particular attention should  be paid to the concept of "cultural heritage", to the question whether  its reception happens consciously or unconsciously, and to the  relationship between those who left this legacy and its later  recipients.<br /><br />We are happy to accept articles from a broad array of  disciplines which involve the Near and Middle East, including cultural  studies, archeology, history, philology, anthropology, literature  studies, sociology, political science, and economics.<br /><br />With regard  to the interdisciplinary and debate-oriented culture of META,  innovative approaches and controversial hypotheses are particularly  welcome.<br /><br />Prior to developing a complete manuscript authors are  asked to submit an abstract (300 words max.) including a working title,  some key words, and 3-5 relevant bibliographic sources. The editors will  then make a preliminary decision regarding the topic’s relevance to the  journal’s aims and scope and will provide suggestions for developing  the manuscript. Please consult our website for further information about  the journal’s concept, sections, and guidelines for submissions.<br /><br />All  articles that fall into the general framework of the journal but do not  relate to the special topic "cultural heritage" will be taken into  consideration for the "off-topic" section of Middle East – Topics &amp;  Arguments.<br /><br />The deadline for abstract submissions is January 15, 2014.<br />The deadline for article submissions is April 30, 2014.<br /><br />Manuscripts  and manuscript proposals as well as any other editorial correspondence  should be sent to: submissions#3@meta-journal.net.</span></td></tr></tbody></table></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="blockSubtitle">Browse</span></span>	<br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://meta-journal.net/issue/archive">By Issue</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://meta-journal.net/search/authors">By Author</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://meta-journal.net/search/titles">By Title</a></span></li></ul></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2520778259496445472/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/11/new-open-access-journal-and-call-for.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2520778259496445472"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2520778259496445472"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/11/new-open-access-journal-and-call-for.html"
         title="New Open Access Journal (and call for papers on Cultural heritage): Middle East - Topics &amp; Arguments"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
