<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5018526631922895128</id>
   <published>2012-06-05T20:41:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-06-06T15:13:33.395-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Thrace"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Sculpture"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Art"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greece"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Macedonia"/>
   <title type="text">Online Catalogue of the sculptures in the Archaeological Museum of Salonica</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/drupal/?q=en/node/212">Catalogue of the sculptures in the Archaeological Museum of Salonica</a><br />G. Despinis - T. Stefanidou-Tiveriou - E. Voutiras<br /><div class="content"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Archaeological_Museum_of_Thessaloniki">The Archaeological Museum</a> of <a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/places/491741">Salonica</a> holds one of the largest and  most diverse collections of ancient sculpture in Greece. This is caused  by the fact that the holdings of the collection derive from a wide  geographical range. Most of the sculptures emerged in and around the  city of Salonica, but objects found in various sites of the ancient  landscapes of <a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/places/991368">Macedonia</a> and Thracia were also added to the Museum's  inventory. Therefore it is possible to regard the collection as  reasonably representative for the sculpture of the north-Aegaean area up  to the <a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/places/511381">Propontis</a> to some extent. Chronologically the sculptures cover  the complete range of ancient art, from the archaic period (2nd half of  the 6th century BC) all the way up to the late antiquity (4th and 5th  century AD). Therefore, in 1989, three professors of archaeology (<a href="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n86851059">G. Despinis</a>, Th. Stefanodou-Tiveriou and <a href="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n91128017">E. Voutiras</a>) initiated a research  program in order to gather the complete collection of antiquities of the  Archaeological Museum of Salonica, as well as to catalogue and publish  it. Thanks to the active support of Ioulia Vokotopolou, the ephor in  charge, the required permission from the central administrative bureau  for the antiquity service (ΚΑΣ) was soon granted so that it was possible  to tackle the project in 1990. Until 1998, the gathering and studying  of the material was funded by a public research program. Additional  financial assistance was rendered by the Cast Museum of the University  of Salonica. The superintendents as well as the staff of the museum  always helped benevolently. Since 1998, Prof. <a href="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n85040527">B. Schmidt-Dounas</a> has also  been working in the editorial department and the group of contributors  has extended to doctoral candidates within the department of Archaeology  in the University as well as to employees of the Archaeological  Service.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The  main goal of the project is to publish a scientific catalogue with all  sculptures of the Archaeological Museum of Salonica. So far, four  volumes are planned. The first was published in 1997, the second in  2003. The third volume is in preparation.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Meanwhile, the register, which is kept in the Cast Museum of the  University of Salonica along with the photographical archive, contains  about 1500 entries. The objects were newly measured, described and  recorded. The sculptures were photographed from several different  perspectives, whenever possible from all four sides. The information  concerning their origin was systematically rechecked to the extent  available.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Besides preparing the catalogue, it seemed useful to use a database,  in order to make it easier to use the archive and to enable the  connection with similar projects. This task was tackled in cooperation  with the CoDArchLab. Consequently, the Arachne website made the part of  the archive that was already published electronically available to an  even wider public.</span><br /><br /><div class="einsprung"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/arachne/index.php?view%5Blayout%5D=sammlungen_item&amp;view%5Bcaller%5D%5Bproject%5D=212&amp;search%5Bconstraints%5D%5Bsammlungen%5D%5BsearchSeriennummer%5D=1005674&amp;view%5Bactive_tab%5D=KontextbrowserDiv">to collection</a></span></div><div class="einsprung"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/arachne/index.php?view%5Blayout%5D=search_result_category&amp;view%5Bcaller%5D%5Bproject%5D=212&amp;view%5Bpage%5D=0&amp;view%5Bcategory%5D=objekt&amp;search%5Bmode%5D=detail&amp;search%5Bconstraints%5D%5Bobjekt%5D%5BPS_SammlungenID%5D=%201005674">to objects</a></span></div></blockquote></div><div class="left"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><a href="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/drupal/"><img alt="Arachne" src="http://arachne.uni-koeln.de/template/images/logo.gif" /></a></div></blockquote></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5018526631922895128/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/06/online-catalogue-of-sculptures-in.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5018526631922895128"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5018526631922895128"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/06/online-catalogue-of-sculptures-in.html"
         title="Online Catalogue of the sculptures in the Archaeological Museum of Salonica"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
