<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1642512453363456260</id>
   <published>2011-11-30T06:23:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2011-11-30T06:29:04.884-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">The Friedberg Genizah Project Updates</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left;">Genazim</div><div style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/open-access-cairo-genizah-manuscripts.html">The Friedberg Genizah Project</a></div><div style="text-align: left;">Announcement 10</div><div style="text-align: left;">November 2011</div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Genazim - the Computerization Unit of the Friedberg Genizah Project – announces the launching of version 8.2 of its website <a href="http://www.genizah.org/">www.genizah.org</a> .</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Following are some of the additional data and improvments  that have been integrated into the website, since the previous  announcement of version 8 in July 2011.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>A – Images</b></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>Cambridge</u><b>: S</b>ince the last announcement  about 4 months ago, an additional set of 40,214 images from the CUL  Genizah Collection has been integrated in the website, mostly from the  collections TS AR, AS, NS, and Or. 2118, bringing the total number of  images of Genizah fragments from Cambridge to almost 258,000 images.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>British Library</u>: An additional set of 316 images has been integrated in the website.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>JTS (Jewish Theological Seminary – New York)</u>: A  set of 1065 images has been received and integrated, most of them new  images, others being improved versions of existing images.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The total number of images in the website is currently about 320,000 images.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>B – Software</b></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">1. <u>Joins:</u> Information (and statistics) about joins  occur now in many pages of the website, from which it was missing,  including in the "results" pages of of an advanced search.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2. <u>Images</u>: Two important new functions are now  available: a|) after processing an image in ViewOne using the "sun" icon  to adjust for optimal contrast, brightness and luminance, the image  with the new settings can be saved in the user's workspace for future  viewing, b) after rotating a given image in the QuickView function  either for straightening it or for allowing easy reading of oblique  lines, the image can be send in its new position to ViewOne to be viewed  and processed there using the rich repertoire available in ViewOne for  such processing; it will be then saved also in the personal workspace  for later viewing.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">3. <u>Scanned catalogs:</u> New scanned catalog-entries from the Zulay and Widder catalogs about Budapest fragments have been integrated.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>4. Institutional registration</u>: A new and  straightforward registration system has been implemented for libraries,  that enables free and immediate access to the Genizah website for  libraries' visitors from up to 20 pcs in that library.&nbsp;</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">5. <u>Various improvements</u>: a) <i>frames</i>: the  "Frames" structure through which users can add restrictions to the  search has been greatly improved and better adapted to the nature of the  Domains and the specific structure of the Titles involved; also a  better separation between the body of a work and its appended  information (preface, appendices, table of contents, etc) has been  implemented, b) <i>statistics</i>: the statistical tables that appear in  each function section and give a detailed overview of the available  information in that section have been greatly enlarged and improved, c) <i>workspace</i>: various icons for specific types of information are now available in the workspace, d) <i>forum</i>: an improved filtering operation is now available for all the notes in the forum, e) <i>restrictions</i>: the time allocated for idle operation has been increased from 40 to 60 minutes.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>Remarks</u>:</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">1) We remind our readers that accredited users can add  new information (including "joins") on Genizah fragments to the website  (which will appear there with their name appended to it), through the  FOLUS system. We urge such users to use this opportunity to enrich the  website with new data, to the benefit of the entire Genizah-studies  community. Other users who would like to contribute in such a way are  kindly asked to send us in email through the "contact us" icon.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2) The users are also encouraged to use the public forum  to present new insights, submit queries, open discussions, etc; on  Genizah issues; take a look at it now!</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">3) We remind our users that the Nahum website is  available and can be reached through the Genizah website, as well as  directly through http://www.jewishmanuscripts.org/ . It contains almost  100,000 high-quality digital images of Yemenite manuscripts from the  Nachum collection, as well as catalog and other data, that can searched  and processed using essentially the same tools as available in the  |Genizah website.</span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">With a cordial <i>Shalom</i></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Genazim.</span></div><div dir="ltr"></div><div dir="ltr"></div></blockquote><div dir="ltr"><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">&nbsp; </span><br /><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>גנזים</b></span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>פרויקט פרידברג לחקר הגניזה</b></span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>הודעה 10</b></span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>נובמבר 2011</b></span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">גנזים – יחידת המחשוב של פרויקט פרידברג לחקר הגניזה – מודיעה על השקת גירסה 8.2 של אתר הגניזה:&nbsp;<a href="http://www.genizah.org/"><span dir="ltr">www.genizah.org</span>.</a></span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">להלן תיאור של השיפורים והנתונים שנוספו באתר מאז ההודעה הקודמת על גירסה 8 ביולי 2011.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>א. תמונות</b></span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>קיימברידג':</u> מאז הודעתנו הקודמת לפני כארבעה חודשים, נוספו באתר עוד 40,214 תמונות מאוסף הגניזה של <span dir="ltr">CUL</span>, ברובן מן האוספים <span dir="ltr">TS</span>: <span dir="ltr">AR</span>, <span dir="ltr">AS</span>, <span dir="ltr">NS</span>&nbsp;&nbsp; ו-<span dir="ltr">Oriental 2118</span>, ובזה מגיע המספר הכללי של התמונות של קטעי גניזה מקיימברידג' לכ-258,000.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>הספריה הבריטית:</u> נוספו 316 תמונות לאתר.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><u><span dir="ltr">JTS (Jewish Theological Seminary – New York)</span></u><u>:</u> נתקבלו והוכנסו לאתר 1065 תמונות, רובן תמונות חדשות, ואחרות שהן גירסאות משופרות של תמונות קיימות.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">המספר הכולל של תמונות באתר הוא כיום כ-320,000.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>ב. תוכנה</b></span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">1. <u>צירופים:</u> בדפים רבים באתר מופיע בגרסה זו מידע (או סטטיסטיקה) על צירופים, שהיה חסר עד כה, כולל בדפי "תוצאות" של חיפוש מתקדם.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">2. <u>תמונות:</u> קיימות שתי פונקציות חשובות חדשות: א) לאחר עיבוד תמונה ב-<span dir="ltr">ViewOne</span> ע"י שימוש באייקון ה"שמש" כדי להגיע לניגוד, בהירות ואור אופיטמליים, אפשר  לשמור את התמונה עם הגדרות התצוגה שלה בשולחן העבודה של המשתמש, לצפייה  עתידית. ב) לאחר סיבוב תמונה נתונה על ידי פונקציית <span dir="ltr">QuickView</span> לצורך יישורה או לצורך הקלת הקריאה של שורות אלכסוניות, ניתן לשלוח את התמונה במיקומה החדש ל-<span dir="ltr">ViewOne</span> כדי לצפות בה שם ולעבד אותה בעזרת השימוש ברפרטואר העשיר של עיבוד תמונה ב-<span dir="ltr">ViewOne</span>; ואז אפשר לשמור אותה בשולחן העבודה האישי לצורך צפייה בעתיד.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">3. <u>קטלוגים סרוקים:</u> הוכנסו סריקות חדשות של ערכים קטלוגיים מהקטלוגים של <span dir="ltr">Zulay</span> ו-<span dir="ltr">Widder</span> על קטעי גניזה של בודפסט, שהיו חסרים עד כה.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">4. <u>רישום מוסדות:</u> נוספה מערכת רישום חדשה ופשוטה  עבור ספריות, המאפשרת גישה חופשית ומיידית לאתר הגניזה לכל המבקרים  בספריות, מתוך עשרים מחשבים המסומנים לכך בספריה.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">5. <u>שיפורים שונים:</u> א) <i>מסגרות:</i> מבנה  ה"מסגרות", המאפשר למשתמשים להוסיף הגבלות לחיפוש, שופר בהרבה והותאם יותר  לטיב התחומים ולמבנה המיוחד של החיבורים; כמו כן נוספה הפרדה טובה יותר בין  גוף הספר למידע המצורף לספר (הקדמה, נספחים, תוכן הענינים וכו'). ב) <i>סטטיסטיקות</i>: הטבלאות הסטטיסטיות המופיעות ב"עזרה" של כל פונקציה ונותנות סקירה מפורטת של המידע, הורחבו ושופרו במידה ניכרת. ג) <i>שולחן העבודה האישי</i>: בשולחן העבודה מופיעים כעת אייקונים שונים המאפשרים קבלת סוגים מסוימים של מידע בשולחן העבודה. ד) <i>פורום:</i> קיימת כעת פעולת סינון משופרת לכל ההערות בפורום. ה) <i>הגבלות:</i> הזמן המוקצה לשהייה "בטלה" (ללא כל פעילות) באתר הוגדל מ-40 ל-60 דקות.</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><u>הערות:</u></span></div><ol style="text-align: right;" type="1"><li dir="rtl"><span style="font-size: x-small;">אנו מזכירים לקוראינו שמשתמשים מורשים רשאים להוסיף מידע  חדש (כולל "צירופים"), אשר יופיעו באתר בתוספת שמו של המשתמש, באמצעות  מערכת <span dir="ltr">FOLUS</span> על כל קטעי הגניזה שבאתר, אנו  מעודדים משתמשים כאלו להשתמש בהזדמנות הניתנת להם להעשרת האתר במידע חדש  לתועלת כל קהילת חוקרי הגניזה. משתמשים נוספים המעוניינים לתרום באופן זה,  מוזמנים לשלוח אלינו דואר אלקטרוני דרך "צור קשר".</span></li><li dir="rtl"><span style="font-size: x-small;">אנו גם מעודדים את המשתמשים להשתמש בפורום הציבורי כדי  להציג הארות חדשות, לשלוח שאילתות, לפתוח דיונים ועוד, על נושאי הגניזה.  העיפו מבט בפורום עוד היום!</span></li><li dir="rtl"><span style="font-size: x-small;">אנו מזכירים למשתמשי אתר הגניזה את קיומו של אתר <span dir="ltr">Nahum</span> שאפשר להגיע אליו דרך אתר הגניזה, וכן גם ישירות בכתובת: <span dir="ltr">http//www.jewishmanuscripts.org</span>.&nbsp;אתר  זה מכיל קרוב ל-100,000 תמונות דיגיטליות באיכות גבוהה מאוסף כתבי היד  התימניים של נחום, וכן גם קטלוג חלקי ומידע נוסף על הקטעים וכתבי היד. אפשר  לחפש ולעבד מידע זה תוך שימוש בכלים המצויים שם והזהים לאלו המופיעים באתר  הגניזה.</span></li></ol><div style="text-align: right;"><br /></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">בברכת שלום,</span></div><div style="text-align: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">גנזים</span></div></blockquote></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1642512453363456260/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/11/friedberg-genizah-project-updates.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1642512453363456260"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1642512453363456260"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/11/friedberg-genizah-project-updates.html"
         title="The Friedberg Genizah Project Updates"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
