<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1853775118113973166</id>
   <published>2011-08-02T10:15:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-08-02T10:15:01.992-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Ancient World Digital Library Book Viewer</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<dl><dt><a href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/awdl/about">Ancient World Digital Library</a></dt><dt>&nbsp;</dt><dd><div class="inner"><div class="content clearfix">The Ancient World Digital Library (AWDL) is an initiative of the <a href="http://www.nyu.edu/isaw/" title="Institute for the Study of the Ancient World at New York University">Institute for the Study of the Ancient World at New York University</a>. AWDL will identify, collect, curate, and provide access to the  broadest possible range of scholarly materials relevant to the study of  the ancient world. AWDL has two primary tracks:  <br /><ol><li>In partnership with the NYU Digital Libraries Program  AWDL is  developing mechanisms to host and preserve existing and newly  contributed content without respect to digital condition, or state of  enrichment of its contents: our overriding objective is to make  available to researchers as large a part of the scholarly heritage of  the relevant fields as possible. Towards this end we are soliciting the  participation of publishers, scholarly societies, organizations, and  individuals who hold the rights to scholarly content.</li><li>AWDL will identify, collect, curate and provide bibliographical  access to the growing corpus of scholarly materials produced and served  elsewhere. This will continue, within the context of the AWDL, the work  Charles Jones has undertaken via <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/" title="Abzu">Abzu</a> and <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/" title="AWOL">AWOL</a> for more than a decade and a half. </li></ol>AWDL is collaborating with <a href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/dlts/" title="NYU Digital Library Technology Services">NYU Digital Library Technology Services (DLTS)</a>  in the development of the book viewer.Within the Institute for the  Study of the Ancient World, AWDL is a collaboration between the <a href="http://www.nyu.edu/isaw/library.htm">Library</a> and <a href="http://www.nyu.edu/isaw/about-projects.htm" title="Digital Programs">Digital Programs</a>.  Additional information on AWDL and other Digital Initiatives of the  Institute for the Study of the Ancient World is available on the <a href="http://www.nyu.edu/isaw/about-projects.htm">ISAW</a> website<br /><br /> </div></div>In its first public release the <a class="external-link" href="http://dlib.nyu.edu/awdl/">Ancient World Digital Library&nbsp;Book Viewer</a> includes a set of books digitized from the collections of the <a href="http://www.nyu.edu/gsas/dept/fineart/research/lib_chan.htm">Stephen Chan Library of Fine Arts</a> of the Institute of Fine Arts.<br /><br /><br /></dd></dl>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1853775118113973166/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/08/ancient-world-digital-library-book.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1853775118113973166"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1853775118113973166"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/08/ancient-world-digital-library-book.html"
         title="Ancient World Digital Library Book Viewer"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
