<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6890170055734701208</id>
   <published>2012-10-21T16:53:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-10-21T16:53:48.983-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Classics Ancient World Podcasts (Cincinnati)</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts">UC Classics Ancient World Podcasts</a><br /><span class="breadcrumbs pathway"></span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div id="story_wrap"><div class="article-content"><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="uc_classics_podcast" height="400" src="http://classics.uc.edu/images/stories/podcasts/uc_classics_podcast.jpg" width="400" /></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">Welcome to the home for <i>UC Classics Ancient World Podcasts</i>,  produced by the faculty and graduate students of the University of  Cincinnati’s Department of Classics. Come along with us as we explore  compelling stories about the lives of people living in the ancient  Mediterranean.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Episodes already available cover topics related to the ancient city  of Pompeii and its destruction, while new series in the coming weeks  will feature Cincinnati and its ties to ancient Greek and Roman culture,  and Qumran and the Dead Sea Scrolls (to coincide with an exhibit at the  Cincinnati Museum Center: <a href="http://www.cincymuseum.org/dead-sea-scrolls" target="_blank">http://www.cincymuseum.org/dead-sea-scrolls</a>).  These series bring together experts in ancient history, language, and  archaeology from our department, from UC’s Judaic Studies Department,  and from Hebrew Union College to share their passion and knowledge about  the Classical world.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The <i>UC Classics Ancient World Podcasts </i>are suitable for  audiences of all ages with an interest in the past, and make a great  supplement on a visit to a museum, or for middle school, high school,  and college classes!</span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;">These podcasts are just one part of our department’s outreach  program, aimed at engaging the wider Cincinnati community and promoting  enthusiasm about the ancient world. Learn more about our offerings of  public lectures, presentations, and educational content at: <a href="http://classics.uc.edu/outreach">http://classics.uc.edu/outreach</a></span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: xx-small;">The latest series of podcasts has been made possible due to the  generous support of a Society Outreach Grant from the Archaeological  Institute of America: <a href="http://www.archaeological.org/grants/712">http://www.archaeological.org/grants/712</a> </span></div></div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2><span style="font-size: xx-small;">The Dead Sea Scroll Series</span></h2><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/189-an-archaeologist-visits-qumran">An Archaeologist Visits Qumran</a></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">It has been over 50 years since approximately 900 Dead Sea scrolls  and fragments were discovered in 11 caves in the neighborhood of Qumran,  Israel. In spite of decades of scholarly debate, many questions remain  about the site. Who lived at Qumran? Was it a fortress, a mansion, an  agricultural center, a pottery workshop, or a commune for an ancient  Jewish sect called the Essenes? Was it where the Dead Sea Scrolls were  written, or just where they were collected? Journey with UC Classics  Professor Barbara Burrell, your archaeological roving reporter, as she  describes Qumran’s surroundings, its features, its finds, and its place  in history.</span><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Written and performed by Barbara Burrell; produced by Christian Cloke  and Sarah Lima; featuring Vivaldi's Gloria; recording and editing by R.  Aaron Allen Productions.</span><br /><h2><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Cincinnati and the Classics Series</span></h2><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/188-a-funny-thing-happened-on-the-way-to-fountain-square-finding-rome-in-cincinnati">A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to Fountain Square: Finding Rome in Cincinnati</a></b></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Ancient historian Kristina Neumann and philologist Michael Hanel (UC  Classics) discuss how the modern city of Cincinnati has much in common  with ancient Rome. Learn where the <i>name </i>Cincinnati came from and  what it has to do with early Roman history. Through a look at these  cities’ water supply, their hilly terrain, and their entertainment  venues (from the Roman Coliseum to Paul Brown Stadium, home of the  Bengals), a tour of downtown Cincinnati shows that more than just the  city’s name harkens back to an important Classical past.</span><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;Written by Kristina Neumann; featuring Michael Hanel and Kristina  Neumann; produced by Christian Cloke and Sarah Lima; featuring Vivaldi's  Gloria; recording and editing by R. Aaron Allen Productions.</span><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><br /></b></span><h2><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Pompeii Series</span></h2><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/169-pompeii-podcasts-the-tombs-of-pompeii">The Tombs of Pompeii</a></b></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">UC Classics graduate student Allison Emmerson shares her expertise on  Pompeii’s tombs. She explains ways in which monuments commemorating  individuals, their families, their slaves, and former slaves can offer  insights into how people lived and what they valued. While these tombs  are an important part of the site for studying the dead, they also  played a prominent role in the living city, serving as places to stop  and sit, write graffiti, and even deposit trash.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/170-pompeii-podcasts-roman-medicine">Roman Medicine</a></b></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Journey back in time to meet noted Roman medical writer Aulus  Cornelius Celsus and naturalist Pliny the Elder as they debate the  merits of Greek and Roman medicine! In this episode, listeners can learn  about bone-saws, cataract operations, enemas, strange recipes for  poultices, and the merits of a good bleeding, all done without the  benefit of anesthesia!</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/171-pompeii-podcasts-plinys-letters-and-the-eruption-of-vesuvius">Pliny’s Letters and the Eruption of Vesuvius</a></b></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">While scientists today closely monitor the world’s active volcanoes,  in AD 79 when Mount Vesuvius erupted, there was little warning and panic  took precedence over scientific observation. Fortunately, one famous  Roman politician and writer, Pliny the Younger, was on the scene and in a  series of famous letters made many important observations about the  eruption and its impact on the residents of the Bay of Naples. Join UC  Classics graduate student Mitchell Brown for an in-depth glimpse at  these fascinating contemporary accounts of the destruction of Pompeii.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/172-pompeii-podcasts-human-remains-at-pompeii">Human Remains at Pompeii</a></b></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">No trip to Pompeii is complete without a glimpse of the stunning  casts of the site’s ancient residents who were trapped by the eruption  of Mount Vesuvius. Ever since Pompeii’s rediscovery in the 1740s, the  bodies of the volcano’s victims have captivated visitors to the site. UC  Classics graduate student Sarah Lima delves into the study of human  remains at Pompeii, and shares how they have played a prominent role in  the development of modern archaeology and shaped the popular imagination  of the site’s last days.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/173-pompeii-podcasts-food-part-1-of-2-dining-at-home">Food Part 1 of 2 (Dining at Home)</a></b></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">In this episode of the long-lost Roman cooking show, “The Splendid  Triclinium,” join host Flavia Poma as she talks Roman cuisine with UC  Classics graduate student Kristina Neumann. In Part 1 they examine the  eating habits of the rich and famous, discuss the Roman diet, and take a  closer look at Roman pots, pans, flatware, and dishes. They say “you  are what you eat,” and from Pompeii we can learn a lot about what  ancient Romans ate!</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/174-pompeii-podcasts-food-part-2-of-2-dining-out-and-grocery-shopping">Food Part 2 of 2 (Dining out and Grocery Shopping)</a></b></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">In our second episode of “The Splendid Triclinium,” our host and  guest move from the dining room to the fish market and fast-food  restaurant! While many of the large houses of Pompeii’s wealthiest  citizens had spectacular dining rooms, most of the city’s inhabitants  had humble cooking facilities at home and relied on restaurants and  carry-out menus. Discover where Romans did their grocery shopping, and  learn about recipes for dormice (yes, mice!) and, for the less  adventurous, deep-fried honey cakes.</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/175-pompeii-podcasts-gladiators">Gladiators</a></b></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Go live to the arena of Pompeii in early AD 79 to meet burgeoning  gladiatorial superstar, Severus, fresh off a major victory! Our intrepid  reporter interviews the new champ, learns about his training, his  finishing moves, and asks why it’s so tricky to fight against a lefty!  Severus talks corruption, riots, the politics of the games, and gives  his thoughts on the construction of the new Colosseum in Rome. Learn why  the Romans loved gladiatorial combat so much from someone with  firsthand experience!</span><br /><h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><b><a href="http://classics.uc.edu/index.php/podcasts/176-pompeii-podcasts-commerce-and-business">Commerce and Business</a></b></span></h3><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Without the eruption of Mount Vesuvius, Pompeii would not be what it  is today, but without a prosperous local economy, there would have been  no site at all. UC Classics professor Peter van Minnen looks to  archaeology and ancient texts to answer the tough questions about how  people in Pompeii made their living. Learn about ancient farming,  shipping, and slavery, and discover how the very volcano which destroyed  the city also gave rise to a booming local wine industry!</span></blockquote>&nbsp;      <span class="article_separator"><br /></span>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6890170055734701208/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/classics-ancient-world-podcasts.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6890170055734701208"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6890170055734701208"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/classics-ancient-world-podcasts.html"
         title="Classics Ancient World Podcasts (Cincinnati)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
