<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3140469734648829471</id>
   <published>2014-01-01T20:44:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2014-01-01T20:44:45.990-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Photography"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Description and Travel"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Middle East"/>
   <title type="text">AGSL Digital Photo Archive - Asia and Middle East</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://collections.lib.uwm.edu/cdm/landingpage/collection/agsphoto">AGSL Digital Photo Archive - Asia and Middle East</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img alt="http://collections.lib.uwm.edu/ui/custom/default/collection/coll_agsphoto/images/agsphoto-header-transparent.png" class="decoded" height="38" src="http://collections.lib.uwm.edu/ui/custom/default/collection/coll_agsphoto/images/agsphoto-header-transparent.png" width="320" /></span> </blockquote><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>AGSL Digital Photo Archive</strong> presents a selection of   images from the extensive photographic holdings of the American   Geographical Society (AGS) Library. The images were selected from   several collections including the American Geographical Society Library   Print Collection, the Harrison Forman Collection, the Robert W. McColl   Collection, the Bert Krawczyk Collection, the Edna Schaus Sorensen and   Clarence W. Sorensen Collection, and the Helmut de Terra Collection.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The American Geographical Society Library Print Collection   represents many decades of research and acquisition. The scope of the   collection is worldwide. Dating from the mid nineteenth century to the   present, these photographs document a wealth of geographic themes. Many   of the photographs were originally donated to the American Geographical   Society to illustrate its publications, such as the <em>Bulletin</em> and <em>Geographical Review</em>.   The images selected for this project include historical photos of   Afghanistan, Egypt, Jordan, Korea, Thailand, Nepal, and China.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Clarence Woodrow Sorensen was an explorer, editor, and CBS  staff  foreign correspondent who traveled extensively capturing images of  the  life, work, and historical events of cultures worldwide. During   Sorenson's extensive travels, Eugene V. Harris, a professional   photographer, accompanied him and took many of  64,000 slides that make   up the collection. The slides selected for this project include photos   of Iran, Iraq, Syria, and Turkey that Sorensen and Harris took in the   1950s and 1960s.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Krawczyk Collection presents approximately 600 images of  China  and India taken during World War II by Hubert Krawczyk, a young   photographer and artist who was stationed in India, and then assigned to   the Hunan (Yunnan) Province of China in 1942 through 1945.  The   negatives are housed at the American Geographical Society Library and   were scanned as part of the <a href="http://www4.uwm.edu/libraries/digilib/NEHgrant/">2010-2012 NEH Grant Project</a> to digitize the library's collection of nitrate negatives.  The   negatives are particularly valuable because he made annotations for his   photography of Chinese cultural events and document the regional   clothing and costumes of the Chinese people during the 1940s.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Mary Jo Read Collection consists of approximately 250  negatives,  supplemented by hand-colored lantern slides and a descriptive  journal  of her photography.  This small collection of negatives was  made in  1935 while Mary Jo Read was on vacation in China, Japan, Korea  and the  Philippines.  She had a selection of these images made into hand   colored lantern slides. The negatives and slides are part of a larger   collection of photography housed at the American Geographical Society   Library.  The negatives were scanned as part of the <a href="http://www4.uwm.edu/libraries/digilib/NEHgrant/">2010-2012 NEH Grant Project</a> to digitize the AGSL's collection of nitrate negatives.</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The current selection of the AGSL Digital Photo Archive focuses  on  the countries of Asia and the Middle East. The coverage of this  digital  collection will expand as more photos are added to the site.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3140469734648829471/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/01/agsl-digital-photo-archive-asia-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3140469734648829471"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3140469734648829471"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/01/agsl-digital-photo-archive-asia-and.html"
         title="AGSL Digital Photo Archive - Asia and Middle East"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
