<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-6358479354593673047</id>
   <published>2011-09-05T11:04:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-07-10T10:23:04.023-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Israel"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: RAMBI</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><div style="text-align: left;"><span class="title"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;[<a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/11/more-open-access-journals-group-8.html">First posted</a> in AWOL 6 November 2009.&nbsp; Updated 5 September 2011]</span></span></div><div style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/goog_725574093"><br /></a></div><div style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://jnul.huji.ac.il/rambi/">RAMBI- The Index of Articles on Jewish Studies - רשימת מאמרים במדעי היהדות -  רמב"י</a></div><blockquote style="color: black;"><div style="text-align: left;"><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><span style="font-family: Times New Roman,Times;">Introduction</span></b></span><span style="font-family: Times New Roman,Times; font-size: x-small;"><b>RAMBI - The Index of Articles on Jewish Studies - </b>is a selective bibliography of articles in the various fields of Jewish studies and in the study of Eretz Israel. Material listed in Rambi is compiled from thousands of periodicals and from collections of articles - in Hebrew, Yiddish, and European languages- mainly from the holdings of the Jewish National and University Library, a world center for research on the Jewish people and Eretz Israel. The main criterion for inclusion in the bibliography is that the article be based on scientific research, or contain important information for such research. Since the inception of this bibliographic project in 1966, the editorial board has striven to include in it all of the important articles published throughout the world in the field of Judaica. Therefore, it includes offprints of articles from journals or collections not on order to the Library. Rambi also lists articles from secondary sources.</span> </blockquote></div></blockquote><blockquote style="color: black;"><div style="text-align: left;"><blockquote> <span style="font-family: Times New Roman,Times; font-size: x-small;">In 1985, Rambi began listing articles electronically as one of the databases on the ALEPH computer network of academic and research libraries in Israel, and in 2000, Rambi became accessible on the Internet via the WWW.&nbsp; In 2001, Rambi published its 50th volume and also completed a retrospective conversion project made possible by a grant from The Lucius N. Littauer Foundation. With the availability of the entire corpus of Rambi's 50 volumes in each of&nbsp; Rambi's computer databases, publication of the printed volumes of Rambi was discontinued.</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />&nbsp; </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b><span style="font-family: Times New Roman,Times;">Information Included in RAMBI</span></b></span><br /><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-family: Times New Roman,Times; font-size: x-small;">A typical record contains the following information: author(s); article title; abbreviated source name; citation (volume, issue, year, pages); narrow and broad subject classifications; full source name, including place of publication; year of publication; language of article. Every record in the Rambi database contains two distinct subject classification fields: a general classification field (e.g. Bible; Diaspora; Philosophy), and specific subject headings (e.g. Genesis: 1; USA: education; Maimonides: Moreh Nevukhim). Attempts are made to utilize the two fields in tandem to provide maximum subject descriptions of the articles.</span> </div></blockquote></div></blockquote><br /><span style="font-size: small;"><span><span><span class="brödtext"><span class="titol"><span class="text">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></span></span></span> </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/6358479354593673047/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/open-access-journal-rambi.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6358479354593673047"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/6358479354593673047"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/open-access-journal-rambi.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: RAMBI"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
