<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3844890379588790433</id>
   <published>2013-10-27T08:30:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-10-27T08:48:50.747-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Digital Library"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#"
             term="institutional repository"/>
   <title type="text">Claremont Colleges Digital Library</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;[First posted 1/16/09. Updated 27 October 2013]</span><br /><br /><a href="http://ccdl.libraries.claremont.edu/cdm/collections">The Claremont Colleges Digital Library</a> is serving some interesting open access  material relating to antiquity:<br /><br /><blockquote><div class="collections_title_link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://ccdl.libraries.claremont.edu/collection.php?alias=aot">Antiquities  of the Institute for Antiquity and Christianity</a></span> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;">The artifacts in this collection represent part of the antiquities  of the Institute for Antiquity and Christianity. The items are mostly  eastern Mediterranean in provenance, originating from ancient Greece,  Cyprus, Anatolia, Syria, Palestine, Egypt, and neighboring regions. A  fair proportion of the collection dates to the Bronze Age, but every  period thereafter is represented up to the fourth century of the current  era. Although the majority is earthenware, other artifacts include  objects of glass, ceramic, stone, metal and Cypriote.</span><br /><div style="float: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><div class="collections_title_link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://ccdl.libraries.claremont.edu/collection.php?alias=bia">Bulletin  of the Institute for Antiquity and Christianity</a></span> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;">  The Institute for Antiquity and Christianity is a center for basic  research on the origins and meaning of the cultural heritage of Western  civilization.   The Bulletin of the Institute for Antiquity and  Christianity is published periodically under the auspices of the Society  for Antiquity and Christianity for the general information of persons  interested in the research programs of the Institute.</span></blockquote><blockquote><div class="collections_title_link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://ccdl.libraries.claremont.edu/collection.php?alias=cpo">Campi  Phlegraei, Observations on the Volcanoes of the Two Sicilies</a></span> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;">The two volumes of the <i>Campi Phlegraei</i> (1776) and the <i>Supplement  to the Campi Phlegraei</i> (1779) provide a firsthand report from Sir  William Hamilton which documents the late eighteenth century eruptions  of Mount Vesuvius and are important to the science of volcanology due to  the precise descriptions of the changes in the appearance of the  volcano, the lava flows and other volcanic activity.  Displayed here in  their entirety, these books contain text in both English and French and  59 hand-colored plates with accompanying explanations.</span><br /><div style="float: right;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div></blockquote><blockquote><div class="collections_title_link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://ccdl.libraries.claremont.edu/collection.php?alias=cce">Claremont Coptic Encyclopedia</a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"> The Claremont Coptic Encyclopedia (CCE) will initially include  approximately 2800 articles published in The Coptic Encyclopedia (Aziz  S. Atiya, ed. NY: Macmillan, 1991). The CCE will continuously add  updates and new topics from the growing body of scholarship in Coptic  studies at institutions worldwide. The scope of articles includes Coptic  language and literature; Copto-Arabic literature; Coptic art,  architecture, archaeology, history, music, liturgy, theology,  spirituality, monasticism; and biblical, apocryphal, social, and legal  texts.</span> </blockquote><blockquote><div class="collections_title_link"> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://ccdl.libraries.claremont.edu/cdm/landingpage/collection/nha">Nag Hammadi Archive </a></span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Nag Hammadi codices, thirteen ancient manuscripts containing  over fifty religious and philosophical texts written in Coptic and  hidden in an earthenware jar for 1,600 years, were accidentally  discovered in upper Egypt in the year 1945. This immensely important  discovery included a large number of primary Gnostic scriptures. These  texts were once thought to have been entirely destroyed during the early  Christian struggle to define "orthodoxy," scriptures such as the Gospel  of Thomas, the Gospel of Philip, and the Gospel of Truth. The images in  this collection were taken during the excavations and translation  project of the 1970’s and record the environments surrounding  excavations, visiting dignitaries, and the scholars working on the  codices. The project has provided momentum to a major reassessment of  early Christian history and the nature of Gnosticism. </span></blockquote><blockquote><div class="collections_title_link"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://ccdl.libraries.claremont.edu/collection.php?alias=sac">Sacred  Text Conference Archives</a></span> </div><span style="font-size: x-small;">The First Annual Conference of Religions is a conversation and  exploration of passages addressing relationships with insiders and  outsiders, and points of inclusivity and exclusivity, within the Sacred  Texts of six groups: Islam, Judaism, Christianity, Zoroastrianism,  LDS/Mormonism, and Hinduism.</span> <script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3844890379588790433/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/01/claremont-colleges-digital-library.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3844890379588790433"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3844890379588790433"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/01/claremont-colleges-digital-library.html"
         title="Claremont Colleges Digital Library"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
