<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5741554572830482821</id>
   <published>2013-12-08T11:00:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-12-08T11:02:07.844-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Composite text search and score generation in CDLI</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<b>Composite text search and score generation in <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/">CDLI</a></b> [via email]<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">I am pleased to announce, after the recent implementation of a new  search and aggregation tool keyed to cylinder seal occurrences in&nbsp;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/">CDLI</a>  text transliterations, a second, similar utility for searching and  displaying composite and witness entries that document  the&nbsp;occasionally quite rich Mesopotamian tradition of text copying and  transmission. Supported by the programming skills of UCLA CS graduate  students&nbsp;Eunice Yuh-Jie Chen and Henry Li, we have begun entering to <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/">CDLI</a> catalogue all “Q” identifiers&nbsp;of such texts,  following the numbering system of <a href="http://oracc.museum.upenn.edu/qca">Oracc’s Qcat</a>,  and,  in line with the&nbsp;system implemented for seals management, have made  these Q numbers searchable at our slightly revamped <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/search/">search page</a>. Thus now a search for the  Gudea text (RIME 3/1.1.7.41 =) Q000911 results in, currently but ever  growing, 399&nbsp;hits, led by Dan Foxvog’s transliteration and translation  of the composite version and followed by entries documenting 398  physical&nbsp;artifacts. While the Q numbers will be less familiar to users,  this system, like its cousin seals ID field, allows  a casual&nbsp;viewing of some random witness text, for instance a recently  tagged <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/P404780">cone fragment in the University of Durham</a>  collection, to expand, by clicking  on its corresponding catalogue composite ID Q000915, to a full view of  the&nbsp;96 <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/">CDLI</a> entries that are associated with that text, led again by  Foxvog’s treatment of an idealized composite version.&nbsp;Indeed, we limit  all translations of such texts to these composite entries.<br /><br />The corresponding tagging of composite text transliterations in <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/">CDLI</a> for  the purpose of generating score versions of each text,&nbsp;that we  delighted in producing as ambitious students of Assyriology, will follow  along at a slower  pace.&nbsp;&lt;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/tools/scores/partitur-index.html">http://cdli.ucla.edu/tools/scores/partitur-index.html</a>&gt;  contains the first several dozen such completed score (“Partitur”)  versions,&nbsp;primarily now of the easier to tag RIME inscriptions, but in  time the much more involved scores of scholarly texts will be  added.&nbsp;Given the great numbers of exemplars of royal inscriptions  catalogued by the RIM project, we have decided to limit Q-tagging  of&nbsp;transliterations to those that are better documented than by their  simple entry in RIM witness catalogues, usually with&nbsp;existing image  files, with the exception of texts with no such documentation.  In these cases, the first otherwise minimally  registered&nbsp;transliteration will serve as a single witness until further  documentation is available to us. Thus while the <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/tools/scores/Q000908.html">score&nbsp;of Gudea 37</a>&nbsp; seems imposing,  it  comprises just 250 of the 1365 registered&nbsp;witnesses to this  inscription. These seals-and-composites tools are, for us, primarily  technical means to improve the standardization&nbsp;and reliability of our  existing transliterations, but should also be of general  interest to colleagues who seek to check the fidelity&nbsp;of the various  published or circulated forms of Partitur apparatus that represent some  of our most treasured research tools.<br /><br />Bob Englund<br />UCLA </span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5741554572830482821/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/12/composite-text-search-and-score.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5741554572830482821"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5741554572830482821"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/12/composite-text-search-and-score.html"
         title="Composite text search and score generation in CDLI"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
