<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5483353641923556821</id>
   <published>2013-03-28T15:30:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-03-28T15:19:18.285-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Digital Library of Inscriptions and Calligraphies</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;[First posted in AWOL 30 November 2010. Updated 28 March 2013] &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://nscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/presentation/mainpage.aspx?lang=en"&gt;The Digital Library of &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://nscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/presentation/mainpage.aspx?lang=en"&gt;Inscriptions and &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://nscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/presentation/mainpage.aspx?lang=en"&gt;Calligraphies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="main-title"&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="right" style="width: 242px;"&gt;          &lt;div class="search"&gt;            &lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;div class="searchInput" style="padding: 2px 0; width: 240px;"&gt;                &lt;img alt="http://inscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/images/title.png" class="decoded" height="25" src="http://inscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/images/title.png" width="400" /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Modern technology in general, digital in particular, have  added new dimensions as well as more sophisticated vocational  requirements to the field of Library and Information Science, from which  researches and knowledge lovers benefit. Amidst this tremendous  quantity of forms of the technological revolution, it was natural for  the Bibliotheca Alexandrina to adopt the concept of digital publication  in order to make it available to researchers interested in science and  knowledge. This, in turn, is what propels the Calligraphy Center to  provide the study of inscriptions, calligraphy, and writings of the  world across the ages from the prehistoric age until now with a new  approach and vision. From this premise, the idea of the Digital Library  of Inscriptions and Calligraphies was generated.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;This project comes at the head of the Center of the Studies of Writings  and Calligraphy’s objectives, which has taken upon itself the  publication of different inscriptions and writings; in particular,  inscriptions in different languages and writings from Egypt and abroad,  which the center has made available to scientists, researchers, and  amateurs in a simplified digital content through the website. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The project of the Digital Library of Inscriptions and Calligraphies is  considered a digital record for writings carved on buildings and  archaeological remains across the ages. These inscriptions are presented  to the user in a digital form, including a synopsis of the  inscription’s data, photos, and a record of the writing’s it bears .&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div style="width: 850px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The project has been adopted in the present time  to record a group of languages in numerous scripts, including Ancient  Egyptian, Arabic, Persian, Turkish, and Greek; developing the  inscriptions of each script separately, and recording a new group of  other languages’ scripts. The basic data and detailed descriptions of  these inscriptions are displayed in two languages: Arabic and English. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div style="width: 850px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Project organizers were keen to build a  flexible, user-friendly website for the Digital Library of Inscriptions  and Calligraphies in order to enable a large number of researchers to  benefit from the gems of archaeological written inscriptions and further  browse the images and references of each inscription separately. The  inscriptions can be easily browsed by language, or the classification of  the inscription; architecture, arts, or sculpture as well as the type  of the archaeological remain. It is possible to find a specific  inscription using the advanced search feature which allows the user to  search by the artifact’s number, place of preservation, or place of  discovery, and also by the period of time to which the written  inscription belongs. At this moment, the researcher will find all the  information related to the archaeological remain accompanied with  high-quality images, analysis of the written inscription, information  and a descriptive synopsis of the remain as well as a translation of the  inscription. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div style="width: 850px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Calligraphy Center aspires to make the  Digital Library of Inscriptions one of the most important digital  libraries specializing in the field of inscriptions and writings on the  internet&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;ul class="main-menu"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://inscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/presentation/AboutDL.aspx?lang=en#" id="aAncientEgyptian"&gt;Ancient Egyptian Inscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://inscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/presentation/AboutDL.aspx?lang=en#" id="aArabic"&gt;Arabic Inscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://inscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/presentation/AboutDL.aspx?lang=en#" id="aPersian"&gt;Persian Inscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://inscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/presentation/AboutDL.aspx?lang=en#" id="aTurkish"&gt;Turkish Inscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://inscriptionslibrary.bibalex.org/presentation/AboutDL.aspx?lang=en#" id="aGreek"&gt;Greek Inscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;And see also the full list of &lt;a href="http://www.bibalex.org/Project/CategoryProjects_EN.aspx?CatID=2"&gt;Digital Projects of the Bibliotheca Alexandrina&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5483353641923556821/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/11/digital-library-of-calligraphies-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5483353641923556821"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5483353641923556821"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/11/digital-library-of-calligraphies-and.html"
         title="Digital Library of Inscriptions and Calligraphies"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
