<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7492454763139676827</id>
   <published>2011-06-14T12:02:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-06-14T12:02:18.229-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">tDAR - Digital Archaeological Record</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.tdar.org/">tDAR - Digital Archaeological Record</a><br /><br /><div class="entry page clear">    <blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Digital Archaeological Record (tDAR)&nbsp;is an international  digital repository for the digital records of archaeological  investigations. tDAR’s use, development, and maintenance are governed by  <a href="http://digitalantiquity.org/">Digital Antiquity</a>,  an organization dedicated to ensuring the long-term preservation of  irreplaceable archaeological data and to broadening access to these  data.&nbsp; The tDAR repository will enable researchers to more effectively  create knowledge of the &nbsp;human past and resource managers to better  preserve and protect archaeological resources.&nbsp;Digital Antiquity’s key  objectives include fostering the use of tDAR and ensuring its financial,  technical, and professional sustainability.&nbsp;Use of tDAR has the  potential to transform archaeological research by providing direct  access to current and historic digital data along with powerful tools to  analyze and reuse it.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The tDAR repository encompasses digital data, documents, and images  derived from ongoing archaeological research, as well as legacy data  derived from more than a century of archaeological research. The  repository provides for long-term preservation and easy discovery and  access to databases, spreadsheets, documents, and images in a variety of  common formats.</span> </blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">tDAR operates under the organizational umbrella of Digital Antiquity, a multi-institutional organization that has been <a href="http://www.tdar.org/images/SAA-McM-Kintigh.pdf">explicitly designed</a>  to ensure the long-term financial, technical, and social sustainability  of the tDAR cyberinfrastructure.&nbsp;&nbsp;Digital Antiquity is led by Executive  Director Francis P. McManamon and Technology Director Adam Brin.  Digital Antiquity is governed by an independent Board of Directors  composed of four members with expertise in finance, law, not-for-profit  organization administration, and information technology, plus  individuals from the <a href="http://cast.uark.edu/">University of Arkansas</a>, <a href="http://www.asu.edu/">Arizona State University</a>, the <a href="http://www.psu.edu/">Pennsylvania State University</a>, the <a href="http://www.srifoundation.org/">SRI Foundation</a>, <a href="http://www.wsu.edu/">Washington State University</a>, and the <a href="http://www.york.ac.uk/">University of York</a>.  Digital Antiquity’s decision-making is supported by a distinguished  external Science Board with representatives from all sectors of  archaeology and from information science. Digital Antiquity currently is  being incubated by Arizona State University. At the end of its initial  development, the organization (and tDAR) may be established as a  “stand-alone” not-for-profit&nbsp; organization or be incorporated into an  appropriate non-profit, such as a professional association.</span></blockquote></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7492454763139676827/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/06/tdar-digital-archaeological-record.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7492454763139676827"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7492454763139676827"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/06/tdar-digital-archaeological-record.html"
         title="tDAR - Digital Archaeological Record"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
