<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1262955367985992358</id>
   <published>2013-08-31T08:00:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-08-31T10:48:46.833-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Bible"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Digital Library"/>
   <title type="text">The SBL's International Cooperation Initiative Program (ICI)</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;[First posted on AWOL 23 March 2009. Updated 31 August 2013]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sbl-site.org/InternationalCoopInitiative.aspx"&gt;The Society of Biblical Literature International Cooperation Initiative (ICI)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The SBL launched the International Cooperation Initiative (ICI) to  foster biblical scholarship and to facilitate mutual cooperation among  colleagues.&lt;/span&gt;            &lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;            International Cooperation Initiative (ICI) Board             &lt;/span&gt;                         &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Anyone interested in participating in the work of the ICI should contact one of the following members of the ICI Board: &lt;a href="mailto:ehud.ben.zvi@ualberta.ca" style="color: #2a33c2;" target="_blank"&gt;Ehud Ben Zvi&lt;/a&gt;; (chair); &lt;a href="mailto:cehao_uca@yahoo.com.ar" style="color: #2a33c2;" target="_blank"&gt;Roxana Flammini&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="mailto:lcj@sun.ac.za" style="color: #2a33c2;" target="_blank"&gt;Louis Jonker&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="mailto:monixm@gmail.com" style="color: #2a33c2;" target="_blank"&gt;Monica Melancthon&lt;/a&gt;; or; &lt;a href="mailto:leigh.andersen@sbl-site.org" style="color: #2a33c2;" target="_blank"&gt;Leigh Andersen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(SBL staff).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;If you visit &lt;a href="http://www.sbl-site.org/publications/onlinebooks.aspx"&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; from a domain identifiable as being in a &lt;a href="http://www.sbl-site.org/assets/pdfs/ICIcountries.pdf"&gt;qualifying country&lt;/a&gt;, you should be able to see links to all the available books.  I would appreciate comment (see below) from those who are able to access these book. This is the current list:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Books in the Program as of July 31, 2013 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sbl-site.org/publications/onlinebooks.aspx"&gt;back to online books page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For more information on the ICI Program, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sbl-site.org/InternationalCoopInitiative.aspx" target="_self"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;click here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Albertz, Rainer, &lt;em&gt;Israel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; in Exile: The History and Literature of the Sixth Century B.C.E.&lt;/em&gt;Studies in Biblical Literature 3. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Albl, Martin C., trans. &lt;em&gt;Pseudo-Gregory of Nyssa: Testimonies against the Jews&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 8. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Allen, James P., &lt;em&gt;The Ancient Egyptian Pyramid Texts&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 23. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ames, Frank Ritchel and Charles William Miller, eds. &lt;em&gt;Foster Biblical Scholarship: Essays in Honor of Kent Harold Richards&lt;/em&gt;. Biblical Scholarship in North America 24. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Amidon, S.J., Philip R, trans. &lt;em&gt;Philostorgius: Church History&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 23. Atlanta: Society of&amp;nbsp; Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anderson, Paul N., Felix Just, S.J., and Tom Thatcher, eds. &lt;em&gt;John, Jesus, and History, Volume 1: Critical Appraisals of Critical View&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 44. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Anderson, Paul N. , Felix Just, S.J., and Tom Thatcher, eds. &lt;em&gt;John, Jesus, and History, Volume 2: Aspects of Historicity in the Fourth Gospel&lt;/em&gt;. Early Christianity and Its Literature 2. Atlanta: Society of&amp;nbsp; Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Arnold, Bill T. &lt;em&gt;Who Were the Babylonians?&lt;/em&gt; Archaeology and Biblical Studies 10. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Arterbury, Andrew E. &lt;em&gt;Entertaining Angels: Early Christian Hospitality in its Meterranean Setting&lt;/em&gt;. New Testament Monographs 8. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Attridge, Harold W. and James C. VanderKam, eds. &lt;em&gt;Presidential Voices: The Society of Biblical Literature in the Twentieth Century&lt;/em&gt;. Biblical Scholarship in North America 22. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Avalos, Hector, Sarah J. Melcher, and Jeremy Schipper, eds. &lt;em&gt;This Abled Body:&lt;br /&gt;Rethinking Disabilities in Biblical Studies&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 55. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Azize, Joseph. &lt;em&gt;The Phoenician Solar Theology: An Investigation into the Phoenician Opinion of the Sun Found in Julian's Hymn to King Helios&lt;/em&gt;. Gorgias Dissertations 15: Near Eastern Studies, Vol. 6. Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Press, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bailey, Randall C., ed. &lt;em&gt;Yet With a Steady Beat: Contemporary U. S. Afrocentric Biblical Interpretation&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 42. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bailey, Randall C., Tat-siong Benny Liew, and Fernando F. Segovia. &lt;em&gt;They Were All Together in One Place? Toward Minority Biblical Criticism.&lt;/em&gt; Semeia Studies 57. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Bandstra, Barry. &lt;em&gt;Genesis 1-11: A Handbook on the Hebrew Text&lt;/em&gt;. Baylor Handbook on Hebrew Bible. Waco: Baylor University Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Bandy, Alan&amp;nbsp;S. &lt;em&gt;The Prophetic Lawsuit in the Book of Revelation. &lt;/em&gt;New Testament Monographs 29. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2010.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Barr, David L., ed., &lt;em&gt;Reading the Book of Revelation: A Resource for Students. &lt;/em&gt;Resourcesfor Biblical Study 44. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Barr, David L., ed. &lt;em&gt;The Reality of Apocalypse: Rhetoric and Politics in the Book of Revelation.&lt;/em&gt; Symposium 39. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Barré, Michael L., S.S., &lt;em&gt;The Lord Has Saved Me: A Study of the Psalm of Hezekiah (Isaiah 38:9-20)&lt;/em&gt;. Catholic Biblical Quarterly Monograph Series 39. Washington: The Catholic Biblical Association of America. 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Bartor, Assnat. &lt;em&gt;Reading Law as Narrative: A Study in the Casuistic Laws of the Pentateuch&lt;/em&gt;. Ancient Israel and Its Literature 5. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Bautch, Richard J., &lt;em&gt;Developments in Genre between Post-Exilic Penitential Prayers and the Psalms of Communal Lament&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 7. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Beckman, Gary M., Trevor R. Bryce, and Eric H. Cline&lt;strong&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ahhiyawa Texts&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Writings from the Ancient World, 28.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta, Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Bellis, Alice Ogden and Joel S. Kaminsky, ed.. &lt;em&gt;Jews, Christians, and the Theology of the Hebrew Scriptures&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 8. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ben Zvi, Ehud and Michael H. Floyd, eds. &lt;em&gt;Writings and Speech in Israelite and Ancient Near Eastern Prophecy&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 10. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ben Zvi, Ehud, Diana V. Edelman &amp;amp; Frank Polak, eds., &lt;em&gt;A Palimpsest: Rhetoric, Ideology, Stylistics, and Language Relating to Persian Israel.&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Perspectives on Hebrew Scriptures and its Contexts&amp;nbsp;5.&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Press, 2009. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Bernat, David A.&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Sign of the Covenant: Circumcision in the Priestly Tradition&lt;/em&gt;. Ancient Israel and Its Literature 3. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bergen, Wesley J. and Armin Siedlecki, eds. &lt;em&gt;Voyages in Uncharted Waters: Essays on the Theory and Practice of Biblical Interpretation&lt;/em&gt;. Hebrew Bible Monographs 13. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Berger, Yitzhak. &lt;em&gt;The Commentary of Rabbi David Kimhi to Chronicles: A Translation with Introduction and Supercommentary&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 345. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Berquist, Jon L., ed. &lt;em&gt;Approaching Yehud: New Approaches to the Study of the Persian Period&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 50. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Black, Fiona C., editor. &lt;em&gt;The Recycled Bible: Autobiography, Culture, and the Space Betwee&lt;/em&gt;n. Semeia Studies 51. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Blaine, Bradford B. Jr., &lt;em&gt;Peter in the Gospel of John: The Making of an Authentic Disciple&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 27. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Boda, Mark J., Daniel K. Falk, and Rodney A. Werline, eds. &lt;em&gt;Seeking the Favor of God: Volume I, The Origins of Penitential Prayer in Second Temple Judaism.&lt;/em&gt; Early Judaism and Its Literature 21. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Boda, Mark J., Daniel K. Falk, and Rodney A. Werline, eds. &lt;em&gt;Seeking the Favor of God: Volume II, The Development of Penitential Prayer in Second Temple Judaism&lt;/em&gt;. Early Judaism and Its Literature 21. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Boda, Mark J., Daniel K. Falk, and Rodney A. Werline, eds. &lt;em&gt;Seeking the Favor of God: Volume III, The Impact of Penitential Prayer beyond Second Temple Judaism&lt;/em&gt;. Early Judaism and Its Literature 23. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bodi, Daniel. &lt;em&gt;The Michal Affair: From Zimri-Lim to the Rabbis&lt;/em&gt;. Hebrew Monographs 3. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bodine, Walter. &lt;em&gt;Discourse&amp;nbsp; Analysis of Biblical Literature: What it Is and What it Offers&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 27. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1995.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Bodner, Keith. &lt;em&gt;1 Samuel: A Narrative Commentary&lt;/em&gt;. Hebrew Bible Monographs 19. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Bodner, Keith. &lt;em&gt;David Observed: A King in the Eyes of his Court&lt;/em&gt;. Hebrew Bible Monographs 5. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Boer, Roland. &lt;em&gt;Rescuing the Bible.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Oxford: Blackwell Publishing Ltd.,&amp;nbsp;2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Boer, Roland, ed. &lt;em&gt;Bakhtin and Genre Theory in Biblical Studies&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 63. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Boer, Roland. &lt;em&gt;Last Stop before Antarctica, Second Edition&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 64. Atlanta: Society of&amp;nbsp; Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Boer, Roland and Jorunn Økland, eds. &lt;em&gt;Marxist Feminist Criticism of the Bible&lt;/em&gt;. Bible in the Modern World 14. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Bons, Eberhard and Jan  Joosten, editors. Septuagint and Cognate Studies 58. &lt;em&gt;Septuagint Vocabulary, Pre-History, Usage, Reception.&lt;/em&gt; Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011. (224 pages, 1.41 MB) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Borowski, Oded. &lt;em&gt;Daily Life in Biblical Times&lt;/em&gt;. Archaeology and Biblical Studies 5. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Bosworth, David A. &lt;em&gt;The Story within a Story in Biblical Hebrew Narrative&lt;/em&gt;. CBQ Monograph Series 45. Washington, DC: Catholic Biblical Association of America, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Botta, Alejandro F. and Pablo R. Andiñach, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Bible and the Hermeneutics of Liberation&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 59. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Brant, Jo-Ann A., Charles W. Hedrick, and Chris Shea, eds., &lt;em&gt;Ancient Fiction: The Matrix of Early Christian and Jewish Narrative&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 32. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Brenner, Athalya and Frank H. Polak, eds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Performing Memory in Biblical Narrative and Beyond&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;The Bible in the Modern World, 25.&amp;nbsp;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press,&amp;nbsp;2009. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Brett, Mark G. &lt;em&gt;Decolonizing God: The Bible in the Tides of Empire&lt;/em&gt;. Bible in the Modern World 16. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Brighton, Mark Andrew. &lt;em&gt;The Sicarii in Josephus's Judean War: Rhetorical Analysis and Historical Observations&lt;/em&gt;. Early Judaism and Its Literature 27. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Broadhead, Edwin K. &lt;em&gt;Mark, Second Edition&lt;/em&gt;. Readings: A New Biblical Commentary. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Brodd, Jeffrey and Jonathan I. Reed, eds. &lt;em&gt;Rome and Religion: A Cross-Disciplinary Dialogue on the Imperial Cult.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Writings from the Greco-Roman World Supplement Series, 5. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Brueggemann, Walter and Tod Linafelt.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;An Introduction to the Old Testament: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Canon and Christian Imagination, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Second Edition.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Louisville: Westminster John Knox, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Buchan, Thomas. &lt;em&gt;Blessed is He who has brought Adam from Sheol: Christ's Descent to the Dead in the Theology of Saint Ephrem the Syrian&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Dissertations in Early Christianity 13, ECS 2, 2004&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Burkett, Delbert. &lt;em&gt;Rethinking the Gospel Sources, Volume 2: The Unity and Plurality of Q&lt;/em&gt;. Early Christianity and Its Literature 1. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Buss, Martin J. &lt;em&gt;The Concept of Form in the Twentieth Century.&lt;/em&gt; Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Buss,Martin J.&lt;em&gt;The Changing Shape of Form Criticism: A Relational Approach. &lt;/em&gt;Hebrew Bible Monographs 18. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2010 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Byron, John&lt;em&gt;. Recent Research on Paul and Slavery&lt;/em&gt;. Recent Research in Biblical Studies 3. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Calvert-Koyzis, Nancy and Heather E. Weir, eds. &lt;em&gt;Strangely Familiar: Protofeminist Interpretations of Patriarchal Biblical Texts&lt;/em&gt;. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Cameron, Ron and Merrill P. Miller, eds. &lt;em&gt;Redescribing Christian Origins&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 28. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Cameron, Ron and Merrill P. Miller, eds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Redescribing Paul and the Corinthians.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Early Christianity and Its Literature, 5.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Campbell, John Cecelia. &lt;em&gt;Kinship Relations in the Gospel of John&lt;/em&gt;. Catholic Biblical Quarterly Monograph Series 42. Washington, DC: The Catholic Biblical Association of America, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Campbell, William Sanger. &lt;em&gt;The “We” Passages in the Acts of the Apostles: The Narrator as Narrative Character&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Biblical Literature 14. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Chase, Frederic Henry.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Lord’s Prayer in the Early Church.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Text and Studies Vol 1, No. 3.&amp;nbsp;Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Press, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Cho, Sukmin. &lt;em&gt;Jesus as Prophet in the Fourth Gospel&lt;/em&gt;. New Testament Monographs 15. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Clarke, Emma C., John M. Dillon, and Jackson P. Hershbell, eds., Iamblichus: &lt;em&gt;On the Mysteries&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 4. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Clifford, Richard J., ed. &lt;em&gt;Wisdom Literature in Mesopotamia and Israel&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 36. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Cohen, Shaye J. D. &lt;em&gt;The Jewish Family in Antiquity&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 289. Atlanta: Scholars Press for Brown Judaic Studies, 1993.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Collins, John J. &lt;em&gt;Introduction to the Hebrew Bible.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Minneapolis: Fortress Press, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Coloe, Mary L. and Tom Thatcher, eds. &lt;em&gt;John, Qumran, and the Dead Sea Scrolls: Sixty Years of Discovery and Debate. &lt;/em&gt;Early Judaism and Its Literature 32. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Cook, Stephen L. &lt;em&gt;The Social Roots of Biblical Yahwism&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Biblical Literature 8. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Cook, Stephen L. and Corrine L. Patton, eds., &lt;em&gt;Ezekiel’s Hierarchical World: Wrestlingwith a Tiered Reality. &lt;/em&gt;Symposium 31. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Corley, Jeremy. &lt;em&gt;Ben Sira’s Teaching on Friendship&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 316. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Corley, Jeremy and Vincent Skemp, eds. &lt;em&gt;Intertextual Studies in Ben Sira and Tobit: Essays in Honor of Alexander A. Di Lella, O.F.M&lt;/em&gt;. Catholic Biblical Quarterly Monograph Series 38.&amp;nbsp;Washington, DC: Catholic Biblical Association of America, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Corley, Jeremy and Vincent Skemp, eds. &lt;em&gt;Studies in the Greek Bible: Essays in Honor of Francis T. Gignac, S.J.&lt;/em&gt; Catholic Biblical Quarterly Monograph Series 44. Washington, DC: Catholic Biblical Association of America, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Cosaert, Carl P.; &lt;em&gt;The Text of the Gospels in Clement of Alexandria.&lt;/em&gt; New Testament in the Greek Fathers, 9.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Culbertson, Philip and Elain M. Wainwright, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Bible in/and Popular Culture: A Creative Encounter&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 65. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Culy, Martin M. &lt;em&gt;1, 2, 3, John: A Handbook on the Greek Text&lt;/em&gt;. Baylor Handbook on the Greek New Testament. Waco: Baylor University Press, 2004. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Culy, Martin M., Mikeal C. Parsons, and Joshua J. Stigall. &lt;em&gt;Luke: A Handbook on the Greek Text&lt;/em&gt;. Baylor Handbook on the Greek New Testament. Waco: Baylor University Press, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Curtis, Byron G. &lt;em&gt;Up the Steep and Stony Road: The Book of Zechariah in Social Location Trajectory Analysis&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblical 25. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Cosaert, Carl P. &lt;em&gt;The Text of the Gospels in Clement of Alexandria&lt;/em&gt;. New Testament in the Greek Fathers 9. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;De Troyer, Kristin. &lt;em&gt;Rewriting the Sacred Text: What the Old Greek Texts Tell Us about the Literary Growth of the Bible&lt;/em&gt;. Text-Critical Studies 4. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;De Troyer, Kristin and Armin Lange, eds. &lt;em&gt;Reading the Present in the Qumran Library: The Perception of the Contemporary by Means of Spiritual Interpretation&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 30. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;DeConick, April D. ed. &lt;em&gt;Paradise Now: Essays on Early Jewish and Christian Mysticism&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 11. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;De Groot, Christiana and Marion Ann Taylor, eds. &lt;em&gt;Recovering Nineteenth-Century Women Interpreters of the Bible&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 38. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;deSilva, David Arthur. &lt;em&gt;Despising Shame: Honor Discourse and Community Maintenance in the Epistle to the Hebrews&lt;/em&gt;, Second Edition. Studies in Biblical Literature 21. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dell, Katharine. &lt;em&gt;Opening the Old Testament. &lt;/em&gt;Oxford: Wiley-Blackwell, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Dietrich, Walter, Joachim Vette, trans. T&lt;em&gt;he Early Monarchy in Israel: The Tenth Century B.C.E&lt;/em&gt;. Biblical Encyclopedia 3. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: black;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Dillon, John M. and Wolfgang Polleichtner, eds. Iamblichus of Chalcis:&lt;em&gt; The Letters&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 19. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Donker, Gerald J., &lt;em&gt;The Text of the Apostolos in Athansaium of Alexandria.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;New Testament in the Greek Fathers, 8.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;dl&gt;&lt;dt&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: black;"&gt;Dozeman, Thomas B. and Konrad Schmid, eds. &lt;em&gt;A Farewell to the Yahwist?:The Composition of the Pentateuch in Recent European Interpretation&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 34. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;&lt;/dl&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Dozeman, Thomas B., Thomas Romer and Konrad Schmid, eds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Pentateuch, Hexateuch, or Enneateuch: Identifying Literary Works in Genesis through Kings.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 115%;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Ancient Israel and Its Literature , 8.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: black;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Draper, Jonathan A., ed., &lt;em&gt;Orality and Colonialism in Southern Africa&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 46. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Draper, Jonathan A., &lt;em&gt;Orality, Literacy, and Colonialism in Antiquity. &lt;/em&gt;Semeia Studies 47. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Dubis, Mark. &lt;em&gt;1 Peter: A Handbook on the Greek Text&lt;/em&gt;. Baylor Handbook on the Greek New Testament. Waco: Baylor University Press, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Eastman, David L., &lt;em&gt;Paul the Martyr:&amp;nbsp;The Cult of the Apostle in the Latin West.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp; Writings from the Greco-Roman World Supplement Series 4. &amp;nbsp;Atlanta, Society of Biblical Literature, 2011. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Eberhart, Christian A., ed. &lt;em&gt;Ritual and Metaphor: Sacrifice in the Bible.&lt;/em&gt; &amp;nbsp;Resources for Biblical Study 68.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Edwards, Mark. &lt;em&gt;John.&lt;/em&gt;Blackwell Bible Commentaries. Oxford: Wiley-Blackwell, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Edwards, Timothy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Exegesis in the Targum of Psalms: The Old, the New, and the Rewritten.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;Biblical Studies, 28/1.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Press, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ehrman, Bart D. &lt;em&gt;Didymus the Blind and the Text of the Gospels&lt;/em&gt;. New Testament in the Greek Fathers 1. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1986.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ehrman, Bart D., Gordon D. Fee, Michael W. Holmes, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Text of the Fourth Gospel in the Writings of Origen&lt;/em&gt;. New Testament in the Greek Fathers 3. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1992.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Eichhorn, Albert, translated by Jeffrey F. Cayzer. &lt;em&gt;The Lord’s Supper in the New Testament:&lt;br /&gt;With an Introductory Essay by Hugo Gressmann. Albert Eichhorn and the History of Religion School&lt;/em&gt;. History of Biblical Studies 1. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Elledge, C. D. &lt;em&gt;The Bible and the Dead Sea Scrolls&lt;/em&gt;. Archaeology and Biblical Studies 14. Atlanta; Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ellens, J. Harold. &lt;em&gt;The Son of Man in the Gospel of John. &lt;/em&gt;New Testament Monographs 28. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2010.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Eskenazi, Tamara Cohn, Gary A. Phillips, and David Jobling, eds. &lt;em&gt;Levinas and Biblical Studies&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 43. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Everson, A. Joseph and Kim, Hyun Chul Paul, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Desert will Bloom: Poetic Visions in Isaiah.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp; Ancient Israel and its Literature, Vol. 4. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Exum, J. Cheryl and Ela Nutu, eds. &lt;em&gt;Between the Text and the Canvas: The Bible and Art in Dialogue&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Bible in the Modern World 13. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Faust, Avraham.&amp;nbsp;Judah in the Neo-Babylonian Period: The Archaeology of Desolation. Archaeology and  Biblical Studies, 18.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Feder, Yitzhaq.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Blood Expiation in Hittite and Biblical Ritual: Origins, Context, and Meaning.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;Writings from the Ancient World Supplement Series, 2.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Finkelstein, Israel, and Amihai Mazar. &lt;em&gt;The Quest for the Historical Israel: Debating Archaeology and the History of Early Israel.&lt;/em&gt; Edited by Brian B. Schmidt. Archaeology and Biblical Studies 17. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Finlan, Stephen. &lt;em&gt;The Background and Content of Paul’s Cultic Atonement Metaphors&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 19. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Fischer,&amp;nbsp;Irmtraud and Mercedes Navarro Puerto, with Andrea Taschl-Erber, eds. &lt;em&gt;Torah.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;The Bible and Women: Hebrew Bible/Old Testament 1.1.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Fitzgerald, John T., Fika J. van Rensburg, and Herrie F. van Rooy, eds. &lt;em&gt;Animosity, the Bible, and Us: Some European, North American, and South African Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Global Perspectives on Biblical Scholarship 12. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fitzpatrick, Paul E., S.M. &lt;em&gt;The Disarmament of God: Ezekiel 38-39 in Its Mythic Context&lt;/em&gt;. Catholic Biblical Quarterly Monograph Series 37.&amp;nbsp; Washington, DC: Catholic Biblical Association of America, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Flannery, Frances, Colleen Shantz, and Rodney A. Werline, eds. &lt;em&gt;Experientia, Volume 1: Inquiry into Religious Experience in Early Judaism and Early Christianity&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 40. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fontaine, Carole R.&lt;em&gt; With Eyes of Flesh&lt;ins cite="mailto:-" datetime="2012-02-09T14:34"&gt;:&lt;/ins&gt;The Bible, Gender and Human Rights&lt;/em&gt;. Bible in the Modern World 10.Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Foster, John L. Hymns, &lt;em&gt;Prayers, and Songs: An Anthology of Ancient Egyptian Lyric Poetry&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 8. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1996.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Fried, Lisbeth S., ed. &lt;em&gt;Was 1 Esdras First? An Investigation into the Priority and Nature of 1 Esdras. &lt;/em&gt;Ancient Israel and Its Literature 7. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Fritz, Volmer. &lt;em&gt;The Emergence of Israel in the Twelfth and Eleventh Centuries B.C.E.&lt;/em&gt; &amp;nbsp;Bible Encyclopedia. &amp;nbsp;Biblical Encyclopedia. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Frood, Elizabeth. &lt;em&gt;Biographical Texts from Ramessid Egypt&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 26. Atlanta: Society of&amp;nbsp; Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Fuller Dow, Lois K. &lt;em&gt;Images of Zion: Biblical Antecedents for the New Jerusalem. &lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;New Testament Monographs 26. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2010. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gaines, Janet Howe. &lt;em&gt;Forgiveness in a Wounded World: Jonah’s Dilemma&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Biblical Literature 5. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Garrett, Duane A. &lt;em&gt;Amos: A Handbook on the Hebrew Text&lt;/em&gt;. Baylor Handbook on the Hebrew Bible. Waco: Baylor University Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Geoghegan, Jeffrey C. &lt;em&gt;The Time, Place and Purpose of the Deuteronomistic History: The Evidence of “Until This Day.”&lt;/em&gt; Brown Judaic Studies 347. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Georgi, Dieter. &lt;em&gt;The City in the Valley: Biblical Interpretation and Urban Theology. &lt;/em&gt;Studies in Biblical Literature 7. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Gentry, Peter John. &lt;em&gt;The Asterisked Materials in the Greek Job&lt;/em&gt;. Septuagint and Cognate Studies 38. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 1995.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Gerstenbeger, Erhard S. &lt;em&gt;Israel in the Persian Period: The Fifth and Fourth Centuries B.C.E.&lt;/em&gt; Biblical Encyclopedia, 8. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Gibson, Craig A., Translator.&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Libanius’s Progymnasmata: Model Exercises in Greek Prose Composition and Rhetoric &lt;/em&gt;(with an Introduction and Notes). Writings from the Greco-Roman World 27. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Glassner, Jean-Jacques. &lt;em&gt;Mesopotamian Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 19. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gordon, Cyrus H. &lt;em&gt;A Scholar’s Odyssey&lt;/em&gt;. Biblical Scholarship in North America 20. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Gordon, Robert P. &lt;em&gt;Hebrews. Readings, A New Biblical Commentary&lt;/em&gt;. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Goulder, Michael. &lt;em&gt;Five Stones and a Sling: Memoirs of a Biblical Scholar. &lt;/em&gt;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenis Press, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Grant, Jamie A. &lt;em&gt;The King as Exemplar: The Function of Deuteronomy’s Kingship Law in the Shaping of the Book of Psalms&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 17. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Gravett, Sandra L.; Karla G. Bohmbach; F. V. Greifenhagen and Donald C. Polaski.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;An Introduction to the Hebrew Bible: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Thematic Approach.&lt;/em&gt; Louisville: Westminster John Knox, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Gray, Alyssa M. &lt;em&gt;A Talmud in Exile: The Influence of Yerushalmi Avodah Zarah on the Formation of Bavli Avodah Zarah&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 342. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Green, Barbara. &lt;em&gt;Mikhail Bakhtin and Biblical Scholarship: An Introduction&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 38. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Greenspahn, Frederick E. &lt;em&gt;An Introduction to Aramaic, Corrected Second Edition&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 46. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Greenstein, Edward L. &lt;em&gt;Essays on Biblical Method and Translation&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 92. Missoula, Mont.: Scholars Press for Brown Judaic Studies, 1985.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Greer, Rowan A. and Margaret M. Mitchell, trans. &lt;em&gt;The Belly-Myther of Endor: Interpretations of 1 Kingdoms 28 in the Early Church&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 16. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Habel, Norman C. and Peter Trudinger, eds. &lt;em&gt;Exploring Ecological Hermeneutics&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 46. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Haber, Susan. &lt;em&gt;They Shall Purify Themselves: Essays on Purity in Early Judaism&lt;/em&gt;. Edited by Adele Reinhartz. Early Judaism and Its Literature 24. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hagelia, Hallvard. &lt;em&gt;The Dan Debate. The Tel Dan Inscription in Recent Research.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;Recent Research in Biblical Studies, 4.&amp;nbsp;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hallbäck, Geert;&amp;nbsp;Hvithamar, Annika; Editors. &lt;em&gt;Recent Releases: The Bible in Contemporary Cinema.&lt;/em&gt; Bible in the Modern World, 15. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ham, Clay Alan. &lt;em&gt;The Coming King and the Rejected Shepherd: Matthew’s Reading of Zechariah’s Messianic Hope&lt;/em&gt;. New Testament Monographs 4. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hamilton, Gordon J. &lt;em&gt;The Origins of the West Semetic Alphabet in Egyptian Scripts&lt;/em&gt;. Catholic Biblical Quarterly Monograph Series 40. Washington, DC: Catholic Biblical Association of America, 2006. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hanneken, Todd R., &lt;em&gt;The Subversion of the Apocalypses in the Book of Jubilees.&lt;/em&gt; Early Judaism and Its Literature, Number 34.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Harrak, Amir, trans. &lt;em&gt;The Acts of Ma˜r Ma˜ri ˜ the Apostle&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 11. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hauser, Alan J., &lt;em&gt;Recent Research on the Major Prophets&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Recent Research in Biblical Studies 1. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Harris, Robert A. &lt;em&gt;Discerning Parallelism: A Study in Northern French Medieval Jewish Biblical Exegesis&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 341. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2005. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Havea, Jione. &lt;em&gt;Elusions of Control: Biblical Law on the Words of Women&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 41. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hawkins, Peter S. and Lesleigh Cushing Stahlberg, eds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;From the Margins 1.&amp;nbsp;Women of the Hebrew Bible and their Afterlives.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Bible in the Modern World, 18. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hayes, Katherine M. &lt;em&gt;The Earth Mourns: Prophetic Metaphor and Oral Aesthetic&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 8. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Heil, John Paul, &lt;em&gt;The Rhetorical Role of Scripture in 1 Corinthians&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Biblical Literature 15. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Heil, John Paul. &lt;em&gt;Ephesians: Empowerment to Walk in Love for the Unity of All in Christ&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Biblical Literature 13. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Heil, John Paul. &lt;em&gt;Colossians: Encouragement to Walk in All Wisdom as Holy Ones in Christ&lt;/em&gt;. Early Christianity and Its Literature 4. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Heil, John Paul. &lt;em&gt;Hebrews: Chiastic Structures and Audience Response&lt;/em&gt;. Catholic Bibilical Quarterly Monograph Series 46. Washington, DC: Catholic Biblical Association of America, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Heil, John Paul. &lt;em&gt;Philippians: Let Us Rejoice in Being Conformed to Christ&lt;/em&gt;. Early Christianity and Its Literature 3. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Helmer, Christine, ed., with the assistance of Charlene T. Higbe. &lt;em&gt;The Multivalence of Biblical Texts and Theological Meanings&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 37. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Helmer, Christine, ed., with the assistance of Taylor G. Petrey. &lt;em&gt;Biblical Interpretation: History, Context, and Reality&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 26. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Henze, Matthias.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Hazon Gabriel: New Reading of the Gabriel Revelation.&lt;/em&gt; Early Judiaism and Its Literature, 29. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Herzer, Jens, trans. &lt;em&gt;4 Baruch (Paraleipomena Jeremiou)&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 22. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hidary, Richard. &lt;em&gt;Dispute for the Sake of Heaven: Legal Pluralism in the Talmud&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 351. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hiebert, Robert J. V., ed. &lt;em&gt;Translation Is Required: The Septuagint in Retrospect and Prospec&lt;/em&gt;t. Septuagint and Cognate Studies 56. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hill, Robert C., trans. Diodore of Tarsus: &lt;em&gt;Commentary on Psalms 1–51&lt;/em&gt;,  with an Introduction and Notes by Robert C. Hill. Writings from the  Greco-Roman World 9. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hill, Robert C., trans. &lt;em&gt;Theodoret of Cyrus: Commentary on Daniel&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 7. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hock, Ronald F. and Edward N. O’Neil, trans and eds. &lt;em&gt;The Chreia and Ancient Rhetoric: Classroom Exercises&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the&amp;nbsp; Greco-Roman World 2. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hoffner, Harry A., Jr. &lt;em&gt;Hittite Myths&lt;/em&gt;: Second Edition. Writings from the Ancient World 2. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 1998.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hoffner, Harry A., Jr. &lt;em&gt;Akkadian Grammar&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 30. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1992.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hoffner, Harry A., Jr. &lt;em&gt;Letters from the Hittite Kingdom&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 15. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Holmstedt, Robert D. &lt;em&gt;Ruth: A Handbook on the Hebrew Text&lt;/em&gt;. Baylor Handbook on the Hebrew Bible. Waco: Baylor University Press, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Horn, Cornelia B. and Robert R. Phenix Jr., trans. with Introduction and notes. &lt;em&gt;John Rufus: The Lives of Peter the Iberian, Theodosius of Jerusalem, and the Monk Romanus&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 24. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Hornsby, Teresa J. and Ken Stone, eds. &lt;em&gt;Bible Trouble: Queer Reading at the Boundaries of Biblical Scholarship. &lt;/em&gt;Semeia Studies 67. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Horsley, Richard A., ed. &lt;em&gt;Hidden Transcripts and the Arts of Resistance: Applying the Work of James C. Scott to Jesus and Paul&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 48. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Horsley, Richard A., ed. &lt;em&gt;Oral Performance, Popular Tradition, and Hidden Transcript in Q&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 60. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hull, Michael F. &lt;em&gt;Baptism on Account of the Dead (1 Cor 15:29): An Act of Faith in the Resurrection&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 22. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hull Jr., Robert F. &lt;em&gt;The Story of the New Testament Text: Movers, Movers, Materials, Motives, Methods, and Models.&lt;/em&gt; Resources for Biblical Study 58. Atlanta, Society of Biblical Literature, 2010. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Hurtado, Larry W., ed. &lt;em&gt;The Freer Biblical Manuscripst: Fresh Studies of an American Treasure Trove&lt;/em&gt;. Text-Critical Studies 6. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Isser, Stanley. &lt;em&gt;The Sword of Goliath: David in Heroic Literature&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Biblical Literature 6. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Iverson, Kelly R. and Skinner, Christopher W. Editors. &lt;em&gt;MARK AS STORY:&amp;nbsp;Retrospect and Prospect.&lt;/em&gt; Resources for Biblical Study, 65.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature. (322 pages, 1.89MB)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Jarick, John. &lt;em&gt;1 Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Readings: A New Biblcial Commentary&lt;/em&gt;. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Jarick, John. &lt;em&gt;2 Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;em&gt; Readings: A New Biblical Commentary.&lt;/em&gt; Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Johnson, Timothy Jay.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Now My Eyes See You: Unveiling an Apocalyptic Job.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;Hebrew Bible Monographs, 24.&amp;nbsp;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Jones, F. Stanley. &lt;em&gt;An Ancient Jewish Christian Source on the History of Christianity: Pseudo-Clementine&lt;/em&gt; Recognitions &lt;em&gt;1. 27-71&lt;/em&gt;. Texts and Translations 37. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 1995. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Jones, F. Stanley, ed. &lt;em&gt;Which Mary?: The Marys of Early Christian Tradition. &lt;/em&gt;Symposium 19. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Jones, F. Stanley, ed. &lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;The Rediscovery of Jewish Christianity: From Toland to Baur.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;History of Biblical Studies, 5.&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Joynes, Christine E. and Christopher C. Rowland, eds. &lt;em&gt;From the Margins 2: Women of the New Testament and Their Afterlives. &lt;/em&gt;Bible in the Modern World 27. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kaltner, John and Steven L. McKenzie, eds. &lt;em&gt;Beyond Babel: A Handbook for Biblical Hebrew and Related Languages&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 42. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature 2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kannaday, Wayne C. &lt;em&gt;Apologetic Discourse and the Scribal Tradition:  Evidence of the Influence of Apologetic Interests on the Text of the  Canonical Gospels&lt;/em&gt;. Text-Critical Studies 5. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kaplan, Zvi Jonathan. &lt;em&gt;Between the Devil and the Deep Blue Sea: French Jewry and the Problem of the Church and State&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 352. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2009. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kelle, Brad E. &lt;em&gt;Hosea 2: Metaphor and Rhetoric in Historical Perspective.&lt;/em&gt; Academia Biblica 20. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Kelle, Brad E. and Frank Ritchel Ames, eds. &lt;em&gt;Writing and Reading War: Rhetoric, Gender, and Ethics in Biblical and Modern Contexts&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 42. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0.0001pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Kelle , Brad E., Frank Ritchel Ames, and Jacob Wright, eds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Interpreting Exile: Displacement and Deportation in Biblical and Modern Contexts.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ancient Israel and Its Literature, 10. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Kennedy, George A. &lt;em&gt;Invention and Method: Two Rhetorical Treatises from the Hermogenic Corpus. &lt;/em&gt;Writings from the Greco-Roman World 15. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kennedy, George A. &lt;em&gt;Progymnasmata: Greek Textbooks of Prose Composition and Rhetoric&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman&amp;nbsp;World 10. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Killebrew, Ann E. &lt;em&gt;Biblical Peoples and Ethnicity: An Archaeological Study of Egyptians, Canaanites, Philistines, and Early Israel 1300–1100 B.C.E.&lt;/em&gt; Archaeology and Biblical Studies 9. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Kim, Seong Hee. &lt;em&gt;Mark, Women and Empire: A Korean Postcolonial Perspective. &lt;/em&gt;Bible in the Modern World 20. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kim, Uriah Y. &lt;em&gt;Decolonizing Josiah: Toward a Postcolonial Reading of Deuteronomistic History&lt;/em&gt;. The Bible in the Modern World 5. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Kim, Uriah Y. &lt;em&gt;Identity and Loyalty in the David Story: A Postcolonial Reading .&lt;/em&gt;Hebrew Bible Monographs 22. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Kinlaw, Pamela E. &lt;em&gt;The Christ Is Jesus: Metamorphosis, Possession, and Johannine Christology&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 18. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kirk, Alan and Tom Thatcher, eds. &lt;em&gt;Memory, Tradition, and Text: Uses of the Past in Early Christianity&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 52. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Kirk-Duggan, Cheryl A., ed. &lt;em&gt;Pregnant Passion: Gender, Sex, and Violence in the Bible&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 44. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Kirk-Duggan, Cheryl A. and Tina Pippin, eds. &lt;em&gt;Mother Goose, Mother Jones, Mommie Dearest: Biblical Mothers and Their Children&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 61. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Knight, Douglas A. &lt;em&gt;Rediscovering the Traditions of Israel&lt;/em&gt;, Third Edition. Studies in Biblical Literature 16. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Knowles, Melody D. &lt;em&gt;Centrality Practiced: Jerusalem in the Religious Practice of Yehud and the Diaspora in the Persian Period&lt;/em&gt;. Archaeology and Biblical Studies 16. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Konstan, David, Clay Diskin, Clarence E. Glad, Johan C. Thom, and James Ware, trans. Philodemus: &lt;em&gt;On Frank Criticism&lt;/em&gt;. Texts and Translations 43. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1998.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Kloppenborg, John S. and Judith H. Newman, eds.&lt;em&gt; Editing the Bible: Assessing the Task Past and Present&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Resources for the Biblical Study, number 69.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Koskenniemi, Erkki, &lt;em&gt;The Exposure of Infants among Jews and Christians in Antiguity.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp; The Social World of Biblical Antiquity, Second Series, 4.; Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: black;"&gt;Kraus, Wolfgang and R. Glenn Wooden, eds. &lt;em&gt;Septuagint Research: Issues and Challenges in the Study of the Greek Jewish Scriptures.&lt;/em&gt; Septuagint and Cognate Studies 53. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Krietzer, Larry J. &lt;em&gt;Philemon&lt;/em&gt;. Readings: A New Biblical Commentary. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: black;"&gt;Kulik, Alexander. &lt;em&gt;Retroverting Slavonic Pseudepigrapha: Toward the Original of the Apocalypse of Abraham&lt;/em&gt;. Text-Critical Studies 3. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Landes, George M. &lt;em&gt;Building Your Biblical Hebrew Vocabulary: Learning Words by Frequency and Cognate. &lt;/em&gt;Resources for Biblical Study 41. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2001. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Langston, Scott M&lt;em&gt;. Exodus Through the Centuries.&lt;/em&gt; Blackwell Bible Commentaries. Oxford: Wiley-Blackwell, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Larkin, William J. &lt;em&gt;Ephesians: A Handbook on the Greek Text. &lt;/em&gt;Baylor Handbook on the Greek New Testament. Waco: Baylor University Press, 2009.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Lasine, Stuart. &lt;em&gt;Knowing Kings: Knowledge, Power, and Narcissism in the Hebrew Bible&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Semeia Studies 40. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2001.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lawrence, Jonathan David. &lt;em&gt;Washing in Water: Trajectories of Ritual Bathing in the Hebrew Bible and Second Temple Literature&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 23. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lee, Bernon P&lt;em&gt;., Between Law and Narrative:&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;The Method and Function of Abstraction.&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Gorgias Biblical Studies&amp;nbsp;51.&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Press, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lee, Nancy C. and Carleen Mandolfo, eds. &lt;em&gt;Lamentations in Ancient and Contemporary Cultural Contexts&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 43. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;LeMon, Joel M. and Kent Harold Richards, eds. &lt;em&gt;Method Matters: Essays on the Interpretation of the Hebrew Bible in Honor of David L. Petersen&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 56.&amp;nbsp; Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Leuchter, Mark. &lt;em&gt;Josiah's Reform and Jeremiah's Scroll: Historical Calamity and Prophetic Response&lt;/em&gt;. Hebrew Bible Monographs 6. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Leuchter, Mark A.&amp;nbsp;and Jeremy M. Hutton. eds. &lt;em&gt;Levites and Priests in History and Tradition.&lt;/em&gt; Ancient Israel and Its Literature Number 9.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Liew,Tat-siong Benny, ed.&amp;nbsp; &lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Postcolonial Interventions: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Essays in Honor of R. S. Sugirtharajah.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bible in the Modern World&lt;/span&gt;, 23.&amp;nbsp;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lindenberger, James M., &lt;em&gt;Ancient Aramaic and Hebrew Letters, &lt;/em&gt;Second Edition&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;Writings from the Ancient World 14. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lipton, Diana.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt; Longing for Egypt and Other Unexpected Biblical Tales&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp; Hebrew Bible Monographs, 15.&amp;nbsp; Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lipton, Diana&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Universalism and Particularism at Sodom and Gomorrah: Essays in Memory of Ron Pirson.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Ancient Israel and Its Literature, Number 11.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lombaard, Christo.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Old Testament and Christian Spirituality: Theoretical and Practical Essays from a South African Perspective.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;International Voices in Biblical Literature, 2.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Long, Adrian.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Paul and Human Rights: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Dialogue with the Father of the Corinthian Community&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;The Bible in the Modern World, 26.&amp;nbsp;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press,&amp;nbsp;2009. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Louw, J. P. &lt;em&gt;Semantics of New Testament Greek&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 11. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1982.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Louw, Johannes P. and Eugene A. Nida. &lt;em&gt;Lexical Semantics of the Greek New Testament&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 25. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1992. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lozada Jr., Francisco. and Tom Thatcher, eds. &lt;em&gt;New Currents through John: A Global Perspective&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 54. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lubetski, Meir, ed. &lt;em&gt;New Seals and Inscriptions, Hebrew, Idumean, and Cuneiform&lt;/em&gt;. Hebrew Bible Monographs 8. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2007. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lyons, William John; Økland , Jorunn; eds. &lt;em&gt;The Way the World Ends? &lt;/em&gt;The Bible in the Modern World, 19. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;McGinnis, Claire Mathews and Patricia K. Tull, eds. &lt;em&gt;As Those Who Are Taught:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; The Interpretation of Isaiah from the LXX to the SBL&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 27. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;McGowan, Andrew B. and Kent Harold Richards, eds. &lt;em&gt;Method and Meaning:Essays on New Testament Interpretation in Honor of Harold W. Attridge. &lt;/em&gt;Resources for Biblical Study 67. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;McIver, Robert K.; &lt;em&gt;Memory, Jesus, and the Synoptic Gospels.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Resources for Biblical Study, 59.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Maclean, Jennifer K. Berenson and Ellen Bradshaw Aitken, trans. Flavius Philostratus: &lt;em&gt;Heroikos&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 1. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2001.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Maclean, Jennifer K. Berenson and Ellen Bradshaw Aitken, trans and eds. &lt;em&gt;Flavius Philostratus: On Heroes&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 3. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;MacDonald, Dennis R., &lt;em&gt;Two Shipwrecked Gospels: The Logoi of Jesus and Papias’s Exposition of Logia about the Lord&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: MinionPro-Regular;"&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Early Christianity and Its Literature, number 8.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literaure, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Maidman, Maynard Paul. &lt;em&gt;Nuzi Texts and Their Uses as Historical Evidence&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 18. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Mandolfo, Carleen R. &lt;em&gt;Daughter Zion Talks Back to the Prophets: A Dialogic Theology of the Book of Lamentations&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 58. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Marchal, Joseph A. &lt;em&gt;Hierarchy, Unity, and Imitation: A Feminist Rhetorical Analysis of Power Dynamics in Paul's Letter to the Philippians&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 24.&amp;nbsp; Atlanta: Society of&amp;nbsp; Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Martin, Gary A. &lt;em&gt;Multiple Originals: New Approaches to Hebrew Bible Textual Criticism&lt;/em&gt;. Text-Critical Studies 7. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Martin, Michael W., &lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Judas&lt;em&gt;and the Rhetoric of Comparison in the Fourth Gospel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class="large-text-red"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; line-height: 115%;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;New Testament Monographs, 25. &lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Mason, Eric F. and Kevin B. McCruden, eds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Reading the Epistles to the Hebrews.&amp;nbsp;A Resource for Students.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Resources for Biblical Study, 66.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Miano, David. &lt;em&gt;Shadow on the Steps: Time Measurement in Ancient Israel&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 64. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Miller, Patrick D., Jr. &lt;em&gt;The Divine Warrior in Early Israel&lt;/em&gt;. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006 (Originally published by the President and Fellows of Harvard College, 1973). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Miller, Patrick and J. J. M. Roberts. &lt;em&gt;The Hand of the Lord: A Reassessment of the Ark Narrative of 1 Samuel&lt;/em&gt;. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008. (Originally published by Johns Hopkins University Press, 1977). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Miscall, Peter. &lt;em&gt;Isaiah&lt;/em&gt;. Readings: A New Biblical Commentary.&amp;nbsp;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Moore, Stephen D. &lt;em&gt;The Bible in Theory: Critical and Postcritical Essays&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 57. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Moore, Stephen D. &lt;em&gt;Empire and Apocalypse: Postcolonialism and the New Testament&lt;/em&gt;. Bible in the Modern World 12. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Moore, Stephen D. and Janice Capel Anderson, eds. &lt;em&gt;New Testament Masculinities&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 45. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Moreland, Milton C. &lt;em&gt;Between Text and Artifact: Integrating Archaeology in Biblical Studies Teaching. &lt;/em&gt;Archaeology and Biblical Studies 8. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Moser, Maureen. &lt;em&gt;Teacher of Holiness: The Holy Spirit in Origen's Commentary on the Epistle to the Romans&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Dissertations in Early Christianity 117, ECS 4, 2005. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Murnane, William J. &lt;em&gt;Texts from the Amarna Period in Egypt&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 5. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1995.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Mykytiuk, Lawrence J. &lt;em&gt;Identifying Biblical Persons in Northwest Semitic. &lt;/em&gt;Academia Biblica 12. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote class="webkit-indent-blockquote" style="margin: 0px 0px 0px 40px; padding: 0px;"&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;See also: Lawrence J. Mykytiuk, Corrections and Updates  to Identifying Biblical Persons in Northwest Semitic Inscriptions of  1200-539 B.C.E. Maarav 16.1 (2009): 49-132. This complete article is  available without cost at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://docs.lib.purdue.edu/lib_research/129/" target="_blank"&gt;http://docs.lib.purdue.edu/lib_research/129/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Neufeld, Dietmar, ed. &lt;em&gt;The Social Sciences and Biblical Translation&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 41. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nir, Rivka. &lt;em&gt;The Destruction of Jerusalem and the Idea of Redemption in the Syriac Apocalypse of Baruch&lt;/em&gt;. Early Judaism and Its Literature 20. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nissinen, Martti, ed. &lt;em&gt;Prophecy in Its Ancient Near Eastern Context Mesopotamian, Biblical, and Arabian Perspectives&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 13. Atlanta: Society of&amp;nbsp; Biblical Literature, 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nissinen, Martti. &lt;em&gt;Prophets and Prophecy in the Ancient Near East. &lt;/em&gt;Writings from the Ancient World 12. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Noegel, Scott B. and Gary A. Rendsburg. &lt;em&gt;Solomon's Vineyard: Literary and Linguistic Studies in the Song of Songs&lt;/em&gt;. Ancient Israel and Its Literature 1. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nogalski . James D. and Marvin A. Sweeney, eds. &lt;em&gt;Reading and Hearing the Book of the Twelve&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 15. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;O’Brien, Julia M. &lt;em&gt;Nahum (Second Edition)&lt;/em&gt;. Readings: A New Biblical Commentary; Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ogden, Graham S. &lt;em&gt;Qoheleth&lt;/em&gt;. 2d ed. Readings: A New Biblical Commentary. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;O'Hare, Daniel M. &lt;em&gt;Have You Seen, Son of Man?: A Study in the Translation and Vorlage of LXX Ezekiel 40-48&lt;/em&gt;. Septuagint and Cognate Studies 57. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Olyan, Saul M., editor. &lt;em&gt;Social Theory and the Study of Israelite Religion: Essays in Retrospect and Prospect&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Resources for Biblical Study, number 71.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Osburn, Carroll D. &lt;em&gt;The Text of the Apostolos in Epiphanius of Salamis&lt;/em&gt;. New Testament in the Greek Fathers 6. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Parker, Simon. ed. &lt;em&gt;Ugaritic Narrative Poetry&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 9. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 1997.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Pardee, Dennis. &lt;em&gt;Ritual and Cult at Ugarit&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 10. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Payne, Annick. &lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Iron Age Hieroglyphic Luwian Inscriptions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;Writings from the Ancient World, 29.&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Penner, Todd and Caroline Vander Stichele, eds. &lt;em&gt;Contextualizing Acts: Lukan Narrative and Greco-Roman Discourse&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 20. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style="line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Perdue, Leo G. ed., &amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Blackwell Companion to the Hebrew Bible.&lt;/em&gt; Oxford: Wiley-Blackwell, 2001.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Person, Raymond F., Jr. &lt;em&gt;The Deuteronomic School: History, Social Setting, and Literature&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Biblical Literature 2. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2002. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Person, Raymond F., Jr. &lt;em&gt;The Deuteronomic History and the Book of Chronicles: Scribal Works in an Oral World&lt;/em&gt;. Ancient Israel and Its Literature 6. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Peters, Dorothy M. &lt;em&gt;Noah Traditions in the Dead Sea Scrolls: Conversations and Controversies of Antiquity&lt;/em&gt;. Early Judaism and Its Literature 26. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Peters, Melvin K. H., ed. &lt;em&gt;XII Congress of the International Organization for Septuagint and Cognate Studies&lt;/em&gt;, Leiden, 2004. Septuagint and Cognate Studies 54. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Peters, Melvin K. H., ed. &lt;em&gt;XIII Congress of the International Organization for Septuagint and Cognate Studies&lt;/em&gt;, Ljubljana, 2007. Septuagint and Cognate Studies 55. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Petersen, David L. &lt;em&gt;Late Israelite Prophecy: Studies in Deutero-Prophetic Literature and in Chronicles&lt;/em&gt;. Monograph 23. Missoula, Mont.: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1977.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Pitkänen, Pekka. &lt;em&gt;Central Sanctuary and Centralization of Worship in Ancient Israel: From the Settlement to the Building of Solomon's Temple&lt;/em&gt;. Gorgias Dissertations 16: Near Eastern Studies, Vol. 4. Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Press, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Porter, Stanley E. and Christopher D. Stanley, eds. &lt;em&gt;As It Is Written: Studying Paul’s Use of Scripture&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 50. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Porter, Stanley E. and Matthew Brook O’Donnell, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Linguist as Pedagogue: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trends in the Teaching and Linguistic Analysis of the Greek New Testament.&lt;/em&gt; New Testament Monographs, 11. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Pyper, Hugh S. &lt;em&gt;An Unsuitable Book: The Bible as Scandalous Text&lt;/em&gt;. The Bible in the Modern World 7. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Racine, Jean-François, &lt;em&gt;The Text of Matthew in the Writings of Basil of Caesarea&lt;/em&gt;. New Testament in the Greek Fathers 5. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Ramelli, Ilaria. &lt;em&gt;Hierocles the Stoic: Elements of Ethics, Fragments, and Excerpts&lt;/em&gt;. Translated by David Konstan. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 28. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reeves, John C., ed. &lt;em&gt;Bible and Qur’an: Essays in Scriptural Intertextuality&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 24. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reeves, John C. &lt;em&gt;Trajectories in Near Eastern Apocalyptic: A Postrabbinic Jewish Apocalypse Reader. &lt;/em&gt;Resources for Biblical Study 45. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reventlow, Henning Graf. Trans. by Leo G. Perdue. &lt;em&gt;History of Biblical Interpretation, Volume 1: From the Old Testament to Origen&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 50. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reventlow, Henning Graf. Trans. by James O. Duke. &lt;em&gt;History of Biblical Interpretation, Volume 2: From Late Antiquity to the End of the Middle Ages&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 61. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reventlow, Henning Graf. Trans. by James O. Duke. &lt;em&gt;History of Biblical Interpretation, Volume 3: Renaissance, Reformation, Humanism&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 62. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reventlow, Henning Graf. Trans. by James O. Duke. &lt;em&gt;History of Biblical Interpretation, Volume 4: From the Enlightenment to the Twentieth Century&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 63. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reymond, Eric D. &lt;em&gt;Innovations in Hebrew Poetry: Parallelism and the Poems of Sirach&lt;/em&gt;. Studies in Biblical Literature 9. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Reymond, Eric D. &lt;em&gt;New Idioms within Old: Poetry and Parallelism in the Non-masoretic Poems of 11Q5(=11QPs&lt;sup&gt;A&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;. Early Judiasm and its Literature 31. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rice, David G. and John E. Stambaugh. &lt;em&gt;Sources for the Study of Greek Religion&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 14. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 1979.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Richey, Lance Byron. &lt;em&gt;Roman Imperial Ideology and the Gospel of John&lt;/em&gt;. Catholic Biblical Quarterly Monograph Series 42. Washington, DC: Catholic Biblical Association of America, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Rindge, Matthew S.&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Jesus’ Parable of the Rich  Fool.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/em&gt;Early Christianity and Its Literature, 6.  Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ritner, Robert K, trans. &lt;em&gt;The Libyan Anarchy: Inscriptions from Egypt's Third Intermediate Period&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 21. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Rollston, Christopher A. &lt;em&gt;Writing and Literacy in the World of Ancient Israel: Epigraphic Evidence from the Iron Age&lt;/em&gt;. Archaeology and Biblical Studies 11. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Roncace, Mark and Patrick Gray, eds. &lt;em&gt;Teaching the Bible: Practical Strategies for Classroom Instruction&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 49. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Roncace, Mark and Patrick Gray, eds. &lt;em&gt;Teaching the Bible through Popular Culture and the Arts&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 53. Atlanta: Society of&amp;nbsp; Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Rooke, Deborah W., ed. &lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Embroidered Garments: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Priests and Gender in Biblical Israel.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class="standard-text-red"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;; line-height: 115%;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Hebrew Bible Monographs, 25.&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Roth, Martha T. &lt;em&gt;Law Collections from Mesopotamia and Asia Minor: Second Edition&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 6. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the&amp;nbsp; Society of Biblical Literature, 1997.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Rowland, Christopher andChristopher Tuckett, eds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Nature of New Testament Theology: Essays in Honour of Robert Morgan.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Oxford: Blackwell Publishing Ltd., 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Runia, David T. and Gregory E. Sterling, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Studia Philonica Annual: Studies in Hellenistic Judaism, Volume XVII (2005)&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 344. Providence, Brown Judaic Studies, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Runia, David&amp;nbsp;T. and Gregory&amp;nbsp;E. Sterling, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Studia Philonica Annual: Studies in Hellenistic Judaism, Volume XVIII (2006). &lt;/em&gt;Studia Philonica Annual 18. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Runia, David T. and Gregory E. Sterling, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Studia Philonica Annual: Studies in Hellenistic Judaism, Volume XIX (2007)&lt;/em&gt;. Studia Philonica Annual 19.&amp;nbsp; Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Runia, David T. and Gregory E. Sterling, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Studia Philonica Annual: Studies in Hellenistic Judaism, Volume XXI (2009)&lt;/em&gt;. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Runia, David T. and Gregory E. Sterling, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Studia Philonica Annual: Studies in Hellenistic Judaism, Volume XXII (2010)&lt;/em&gt;. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Runia, David T. and Gregory E. Sterling, eds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Studia Philonica Annual: Studies in Hellenistic Judaism, Volume XXIV.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Studia Philonica. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Russell, Donald A. and David Konstan, eds.&amp;nbsp;and trans. Heraclitus: &lt;em&gt;Homeric Problems&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World 14. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ryan, Roger. &lt;em&gt;Judges&lt;/em&gt;. Readings: A New Biblical Commentary. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Salzman, Michele Renee and Michael Roberts, trans. &lt;em&gt;The &lt;/em&gt;Letters&lt;em&gt; of Symmachus: Book 1.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;Writings from the Greco-Roman World 30. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Schenker, Adrian, ed. &lt;em&gt;The Earliest Text of the Hebrew Bible:  The Relationship between the Masoretic Text and the Hebrew Base of the  Septuagint Reconsidere&lt;/em&gt;. Septuagint and Cognate Studies 52. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Schuller, Eileen M. and Carol A. Newsom.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Hodayot (Thanksgiving Psalms: A Study Edition of 1QHa).&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Early Judaism and Its Literature, Number 36.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Schüssler Fiorenza, Elizabeth and Kent Harold Richards, eds. &lt;em&gt;Transforming Graduate Biblical Education: Ethos and Discipline&lt;/em&gt;. Global Perspectives on Biblical Scholarship 10. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Segovia, Fernando F., editor. &lt;em&gt;What is John?: Volume I,&amp;nbsp; Readers and Readings of the Fourth Gospel&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 3. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 1999.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Shectman, Sarah.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Women in the Pentateuch: A Feminist and Source-Critical Analysis.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Hebrew Bible Monographs, 23.&amp;nbsp;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Shemunkasho, Aho. &lt;em&gt;Healing in the Theology of Saint Ephrem&lt;/em&gt;. Gorgias Dissertations 1: Near Eastern Studies, Vol. 1. Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Press, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Shipp, R. Mark. &lt;em&gt;Of Dead Kings and Dirges: Myth and Meaning in Isaiah 14:4b–21&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 11. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Sigal, Phillip, &lt;em&gt;The Halakhah of Jesus of Nazareth according to the Gospel of Matthew&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Studies in Biblical Literature 18. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Singer, Itamar. &lt;em&gt;Hittite Prayers. &lt;/em&gt;Writings from the Ancient World. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Singer, Itamar.&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Calm before the Storm: Selected Writings of Itamar Singer on the Late Bronze Age in Anatolia and the Levant. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;Writings from the Ancient World Supplements, Number 1.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Sinkoff, Nancy. &lt;em&gt;Out of the Shtetl: Making Jews Modern in the Polish Borderlands&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 336. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Sjöberg, Mikael. &lt;em&gt;Wrestling with Textual Violence: The Jephthah Narrative in Antiquity and Modernity&lt;/em&gt;. The Bible in the Modern World 4. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Skinner, Christopher W. and Kelly R. Iverson, eds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Unity and Diversity in the Gospels and Paul: Essays in Honor of Frank J. Matera.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;Early Christianity and Its Literature, 7.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Sklar, Jay. &lt;em&gt;Sin, Impurity, Sacrifice, Atonement: The Priestly Conceptions&lt;/em&gt;. Hebrew Bible Monographs 2. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Smith, James A. &lt;em&gt;Marks of an Apostle: Deconstruction, Philippians, and Problematizing Pauline Theology&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 53. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Smith, Mark S. &lt;em&gt;The Rituals and Myths of the Feast of the Goodly Gods  of KTU/CAT 1.23: Royal Constructions of Opposition, Intersection,  Integration, and Domination&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 51. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Smith, Richard. &lt;em&gt;A Concise Coptic-English Lexicon: Second Edition&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 35. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1999.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Sneed, Mark R.&lt;em&gt;The Politics of Pessimism in Ecclesiastes: A Social-Science Perspective.&lt;/em&gt;Ancient Israel and Its Literature 12. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2012.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Sparks, James T. &lt;em&gt;The Chronicler's Genealogies: Towards an Understanding of 1 Chronicles 1–9&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 28. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Starbuck, Scott R. A. &lt;em&gt;Court Oracles in the Psalms: The So-Called Royal Psalms in their Ancient Near Eastern Context&lt;/em&gt;. Dissertation Series 172. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1999.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steck, Odil Hannes. Trans. by James D. Nogalski. &lt;em&gt;Old Testament Exegesis: A Guide to the Methodology, Second Edition&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 39. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 1998.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Steiner, Richard C. &lt;em&gt;Stockmen from Tekoa, Sycomores from Sheba: A Study of Amos’ Occupations&lt;/em&gt;. Catholic Biblical Quarterly Monograph Series 36.&amp;nbsp; Washington, DC: Catholic Biblical Association of America. 2003.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Stepp, Perry L. &lt;em&gt;Leadership Succession in the World of the Pauline Circle&lt;/em&gt;. New Testament Monographs 5. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2005&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Steppa, Jan-Eric. &lt;em&gt;John Rufus and the World Vision of Anti-Chalcedonean Culture&lt;/em&gt;. Piscataway, NJ: Gorgias Dissertations in Early Christian Studies 4, ECS 1, 2005.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stern, Elsie R. &lt;em&gt;From Rebuke to Consolation: Exegesis and Theology in the Liturgical Anthology of the Ninth of Av Season&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 338. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Stone, Michael E., Aryeh Amihay, and Vered Hillel, eds. &lt;em&gt;Noah and His Book(s)&lt;/em&gt;. Early Judaism and Its Literature 28. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Strudwick, Nigel C. &lt;em&gt;Texts from the Pyramid Age&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 16. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Sugirtharajah, R.S., Ed., &lt;em&gt;The Postcolonial Biblical Reader.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Calibri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;sans-serif&amp;quot;; line-height: 115%;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Oxford: Blackwell Publishing Ltd., 2006.&lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Calibri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;sans-serif&amp;quot;; line-height: 115%;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Sugirtharajah, R.S., &lt;em&gt;Troublesome Texts, The Bible in Colonial and Contemporary Culture&lt;/em&gt;.  The Bible in the Modern World, 17. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Talshir, Zipora. &lt;em&gt;I Esdra: From Origin to Translation&lt;/em&gt;. Septuagint and Cognate Studies 47. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 1999.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tatum, Gregory, O. P. &lt;em&gt;New Chapters in the Life of Paul: The Relative Chronology of His Career&lt;/em&gt;. Catholic Biblical Quarterly Monograph Series 41. Washington, DC: Catholic Biblical Association of America, 2006. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Tauberschmidt, Gerhard. &lt;em&gt;Secondary Parallelism: A Study of Translation Technique in LXX Proverbs&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 15. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2004.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Thatcher, Tom and Stephen D. Moore, eds. &lt;em&gt;Anatomies of Narrative Criticism: The Past, Present, and Futures of the Fourth Gospel as Literature&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 55. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Thomas, Samuel I. &lt;em&gt;The Mysteries of Qumran: Mystery, Secrecy, and Esotericism in the Dead Sea Scrolls&lt;/em&gt;. Early Judaism and Its Literature 25. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Tomes, Roger. &lt;em&gt;I Have Written to the King, My Lord: Secular Analogies for the Psalms&lt;/em&gt;. Hebrew Bible Monographs 1. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Torrey, Charles C. &lt;em&gt;The Lives of the Prophets: Greek Text and Translation&lt;/em&gt;.  Monograph Series 1. Philadelphia: Society of Biblical Literature and  Exegesis, 1946. (Reprinted by the Society of Biblical Literature, 2006).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Tucker, W. Dennis, Jr. &lt;em&gt;Jonah: A Handbook on the Hebrew Text&lt;/em&gt;. Baylor Handbook on the Hebrew Bible. Waco: Baylor University Press, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Turner, John D. and Kevin Corrigan, eds. &lt;em&gt;Plato's&lt;/em&gt; Parmenides &lt;em&gt;and Its Heritage, Volume 1: History and Interpretation from the Old Academy to Later Platonism and Gnosticism&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World Supplement Series 2. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Turner, John D. and Kevin Corrigan, eds. &lt;em&gt;Plato's&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Parmenides and Its Heritage, Volume 2: Its Reception in Neoplatonic, Jewish, and Christian Texts&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Greco-Roman World Supplement Series 3. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2010.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Turner, John D. and Ruth Majercik, eds. &lt;em&gt;Gnosticism and Later Platonism: Themes, Figures, and Texts&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium 12. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2001.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Turner, Laurence A.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Genesis, Second Edition.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: &amp;quot;Calibri&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;sans-serif&amp;quot;; line-height: 115%;"&gt;Readings: A New Biblical Commentary&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Udoh, Fabian E. &lt;em&gt;To Caesar What Is Caesar’s: Tribute, Taxes, and Imperial Administration in Early Roman Palestine (63 B.C.E.–70 C.E.)&lt;/em&gt;. Brown Judaic Studies 343. Providence: Brown Judaic Studies, 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Ukpong, Justin S. et al. eds. &lt;em&gt;Reading the Bible in the Global Village: Cape Town&lt;/em&gt;. Global Perspectives on Biblical Scholarship 8. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2002.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Valeta, David, Lions and Ovens and Visions; &lt;em&gt;A Satirical Reading of Daniel 1-6. &lt;/em&gt;Hebrew Bible Monographs, 12. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Van Voorst, Robert E. &lt;em&gt;Building Your New Testament Greek Vocabulary, Third Edition. &lt;/em&gt;Resources for Biblical Study 43. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2001. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Vander Stichele, Caroline and Todd Penner, eds. &lt;em&gt;Her Master’s Tools? Feminist and Postcolonial Engagements of Historical-Critical Discourse&lt;/em&gt;. Global Perspectives on Biblical Scholarship 9. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;van de Sandt, Huub and Jürgen K. Zangenberg, eds. &lt;em&gt;Matthew, James, and Didache: Three Related Documents in Their Jewish and Christian Settings&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 45. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2008.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Vanstiphout, Herman. &lt;em&gt;Epics of Sumerian Kings: The Matter of Aratta&lt;/em&gt;. Writings from the Ancient World 20. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Vaughn, Andrew G. &lt;em&gt;Theology, History, and Archaeology in the Chronicler’s Account of Hezekiah&lt;/em&gt;.  Archaeology and Biblical Studies 4. Atlanta, Scholars Press for the  Society of Biblical Literature and the American Schools of Oriental  Research, 1999.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Verner, David C. &lt;em&gt;The Household of God: The Social World of the Pastoral Epistles&lt;/em&gt;. Dissertation Series 71. Chico: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1983.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;von Ehrenkrook, Jason.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Sculpting Idolatry in Flavian Rome.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;Early Judaism and Its Literature, 33.&amp;nbsp;Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;div style="line-height: normal; margin-bottom: 0pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Wachtel, Klaus and Michael W. Holmes, eds. &lt;em&gt;The Textual History of the Greek New Testament: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Changing Views in Contemporary Research.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;Text-Critical Studies, 8. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2011.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Wade, Martha. &lt;em&gt;Consistency of Translation Techniques in the Tabernacle Accounts of Exodus in the Old Greek.&lt;/em&gt; Septuagine and Cognate Studies 49. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Walker-Jones, Arthur. &lt;em&gt;Hebrew for Biblical Interpretation&lt;/em&gt;. Resources for Biblical Study 48. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Wallace, Howard N. &lt;em&gt;Psalms&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Readings: A New Biblical Commentary&lt;/em&gt;. &amp;nbsp;Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2009.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt; &lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Wassen, Cecilia. &lt;em&gt;Women in the Damascus Document&lt;/em&gt;. Academia Biblica 21. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Watson, Duane F., ed. &lt;em&gt;The Intertexture of Apocalyptic Discourse in the New Testament&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 14. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2002. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Watts, James W., ed. &lt;em&gt;Persia and Torah: The Theory of Imperial Authorization of the Pentateuch&lt;/em&gt;. Symposium Series 17. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2001.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;West, Gerald O. &lt;em&gt;Reading Other-Wise: Socially Engaged Biblical Scholars Reading with Their Local Communities&lt;/em&gt;. Semeia Studies 62. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Whybray, Norman. &lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt;. Readings: A New Biblical Commentary. Sheffield: Sheffield Phoenix Press, 2008. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Wright, Benjamin G. III and Lawrence M. Wills, eds. &lt;em&gt;Conflicted Boundaries in Wisdom and Apocalypticism. &lt;/em&gt;Symposium 35. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2005.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yeivin, Israel. &lt;em&gt;Introduction to the Tiberian Masorah. &lt;/em&gt;Masoretic Studies 5. Atlanta: Scholars Press for the Society of Biblical Literature, 1985.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Zevit, Ziony, &lt;em&gt;The Anterior Construction in Classical Hebrew&lt;/em&gt;. Monograph 50. Atlanta: Scholars Press on behalf of the Society of Biblical Literature, 1998.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div align="left"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1262955367985992358/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/03/sbls-international-cooperation.html#comment-form"
         title="2 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1262955367985992358"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1262955367985992358"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/03/sbls-international-cooperation.html"
         title="The SBL's International Cooperation Initiative Program (ICI)"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>2</thr:total>
</entry>
