<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4614442783341663944</id>
   <published>2012-04-01T14:00:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-04-01T20:44:50.286-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">ARCHIBAB Update</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.archibab.fr/">ACHIBAB: Archives babyloniennes (XXe-XVIIe siècles av. J.C.</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.archibab.fr/images/bg_head.png" src="http://www.archibab.fr/images/bg_head.png" />&nbsp; </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><tt>As of &nbsp;Friday, March 30, 2012, many additional texts are now available on ARCHIBAB. These include: <br /><br />- 775 texts published by Ilya Arkhipov in ARM 32. The online edition was facilitated by the author, with photos as well for most of them (732). (We thank Firas Hammoush for his help in making the transfer.) In this way, we are pleased to continue on what was recently done as regards A. Jacquet’s volume (FM 12), that is, to make available online texts and photos even as a hard copy of a book is distributed <br />(&lt;<a href="https://webmail.uchicago.edu/wm/mail/fetch.html?urlid=g035d0db7c7066627dcbcf94e212222d0fl1kkgahpl&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.peeters-leuven.be%2Fboekoverz.asp%3Fnr%3D9106" target="_blank">http://www.peeters-leuven.be/boekoverz.asp?nr=9106</a>&gt;). <br /><br />- The letters published in ARM 26/1 are now available in transcription, translation, and notes, thanks to J.-M. Durand who furnished us with an electronic version and to A.-L. Langlois &nbsp;for setting the texts into the proper database format. As well, the first two segments of ARM 26/2 are similarly available. <br /><br />- 280 texts from Kisurra as edited by A. Goddeeris in Santag 9 <br />(<a href="https://webmail.uchicago.edu/wm/mail/fetch.html?urlid=g035d0db7c7066627dcbcf94e212222d0fl1kkgahpl&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.harrassowitz-verlag.de" target="_blank">http://www.harrassowitz-verlag.de</a>). &nbsp;Many thanks to Anne Goddeeris for providing us with an electronic version of her manuscript and to Anne-Isabelle Langlois for setting the texts into the proper database <br />format. <br /><br />- 110 texts Khafajah (Tutub), edited by R. Harris JCS 9. We thank Walter Sommerfeld for giving us an electronic version of his manuscript and Antoine Jacquet for setting the texts into the proper database format. <br /><br />-Additionally, the list of Year Names is now complete for Babylon and Kisurra <br /><br />There are now at least 7000 documents online, with catalog records. Among them, 4500 are transliterated and about 1100 are reproduced, most as photos. <br /><br /><br />==================================================================================== <br /><br /><br />Depuis le vendredi 30 mars 2012, de nombreux textes supplémentaires sont consultables sur ARCHIBAB. Il s'agit notamment de: <br /><br />– 775 textes édités par I. Arkhipov dans ARM 32 : les éditions des textes sont consultables (grâce à l'auteur du livre, Ilya Arkhipov) et les photos de la plupart d'entre eux (732) également (merci à Firas Hammoush pour sa collaboration). <br /><br /> &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Nous sommes heureux d'avoir pu recommencer ce qui avait été fait l'an dernier pour le volume FM 12 d'A. Jacquet : mettre en ligne les textes avec leurs photos au moment même de la parution du livre <br />(&lt;<a href="https://webmail.uchicago.edu/wm/mail/fetch.html?urlid=g035d0db7c7066627dcbcf94e212222d0fl1kkgahpl&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.peeters-leuven.be%2Fboekoverz.asp%3Fnr%3D9106" target="_blank">http://www.peeters-leuven.be/boekoverz.asp?nr=9106</a>&gt;) <br /><br />-Les lettres de ARM 26/1 sont désormais accessibles en totalité (transcription, traduction et notes), grâce à J.-M. Durand qui nous a communiqué son manuscrit électronique et A.-I. Langlois qui a entré les textes dans la base et assuré leur mise au normes. Les deux premières parties de ARM 26/2 sont également accessible en transcription, traduction et notes. <br /><br />– 280 textes de Kisurra édités par A. Goddeeris dans SANTAG 9 <br />(<a href="https://webmail.uchicago.edu/wm/mail/fetch.html?urlid=g035d0db7c7066627dcbcf94e212222d0fl1kkgahpl&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.harrassowitz-verlag.de" target="_blank">http://www.harrassowitz-verlag.de</a>). Merci à Anne Goddeeris qui nous a communiqué son manuscrit électronique et à Anne-Isabelle Langlois qui a entré les textes dans la base et assuré leur mise au normes. <br /><br />– 110 textes de Khafajah (Tutub) édités par R. Harris dans JCS 9. Merci à Walter Sommerfeld qui nous a communiqué son manuscrit électronique et à Antoine Jacquet qui a entré les textes dans la base et assuré leur mise au normes. <br /><br /><br />De plus, les données des NOMS D'ANNEES sont maintenant complètes pour Babylone et Kisurra. <br /><br />Désormais, 7000 textes sont en ligne (au minimum avec une notice de catalogue; 4500 textes sont pourvus d'une transcription et 1100 d'une reproduction [photo le plus souvent]). </tt></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4614442783341663944/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/04/achibab-update.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4614442783341663944"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4614442783341663944"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/04/achibab-update.html"
         title="ARCHIBAB Update"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
