<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5190044407733096713</id>
   <published>2010-03-01T16:19:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2010-03-02T07:32:07.800-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Ten more volumes of Egyptology from the Oriental Institute</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/news/">On March 1, 2010</a>, The Oriental Institute published digital editions of ten more volumes of Egyptological scholarship:<br /><blockquote><p>As part of its Electronic Publications Initiative and with the generous support of Misty and Lewis Gruber, the Oriental Institute Publications Office announces the Adobe Portable Document Format (PDF) publication of: </p><ul><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oimp/oimp23.html">OIMP 23. Ancient Egypt: Treasures from the Collection of the Oriental Institute.</a> By Emily Teeter. Originally published in 2003.</li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine10.html">OINE 10. Excavations at Serra East, Parts 1-5: A-Group, C-Group, Pan Grave, New Kingdom, and X-Group Remains from Cemeteries A-G and Rock Shelters.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1993.</li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine9.html">OINE 9. Excavations Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 9: Noubadian X-Group Remains from Royal Complexes in Cemeteries Q and 219 and Private Cemeteries Q, R, V, W, B, J, and M at Qustul and Ballana.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1991.</li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine8.html">OINE 8. Excavations Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 8: Meroitic Remains from Qustul Cemetery Q, Ballana Cemetery B, and a Ballana Settlement.</a> By B. B. Williams, et. al. Originally published in 1991.</li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine7.html">OINE 7. Excavations Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 7: Twenty-Fifth Dynasty and Napatan Remains at Qustul Cemeteries W and V.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1990.</li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine4.html">OINE 4. Excavations Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Parts 2, 3, and 4: Neolithic, A-Group, and Post A-Group Remains from Cemeteries W, V, S, Q, T, and a Cave East of Cemetery K.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1989.</li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine3.html">OINE 3. Excavations Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 1: The A-Group Royal Cemetery at Qustul, Cemetery L.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1986.</li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine5.html">OINE 5. Excavations Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 5: C-Group, Pan Grave, and Kerma Remains at Adindan Cemeteries T, K, U, and J.</a> By B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1983.</li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine1.html">OINE 1. The Beit el-Wali Temple of Ramesses II.</a> By Herbert Ricke, George R. Hughes, and Edward F. Wente. Originally published in 1967.</li><li><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc53.html">SAOC 53. Glass from Quseir al-Qadim and the Indian Ocean Trade.</a> By Carol Meyer. Originally published in 1992.</li></ul></blockquote>For an up to date list of all of the ca. two hundred and sixty volumes of Oriental Institute publications available online see <a href="http://ancientworldbloggers.blogspot.com/2008/04/awol-ancient-world-online-2.html">AWOL - The Ancient World Online - 2: The Oriental Institute Electronic Publications Initiative</a>.<br /><br /><a title="data:post.title" url="data:post.url" class="addthis_button"><img src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/v2/lg-share-en.gif" alt="Bookmark and Share" style="border: 0pt none ;" height="16" width="125" /></a>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5190044407733096713/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/03/ten-more-volumes-of-egyptology-from.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5190044407733096713"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5190044407733096713"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/03/ten-more-volumes-of-egyptology-from.html"
         title="Ten more volumes of Egyptology from the Oriental Institute"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
