<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9146145530524821179</id>
   <published>2009-06-16T09:04:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2009-06-16T09:23:45.898-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Twenty six more Oriental Institute publications online open access</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[OIP 3. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip3.html">The Edwin Smith Surgical Papyrus, Volume 1: Hieroglyphic Transliteration, Translation, and Commentary</a>. By J. H. Breasted. Oriental Institute Publications 3. 1930<br /><br />OIP 4. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip4.html">The Edwin Smith Surgical Papyrus, Volume 2: Facsimile Plates and Line for Line Hieroglyphic Transliteration</a>. By J. H. Breasted. Oriental Institute Publications 4. 1930<br /><br />OIP 17. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip17.html">Paleolithic Man and the Nile-Faiyum Divide in Nubia and Upper Egypt: A Study of the Region during Pliocene and Pleistocene Times</a>. By K. S. Sandford and W. J. Arkell. Oriental Institute Publications 17, Prehistoric Survey of Egypt and Western Asia II. 1933<br /><br />OIP 34. <a href="http://www.blogger.com/%20http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip34.html">The Egyptian Coffin Texts 1: Texts of Spells 1-75</a>. By Adriaan de Buck. Oriental Institute Publications 34. 1935<br /><br />SAOC 33. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc33.html">Late Ramesside Letters</a>. By Edward F. Wente. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 33. 1967<br /><br />SAOC 34. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc34.html">A Study of the Ba Concept in Ancient Egyptian Texts</a>. By Louis V. Zabkar. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 34. 1968<br /><br />SAOC 35. <a href="http://www.blogger.com/%20http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc35.html">Studies in Honor of John A. Wilson</a>. Edited by E. B. Hauser. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 35. 1969. <span style="font-size:85%;">Kindly note that this volume is also available in print.</span><br /><br />SAOC 39. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc39.html">Studies in Honor of George R. Hughes, January 12, 1977</a>. Edited by Janet H. Johnson and Edward F. Wente. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 39. 1976. <span style="font-size:85%;">Kindly note that this volume is also available in print.<br /></span><br />SAOC 40. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc40.html">Ancient Egyptian Coregencies</a>. By William J. Murnane. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 40. 1977<br /><br />SAOC 47. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc47.html">Essays in Ancient Civilization Presented to Helene J. Kantor.</a> Edited by Albert Leonard Jr. and Bruce B. Williams. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 47. 1989. <span style="font-size:85%;">Kindly note that this volume is also available in print.</span><br /><br />SAOC 48. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc48.html">Egyptian Phyles in the Old Kingdom: The Evolution of a System of Social Organizatio</a>n. By Ann Macy Roth. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 48. 1991<br /><br />SAOC 51. <a href="http://www.blogger.com/%20http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc51.html">Life in a Multi-Cultural Society: Egypt from Cambyses to Constantine and Beyond</a>. Edited by Janet Johnson. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 51. 1992. <span style="font-size:85%;">Kindly note that this volume was already available; the replacement PDF file is created from a better scan.</span><br /><br />SAOC 52. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc52.html">A Late Period Hieratic Wisdom Text (P. Brooklyn 47.218.135)</a>. By Richard Jasnow. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 52. 1992. <span style="font-size:85%;">Kindly note that this volume is also available in print.</span><br /><br />SAOC 55. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc55.html">For His Ka: Essays Offered in Memory of Klaus Baer</a>. Edited by D. P. Silverman. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 55. 1994<br /><br />SAOC 56. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc56.html">Portrait Mummies from Roman Egypt (I-IV Centuries A.D.) with a Catalog of Portrait Mummies in Egyptian Museums</a>. By Lorelei H. Corcoran. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 56. 1995<br /><br />SAOC 57. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc57.html">The Presentation of Maat: Ritual and Legitimacy in Ancient Egypt</a>. By Emily Teeter. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 57. 1997<br /><br />SAOC 58. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc58.html">Gold of Praise: Studies on Ancient Egypt in Honor of Edward F. Wente</a>. Edited by Emily Teeter and John A. Larson. Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 58. 2000. <span style="font-size:85%;">Kindly note that this volume is also available in print.</span><br /><br />MISC. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/burden.html">The Burden of Egypt: An Interpretation of Ancient Egyptian Culture</a>. By John A. Wilson. Oriental Institute Essay. 1951<br /><br />MISC. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/culture.html">The Culture of Ancient Egypt</a>. By John A. Wilson. Oriental Institute Essay. Phoenix Edition 1956. <span style="font-size:85%;">Kindly note that this title was first published under the title The Burden of Egypt: An Interpretation of Ancient Egyptian Culture (1951).</span><br /><br />MISC. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/quseir.html">Quseir Al-Qadim 1978: Preliminary Report</a>. By D. S. Whitcomb and J. H. Johnson. 1979<br /><br />MISC. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/quseir_1980.html">Quseir al-Qadim 1980: Preliminary Report</a>. By Donald S. Whitcomb and Janet H. Johnson. American Research Center in Egypt Reports 7. 1982<br /><br />MISC. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/kingship.html">Kingship and the Gods: A Study of Ancient Near Eastern Religion as the Integration of Society and Nature</a>. By Henri Frankfort, with a new Preface by Samuel Noah Kramer. Oriental Institute Essay. 1948<br /><br />MISC. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/most_ancient.html">Most Ancient Egypt</a>. By William C. Hayes, edited by Keith C. Seele. 1965<br /><br />MISC. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/paintings3.html">Ancient Egyptian Paintings Selected, Copied, and Described, Volume III: Descriptive Text</a>. By Nina M. Davies with the editorial assistance of Alan H. Gardiner. 1936<br /><br />MISC. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/when_egypt.html">When Egypt Ruled the East</a>. By George Steindorff and Keith C. Seele, revised by Keith C. Seele. 1957<br /><br />MISC. <a href="http://www.blogger.com/%20http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/textiles.html">Ancient Textiles from Nubia: Meroitic, X-Group, and Christian Fabrics from Ballana and Qustul</a>. By Christa C. Mayer Thurman and Bruce Williams. 1979]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9146145530524821179/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/06/twenty-six-more-oriental-institute.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9146145530524821179"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9146145530524821179"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/06/twenty-six-more-oriental-institute.html"
         title="Twenty six more Oriental Institute publications online open access"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
