<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8613960629914385651</id>
   <published>2010-09-20T09:31:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2010-09-20T09:31:01.115-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">News from the Centre for Computer-aided Egyptological Research</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.ccer.nl/">Centre for Computer-aided Egyptological Research</a><br /><br />The CCER is circulating <a href="http://www.ccer.nl/news.html">this announcement:</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">Dear colleagues and friends of the CCER.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The team of the Centre of Computer-aided Egyptological Research (CCER, Utrecht University) has developed pioneering and useful computing tools and international projects for Egyptological research since 1990 (among other things Manual de Codage, Multilingual Egyptological Thesaurus, Glyph for Windows &amp; Extended Library, Coffin Texts Word Index, Egyptian Treasures in Europe, Global Egyptian Museum). The CCER was the driving force of the group Informatique &amp; Egyptologie and the Horssen Meetings. CCER inspired Egyptological scholars, students and institutions to make use of these upcoming new ICT tools and helped them to implement them.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Now 20 years after the founding of CCER it is time to accept that CCER has become part of history and that the well-known CCER site must switch to another life and a new concept. Some years ago it appeared that there was no future for CCER in the Netherlands. Besides its director retired. Therefore I have decided to stop finally also the shop of the site www.ccer.nl by the end of this year. I"ll transmit by then the site and all rights to my former assistant Hans van den Berg. He was my gifted and much appreciated "life-ware" and "soft-hand" during many years. He would like to use this site to record the history of Computing &amp; Egyptology. He will continue and maintain some useful tools for Egyptology on this site as well.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Until the end of this year there will be a sale with reduced prices of all available products of the former CCER (Glyph for Windows, Hieroglyphica, Coffin Texts Word Index etc.).</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Glyph for Windows is a 16-bit program and will not run with 64-bit (x64) operating systems. Because there will be no upgrade of the 16-bit version of Glyph and the extended library, I advise all of you to keep a PC with Windows XP, 32-bit Windows Vista or 32-bit Windows 7 to run specially Glyph for Windows in order to be able to process your hieroglyphic texts. The last version of Glyph for Windows Professional edition (including the extended library) which is compatible with aforementioned operating systems can be ordered for only Euro 100 (including Hieroglyphica).</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">I would like to thank all colleagues, assistants and friends for the collaboration and confidence during those pioneering years,</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Dirk van der Plas </span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;"><br /><a expr:id="data:post.url" expr:name="data:post.title" href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-create.g?blogID=116259103207720939" onclick="return addthis_sendto()" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onmouseover="return addthis_open(this, &quot;&quot;, this.id, this.name);"><img alt="Bookmark and Share so Your Real Friends Know that You Know" height="16" src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif" style="border: 0pt none;" width="125" /></a> <script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8613960629914385651/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/09/news-from-centre-for-computer-aided.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8613960629914385651"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8613960629914385651"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/09/news-from-centre-for-computer-aided.html"
         title="News from the Centre for Computer-aided Egyptological Research"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
