<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-136894099415794198</id>
   <published>2013-07-19T13:55:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-07-19T13:55:30.150-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New Online from The Oriental Institute: Heaven on Earth: Temples, Ritual, and Cosmic Symbolism in the Ancient World</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3><span style="font-size: small;"><span style="font-weight: normal;"><a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois9.html">OIS 9.<cite>&nbsp; Heaven on Earth: Temples, Ritual, and Cosmic Symbolism in the Ancient World</cite></a><br /> Edited by Deena Ragavan</span></span></h3><div class="buy"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="download" href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/pdf/ois9.pdf" title="Download PDF">Download PDF</a> &nbsp;</span></div><div class="buy"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="terms" href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/epi.html">Terms of Use</a></span> </div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h4><span style="font-size: x-small;">Oriental Institute Seminars 9</span></h4><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The volume is the result of the eighth Annual University of Chicago  Oriental Institute Seminar, held on March 2-3, 2012. Seventeen speakers,  from both the US and abroad, examined the interconnections between  temples, ritual, and cosmology from a variety of regional  specializations and theoretical perspectives. The seminar revisited a  classic topic, one with a long history among scholars of the ancient  world: the cosmic symbolism of sacred architecture. Archaeologists, art  historians, and philologists working not only in the ancient Near East,  but also Mesoamerica, Greece, South Asia, and China, re-evaluated the  significance of this topic across the ancient world.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://oi.uchicago.edu/i/ois9_5.jpg" class="decoded" height="200" src="http://oi.uchicago.edu/i/ois9_5.jpg" width="140" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><h5><span style="font-size: x-small;">Table of Contents</span></h5><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Introduction<br />1. Heaven on Earth: Temples, Ritual, and Cosmic Symbolism in the Ancient World. Deena Ragavan</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Part I: Architecture and Cosmology<br />2. Naturalizing Buddhist Cosmology in the Temple Architecture of China: The Case of the Yicihui Pillar. Tracy Miller<br />3. Hints at Temple Topography and Cosmic Geography from Hittite Sources. Susanne Görke<br />4. Images of the Cosmos: Sacred and Ritual Space in Jaina Temple Architecture in India. Julia A. B. Hegewald </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Part II: Built Space and Natural Forms<br />5. The Classic Maya Temple: Centrality, Cosmology, and Sacred Geography in Ancient Mesoamerica. Karl Taube <br />6. Seeds and Mountains: The Cosmogony of Temples in South Asia. Michael W. Meister<br />7. Intrinsic and Constructed Sacred Space in Hittite Anatolia. Gary Beckman </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Part III: Myth and Movement<br />8. On the Rocks: Greek Mountains and Sacred Conversations. Betsey A. Robinson<br />9. Entering Other Worlds: Gates, Rituals, and Cosmic Journeys in Sumerian Sources. Deena Ragavan </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Part IV: Sacred Space and Ritual Practice<br />10. “We Are Going to the House in Prayer”: Theology, Cultic Topography,  and Cosmology in the Emesal Prayers of Ancient Mesopotamia. Uri Gabbay<br />11. Temporary Ritual Structures and Their Cosmological Symbolism in Ancient<br />Mesopotamia. Claus Ambos <br />12. Sacred Space and Ritual Practice at the End of Prehistory in the Southern Levant. Yorke M. Rowan</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Part V: Architecture, Power, and the State<br />13. Egyptian Temple Graffiti and the Gods: Appropriation and Ritualization in Karnak and Luxor. Elizabeth Frood <br />14. The Transformation of Sacred Space, Topography, and Royal Ritual in Persia and the Ancient Iranian World. Matthew P Canepa<br />15. The Cattlepen and the Sheepfold: Cities, Temples, and Pastoral Power in Ancient Mesopotamia. Omur Harmansah </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Part VI: Images of Ritual<br />16. Sources of Egyptian Temple Cosmology: Divine Image, King, and Ritual Performer. John Baines <br />17. Mirror and Memory: Images of Ritual Actions in Greek Temple Decoration. Clemente Marconi </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">PART VII: Responses<br />18. Temples of the Depths, Pillars of the Heights, Gates in Between. Davíd Carrasco <br />19. Cosmos and Discipline. Richard Neer</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Oriental Institute Seminars 9</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Chicago: The Oriental Institute, 2013</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">ISBN-13: 978-1-885923-96-7</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Pp. viii+463; 174 illustrations</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="pubprice">$29.95</span></span></li></ul></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Oriental Institute Seminars (OIS)</b> | <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/">List of volumes in print</a></span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">OIS 9. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois9.html">Heaven on Earth: Temples, Ritual, and Cosmic Symbolism in the Ancient World.</a> Edited by Deena Ragavan. 2013.</span> </li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">OIS 8. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois8.html">Iconoclasm and Text Destruction in the Ancient Near East and Beyond.</a> Edited by Natalie Naomi May. 2012.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">OIS 7. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois7.html">Slaves and Households in the Near East</a>, Edited by Laura Culbertson. 2011</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">OIS 6. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois6.html">Divination and Interpretation of Signs in the Ancient World</a><span style="font-weight: bold;">, </span>Edited by Amar Annus. 2010</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">OIS 5. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois5.html">Nomads, Tribes, and the State in the Ancient Near East: Cross-disciplinary Perspectives,</a> Edited by Jeffrey Szuchman. 2009.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">OIS 4. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois4.html">Religion and Power: Divine Kingship in the Ancient World and Beyond, </a>Nicole Brisch, ed., 2008. Second printing with minor corrections, 2012.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">OIS 3. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois3.html">Performing Death: Social Analyses of Funerary Traditions in the Ancient Near East and Mediterranean.</a>  Nicola Laneri, ed. 2007.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">OIS 2. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois2.html">Margins of Writing, Origins of Cultures.</a>  Seth L. Sanders, ed. 2006, 2007.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">OIS 1. <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois1.html">Changing Social Identity with the Spread of Islam: Archaeological Perspectives.</a>  Donald Whitcomb, ed. 2004. </span></li></ul><br /><div style="text-align: center;">For an up to date list of all Oriental Institute publications available online see:</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/10/oriental-institute-open-access.html">The Oriental Institute Open Access Publications</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/136894099415794198/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/07/new-online-from-oriental-institute.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/136894099415794198"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/136894099415794198"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/07/new-online-from-oriental-institute.html"
         title="New Online from The Oriental Institute: Heaven on Earth: Temples, Ritual, and Cosmic Symbolism in the Ancient World"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
