<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7554426205875468670</id>
   <published>2010-01-26T05:36:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2010-01-26T11:29:56.702-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Oriental Institute Open Access Publications in 2009</title>
   <content type="html">The Oriental Institute of The University of Chicago is a leader in open access publishing of scholarly work on the Ancient World.  In 2009 they published some 114 titles online, many of which are long out of print, rare, and hard to find.  These are listed below in the order in which they appeared online, earliest at the top.&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/epi.html"&gt; The Electronic Publications Initiative of the Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago&lt;/a&gt; outlines the forward thinking policies which guide this effort.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For an up to date list of all Oriental Institute publications available online see &lt;a href="http://ancientworldbloggers.blogspot.com/2008/04/awol-ancient-world-online-2.html"&gt;AWOL - The Ancient World Online - 2: The Oriental Institute Electronic Publications Initiative&lt;/a&gt;. All told, nearly two hundred fifty volumes are now accessible.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;Newly Published in 2009: Print + Digital Publications&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[5 titles]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oimp/oimp29.html"&gt;OIMP 29. The Life of Meresamun: A Temple Singer in Ancient Egypt. Edited by Emily Teeter and Janet H. Johnson. 2009.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/pdf/MesDir.pdf"&gt;Mesopotamian Directory 2009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/ois/ois5.html"&gt;OIS 5. Nomads, Tribes, and the State in the Ancient Near East: Cross-disciplinary Perspectives. Edited by Jeffrey Szuchman. 2009.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip134.html"&gt;OIP 134. The Archaeology and Geography of Ancient Transcaucasian Societies, Volume 1: The Foundations of Research and Regional Survey in the Tsaghkahovit Plain, Armenia. Adam T. Smith, Ruben S. Badalyan, Pavel Avetisyan. With contributions by Alan Greene and Leah Minc. 2009.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip136.html"&gt;OIP 136. Medinet Habu IX. The Eighteenth Dynasty Temple, Part I: The Inner Sanctuaries. With Translations of Texts, Commentary, and Glossary. By The Epigraphic Survey. 2009.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Newly Published in 2009: Born Digital Publications&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[3 titles]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/projects/lobpni"&gt;Database of Late Old Babylonian personal names derived from cuneiform texts chiefly dating to the reigns of the last three kings of the First Dynasty of Babylon, 1683-1595 B.C.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;"H with a dot", &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/cdd/"&gt;Chicago Demotic Dictionary&lt;/a&gt;, edited by Janet H. Johnson.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;"W",  &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/cdd/"&gt;Chicago Demotic Dictionary&lt;/a&gt;, edited by Janet H. Johnson.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Republished online in 2009&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[106 titles]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oic/oic5.html"&gt;OIC 5. Medinet Habu 1924-28.&lt;/a&gt; Part 1: The Epigraphic Survey of the Great Temple of Medinet Habu (Seasons 1924-25 To 1927-28). By Harold H. Nelson Part 2: The Architectural Survey of the Great Temple and Palace of Medinet Habu (Season 1927-28). By Uvo Hölscher Originally published in 1929. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine6.html"&gt;OINE 6. Excavations Between Abu Simbel and the Sudan Frontier, Part 6: New Kingdom Remains from Cemeteries R, V, S, and W at Qustul and Cemetery K at Adindan.&lt;/a&gt; B. B. Williams. Originally published in 1992. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip10.html"&gt;OIP 10. Paleolithic Man and the Nile-Faiyum Divide: A Study of the Region during Pliocene and Pleistocene Times.&lt;/a&gt; K.S. Sandford and W.J. Arkell. Originally published in 1929. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip49.html"&gt;OIP 49. The Egyptian Coffin Texts, Volume 2: Texts of Spells 76-163.&lt;/a&gt; By Adriaan De Buck. Originally published in 1929. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip80.html"&gt;OIP 80. Demotic Ostraca from Medinet Habu. By Miriam Lichtheim.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published in 1957. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip81.html"&gt;OIP 81. The Egyptian Coffin Texts, Volume 6: Texts of Spells 472-787.&lt;/a&gt; By Adriaan de Buck. Originally published in 1956. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc1.html"&gt;SAOC 1. Notes on Egyptian Marriage Chiefly in the Ptolemaic Period.&lt;/a&gt; William F. Edgerton. Originally published in 1931. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc37.html"&gt;SAOC 37. The Book of the Dead or Going Forth by Day: Ideas of the Ancient Egyptians Concerning the Hereafter as Expressed in Their Own Terms.&lt;/a&gt; Translated by Thomas George Allen. Originally published in 1974. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/early_hydraulic.html"&gt;Early Hydraulic Civilization in Egypt: A Study in Cultural Ecology.&lt;/a&gt; Karl W. Butzer. Originally published in 1976. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/egyptology.html"&gt;Egyptology at the Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago.&lt;/a&gt; The Oriental Institute. Originally published in 1983. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/united.html"&gt;United with Eternity: A Concise Guide to the Monuments of Medinet Habu.&lt;/a&gt; William J. Murnane. Originally published in 1980. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/cameron_letters.html"&gt;Letters from Egypt and Iraq, 1954.&lt;/a&gt; Margaret Bell Cameron. Originally published in 2001.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/signs.html"&gt;Signs and Wonders upon Pharaoh: A History of American Egyptology.&lt;/a&gt; John A. Wilson. Originally published in 1964.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oic/oic18.html"&gt;OIC 18. Work in Western Thebes, 1931-33.&lt;/a&gt; By Harold H. Nelson and Uvo Hölscher with a Chapter by Siegfried Schott. Originally published in 1934.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oic/oic15.html"&gt;OIC 15. Excavations at Ancient Thebes, 1930/31.&lt;/a&gt; By Uvo Hölscher. Originally published in 1932.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oic/oic10.html"&gt;OIC 10. Medinet Habu Reports – Third Preliminary Report.&lt;/a&gt; Part 1. The Epigraphic Survey, 1992-31. By Harold H. Nelson Part 2. The Architectural Survey, 1929/30. By Uvo Hölscher Originally published in 1931.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oic/oic7.html"&gt;OIC 7. Medinet Habu 1928-29.&lt;/a&gt; Part 1: The Architectural Survey. By Uvo Hölscher Part 2: The Language of the Historical Texts Commemorating Ramses III. By John A. Wilson Originally published in 1930.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip67.html"&gt;OIP 67. The Egyptian Coffin Texts, Volume 4: Texts of Spells 268-354.&lt;/a&gt; By Adriaan De Buck. Originally published in 1951.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc19.html"&gt;SAOC 19. The Coregency of Ramses II with Seti I and the Date of the Great Hypostyle Hall at Karnak.&lt;/a&gt; By Keith C. Seele. Originally published in 1940.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc16.html"&gt;SAOC 16. The Monasteries of the Fayyum.&lt;/a&gt; By Nabia Abbott. Originally published in 1937.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc12.html"&gt;SAOC 12. Historical Records of Ramses III: The Texts in Medinet Habu Volumes 1 and 2. Translated With Explanatory Notes.&lt;/a&gt; By William F. Edgerton and John A. Wilson. Originally published in 1936.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc8.html"&gt;SAOC 8. The Thutmosid Succession.&lt;/a&gt; By William F. Edgerton. Originally published in 1933.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oic/oic12.html"&gt;OIC 12. The Alphabet: Its Rise and Development from the Sinai Inscriptions.&lt;/a&gt; By Martin Sprengling. Originally published in 1931.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oic/oic27.html"&gt;OIC 27. The Registry of the Photographic Archives of the Epigraphic Survey, with Plates from Key Plans Showing Locations of Theban Temple Decorations (H. H. Nelson).&lt;/a&gt; The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1995.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oic/oic28.html"&gt;OIC 28. Bir Umm Fawakhir Survey Project 1993: A Byzantine Gold-Mining Town in Egypt.&lt;/a&gt; C. Meyer, L.A. Heidorn, W.E. Kaegi, and T. Wilfong. Originally published in 2000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip18.html"&gt;OIP 18. Paleolithic Man and the Nile Valley in Upper and Middle Egypt: A Study of the Region during Pliocene and Pleistocene Times.&lt;/a&gt; By K. S. Sandford. Prehistoric Survey of Egypt and Western Asia, Volume III. Originally published in 1934.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip46.html"&gt;OIP 46. Paleolithic Man and the Nile Valley in Lower Egypt with Some Notes upon a Part of the Red Sea Littoral: A Study of the Regions during Pliocene and Pleistocene Times.&lt;/a&gt; By K. S. Sandford and W. J. Arkell. Prehistoric Survey of Egypt and Western Asia, Volume IV. Originally published in 1939.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip73.html"&gt;OIP 73. The Egyptian Coffin Texts 5: Texts of Spells 355-471.&lt;/a&gt; By Adriaan de Buck. Originally published in 1954.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip113.html"&gt;OIP 113. The Oriental Institute Hawara Papyri: Demotic and Greek Texts from an Egyptian Family Archive in the Fayum (Fourth to Third Century B.C.).&lt;/a&gt; G. R. Hughes and R. Jasnow. Originally published in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc26.html"&gt;SAOC 26. The Calendars of Ancient Egypt.&lt;/a&gt; By Richard A. Parker. Originally published in 1950.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc27.html"&gt;SAOC 27. Occurrences of Pyramid Texts with Cross Indexes of These and Other Egyptian Mortuary Texts.&lt;/a&gt; By Thomas George Allen. Originally published in 1950.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc28.html"&gt;SAOC 28. Saite Demotic Land Leases.&lt;/a&gt; By George Robert Hughes. Originally published in 1952.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc30.html"&gt;SAOC 30. Wall Scenes from the Mortuary Chapel of the Mayor Paser at Medinet Habu.&lt;/a&gt; By Siegfried Schott. Translated By Elizabeth B. Hauser. Originally published in 1957.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oic/oic12.html"&gt;OIC 12. The Alphabet: Its Rise and Development from the Sinai Inscriptions.&lt;/a&gt; By Martin Sprengling. Originally published in 1931.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc58.html"&gt;SAOC 58. Gold of Praise: Studies on Ancient Egypt in Honor of Edward F. Wente.&lt;/a&gt; E. Teeter and J. A. Larson, eds.. Originally published in 2000.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc57.html"&gt;SAOC 57. The Presentation of Maat: Ritual and Legitimacy in Ancient Egypt.&lt;/a&gt; By Emily Teeter. Originally published in 1997.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc56.html"&gt;SAOC 56. Portrait Mummies from Roman Egypt (I-IV Centuries A.D.) with a Catalog of Portrait Mummies in Egyptian Museums.&lt;/a&gt; By Lorelei H. Corcoran. Originally published in 1995.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc55.html"&gt;SAOC 55. For His Ka: Essays Offered in Memory of Klaus Baer.&lt;/a&gt; D. P. Silverman, ed.. Originally published in 1994.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc52.html"&gt;SAOC 52. A Late Period Hieratic Wisdom Text (P. Brooklyn 47.218.135).&lt;/a&gt; R. Jasnow. Originally published in 1992.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc48.html"&gt;SAOC 48. Egyptian Phyles in the Old Kingdom: The Evolution of a System of Social Organization.&lt;/a&gt; By Ann Macy Roth. Originally published in 1991.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc47.html"&gt;SAOC 47. Essays in Ancient Civilization Presented to Helene J. Kantor.&lt;/a&gt; A. Leonard, Jr. and B. B. Williams, eds.. Originally published in 1989.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/quseir_1980.html"&gt;Quseir al-Qadim 1980: Preliminary Report.&lt;/a&gt; By Donald S. Whitcomb and Janet H. Johnson. Originally published in 1982.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc40.html"&gt;SAOC 40. Ancient Egyptian Coregencies.&lt;/a&gt; By William J. Murnane. Originally published in 1977.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc39.html"&gt;SAOC 39. Studies in Honor of George R. Hughes, January 12, 1977.&lt;/a&gt; J. H. Johnson and E. F. Wente, eds. Originally published in 1976.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc35.html"&gt;SAOC 35. Studies in Honor of John A. Wilson.&lt;/a&gt; E. B. Hauser, ed.. Originally published in 1969.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc34.html"&gt;SAOC 34. A Study of the Ba Concept in Ancient Egyptian Texts.&lt;/a&gt; By Louis V. Zabkar. Originally published in 1968.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc33.html"&gt;SAOC 33. Late Ramesside Letters. By Edward F. Wente. Originally published in 1967.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/burden.html"&gt;The Burden of Egypt: An Interpretation of Ancient Egyptian Culture.&lt;/a&gt; By John A. Wilson. Originally published in 1951.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/quseir.html"&gt;Quseir Al-Qadim 1978: Preliminary Report. By D. S. Whitcomb and J. H. Johnson. Originally published in 1979.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/textiles.html"&gt;Ancient Textiles from Nubia: Meroitic, X-Group, and Christian Fabrics from Ballana and Qustul. By Christa C. Mayer Thurman and Bruce Williams. Originally published in 1979.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/most_ancient.html"&gt;Most Ancient Egypt. By William C. Hayes. Originally published in 1965.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/when_egypt.html"&gt;When Egypt Ruled the East. By George Steindorff and Keith C. Seele, Revised by Keith C. Seele. Originally published as second edition in 1957.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/burden.html"&gt;The Culture of Egypt. By John A. Wilson. Originally published in 1956.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/kingship.html"&gt;Kingship and the Gods: A Study of Ancient Near Eastern Religion as the Integration of Society and Nature. By Henri Frankfort. Originally published in 1948.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/paintings3.html"&gt;Ancient Egyptian Paintings Selected, Copied, and Described. Volume III: Descriptive Text. By Nina M. Davies with the Editorial Assistance of Alan H. Gardiner. Originally published in 1936.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip34.html"&gt;OIP 34. The Egyptian Coffin Texts 1: Texts of Spells 1-75. By Adriaan De Buck. Originally published in 1935.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip17.html"&gt;OIP 17. Paleolithic Man and the Nile-Faiyum Divide in Nubia and Upper Egypt: A Study of the Region during Pliocene and Pleistocene Times. By K. S. Sandford and W. J. Arkell. Originally published in 1933.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip4.html"&gt;OIP 4. The Edwin Smith Surgical Papyrus, Volume 2: Facsimile Plates and Line for Line Hieroglyphic Transliteration. J. H. Breasted. Originally published in 1930, revised in 1991.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip3.html"&gt;OIP 3. The Edwin Smith Surgical Papyrus, Volume 1: Hieroglyphic Transliteration, Translation, and Commentary. J. H. Breasted. Originally published in 1930, revised in 1991.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oine/oine2.html"&gt;OINE 2. Ausgrabungen von Khor-Dehmit bis Bet El-Wali. H. Ricke. Originally published in 1967.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip106.html"&gt;OIP 106. The Great Hypostyle Hall at Karnak, Volume 1, Part 1: The Wall Reliefs. By Harold Hayden Nelson. Edited by William J. Murnane. Originally published in 1981&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip94.html"&gt;OIP 94. Medinet Habu, Vol. VIII: The Eastern High Gate with Translations of Texts. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1970&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip87.html"&gt;OIP 87. The Egyptian Coffin Texts 7, Texts of Spells 787-1185. By Adriaan de Buck. Originally published in 1961&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip86.html"&gt;OIP 86. The Tomb of Tjanefer at Thebes. By Keith C. Seele. Originally published in 1959&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip82.html"&gt;OIP 82. The Egyptian Book of the Dead: Documents in the Oriental Institute Museum at the University of Chicago. Edited by Thomas George Allen. Originally published in 1960&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip71.html"&gt;OIP 71. Coptic Ostraca from Medinet Habu. By Elizabeth Stefanski and Miriam Lichtheim. Originally published in 1952&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip66.html"&gt;OIP 66. Post-Ramessid Remains. The Excavation of Medinet Habu, Volume 5. By Uvo Hölscher. Originally published in 1954&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip64.html"&gt;OIP 64. The Egyptian Coffin Texts 3: Texts of Spells 164-267. By Adriaan de Buck. Originally published in 1947&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip54.html"&gt;OIP 54. The Mortuary Temple of Ramses III, Part 1. The Excavation of Medinet Habu, Volume 3. By Uvo Hölscher. Originally published in 1941&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip41.html"&gt;OIP 41. The Excavation of Medinet Habu, Volume 2: The Temples of the Eighteenth Dynasty. By Uvo Hölscher. Originally published in 1939&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip93.html"&gt;OIP 93. Medinet Habu, Vol. VII: The Temple Proper, Pt. III: The Third Hypostyle Hall and All Rooms Accessible from It with Friezes of Scenes from the Roof Terraces and Exterior Walls of the Temple. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1964.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip107.html"&gt;OIP 107. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Karnak, Volume IV: The Battle Reliefs of King Sety I. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1986.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip112.html"&gt;OIP 112. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Luxor Temple, Volume 1: The Festival Procession of Opet in the Colonnade Hall. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1994.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc42.html"&gt;SAOC 42. The Road to Kadesh: A Historical Interpretation of the Battle Reliefs of King Sety I at Karnak. W. J. Murnane. Originally published in 1985.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc42.html"&gt;SAOC 42, 2nd Edition. The Road to Kadesh: A Historical Interpretation of the Battle Reliefs of King Sety I at Karnak, 2nd Edition. W. J. Murnane. Originally published in 1990.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc54.html"&gt;SAOC 54. The Mechanics of Ancient Egyptian Magical Practice. R. K. Ritner. Originally published in 1993.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/saoc/saoc54.html"&gt;SAOC 54, 4th Printing. The Mechanics of Ancient Egyptian Magical Practice, 4th Printing. R. K. Ritner. Originally published in 2008.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/le/"&gt;Lost Egypt, Volumes I. A Limited Edition Portfolio Series of Photographic Images from Egypt’s Past. The Epigraphic Survey of the Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago. Originally published in 1992.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/le/"&gt;Lost Egypt, Volumes II. A Limited Edition Portfolio Series of Photographic Images from Egypt’s Past. The Epigraphic Survey of the Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago. Originally published in 1992.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/le/"&gt;Lost Egypt, Volumes III. A Limited Edition Portfolio Series of Photographic Images from Egypt’s Past. The Epigraphic Survey of the Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago. Originally published in 1992.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/paintings1.html"&gt;Ancient Egyptian Paintings Selected, Copied, and Described. Volume I: Descriptive Text. By Nina M. Davies with the Editorial Assistance of Alan H. Gardiner. Originally published in 1936.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/paintings2.html"&gt;Ancient Egyptian Paintings Selected, Copied, and Described. Volume II: Descriptive Text. By Nina M. Davies with the Editorial Assistance of Alan H. Gardiner. Originally published in 1936.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip116.html"&gt;OIP 116. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Luxor Temple, Volume 2: The Facade, Portals, Upper Register Scenes, Columns, Marginalia, and Statuary in the Colonnade Hall. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1998.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip103.html"&gt;OIP 103. The Temple of Khonsu, Volume 2: Scenes and Inscriptions in the Court and the First Hypostyle Hall. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1981.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip100.html"&gt;OIP 100. The Temple of Khonsu, Volume I: Scenes of King Herihor in the Court. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1979.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip83.html"&gt;OIP 83. Medinet Habu, Volume V. The Temple Proper, Part I: The Portico, the Treasury, and Chapels Adjoining the First Hypostyle Hall with Marginal Material from the Forecourts. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1957.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip74.html"&gt;OIP 74. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Karnak, Volume III. The Bubastite Portal. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1954.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip56.html"&gt;OIP 56. Key Plans Showing Locations of Theban Temple Decorations. By Harold Hayden Nelson. Originally published in 1941.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip51.html"&gt;OIP 51. Medinet Habu, Volume 4. Festival Scenes of Ramses III. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1940.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip39.html"&gt;OIP 39. The Mastaba of Mereruka, Part II: Chamber A 11-13, Doorjambs and Inscriptions of Chambers A 1-21, Tomb Chamber, and Exterior. By the Sakkarah Expedition. Originally published in 1938.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip36.html"&gt;OIP 36. Medinet Habu Graffiti: Facsimiles. Edited by William F. Edgerton. Originally published in 1937.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip23.html"&gt;OIP 23. Medinet Habu, Volume III. The Calendar, the “Slaughterhouse,” and Minor Records of Ramses III. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1934.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip8.html"&gt;OIP 8. Medinet Habu, Volume I. Earlier Historical Records of Ramses III. By the Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1930.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip9.html"&gt;OIP 9. Medinet Habu, Volume II. The Later Historical Records of Ramses III. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1932.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip25.html"&gt;OIP 25. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Karnak, Volume I. Ramses III's Temple with the Great Inclosure of Amon, Part I. The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1936.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip31.html"&gt;OIP 31. The Mastaba of Mereruka, Part I. Chambers A 1-10. By The Sakkara Expedition. Originally published in 1938.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip35.html"&gt;OIP 35. Reliefs and Inscriptions at Karnak, Volume II. Ramses III's Temple within the Great Inclosure of Amon, Part II; and Ramses III's Temple in the Precinct of Mut. By The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1936.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip84.html"&gt;OIP 84. Medinet Habu, Volume IV. The Temple Proper, Part II: The Re Chapel, the Royal Mortuary Complex, and Adjacent Rooms with Miscellaneous Material from the Pylons, the Forecourts, and the First Hypostyle Hall. By The Epigraphic Survey. Originally published in 1963.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip55.html"&gt;OIP 55. The Excavation of Medinet Habu, Volume VI. The Mortuary Temple of Ramses III, Part II. By Uvo Hölscher. With contributions by Rudolf Anthes. Originally published in 1951.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/misc/pioneer.html"&gt;Pioneer to the Past: The Story of James Henry Breasted, Archaeologist, Told by His Son Charles Breasted. By Charles Breasted. Reprint of the Charles Scribner's Sons 1943 Edition with New Foreword and Photographs. Published in 2009.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Oriental Institute &lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/ar/"&gt;Annual Reports&lt;/a&gt; for:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/ar/03-04/"&gt;2003-2004&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/ar/04-05/"&gt;2004-2005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/ar/05-06/"&gt;2005-2006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/ar/06-07/"&gt;2006-2007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/ar/07-08/"&gt;2007-2008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/ar/"&gt;2008-2009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a title="data:post.title" url="data:post.url" class="addthis_button"&gt;&lt;img src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/v2/lg-share-en.gif" alt="Bookmark and Share" style="border: 0pt none ;" height="16" width="125" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script type="text/javascript" src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js#username=xa-4b4cc6be5f7e0135"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;!-- AddThis Button END --&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7554426205875468670/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/01/oriental-institute-open-access.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7554426205875468670"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7554426205875468670"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/01/oriental-institute-open-access.html"
         title="Oriental Institute Open Access Publications in 2009"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
