<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7681363531070363162</id>
   <published>2010-05-28T11:00:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2010-05-28T11:10:27.214-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Projects from the UCLA Cultural Virtual Reality Laboratory</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[Two interesting projects from the  <a href="http://www.cvrlab.org/">UCLA Cultural Virtual Reality  Laboratory</a> :<br /><br /><a href="http://dlib.etc.ucla.edu/projects/Karnak/">Digital Karnak</a><br /><p><span style="font-size:85%;"></span></p><blockquote><p><span style="font-size:85%;">Through at least three thousand years of development, from local  shrine in a regional town to national center of power, the temple of  Amun-Ra at Karnak has known dramatic modifications tied in with  political shifts, religious reform and ritual changes.  As a legacy of a  culture where every aspect of life was permeated with religion, the  study of this temple complex touches upon every factor of human  existence in ancient Egypt. Karnak therefore presents an excellent entry  for understanding more about all aspects of ancient Egyptian culture  and the study of its legacy.</span></p><p><span style="font-size:85%;">The Digital Karnak Project aims to  make the site of Karnak more accessible to students and instructors in  the English-speaking world.  The features of this website have been  designed to provide college classrooms (and the interested public) with  easily accessible, up-to-date, expert material relating to the temple  precinct.  As part of this goal, a 3-D Virtual Reality model of the  temple was constructed, offering students a completely new way to view  the temple: reign-by-reign, following the complex patterns of royal  construction, modification and destruction that are now obscured by the  latest building phases at the site.   Footage of this model, as well as  original videos and maps, are accompanied by thematic essays written and  reviewed by Egyptologists to supply students and instructors with  reliable information in a digital and visually dynamic platform.  A  simplified version of the Virtual Reality model of the temple is also  made available in Google Earth, for a completely interactive experience.</span></p><p><span style="font-size:85%;">A  team of noted Egyptologists, educators, architects, and technologists  were brought together to develop learning resources related to the  Temple at Karnak in Egypt. The project had three primary goals: (1) to  assemble databases of information related to Karnak, (2) build an  interactive computer model of the site, and (3) create a series of  resources using the model and databases that are available online  free-of-charge through this website and can be easily used for  undergraduate education.</span></p><p><span style="font-size:85%;">The Digital Karnak Project combines the  experience and talent of two sections of the University of California at  Los Angeles (UCLA): the Experiential Technologies Center (ETC) and the  UCLA Encyclopedia of Egyptology (UEE). Directed by Dr.  Diane Favro  through the School of the Arts and Architecture with support from UCLA’s  Academic Technology Services, the ETC uses powerful information  technology tools to support creative and cross-disciplinary research in  archaeology, architecture, humanities, social sciences, and the  performing arts.  Dr. Willeke Wendrich of the Department of Near Eastern  Languages and Cultures is director of the UCLA Digital Humanities  Incubator Group (UDHIG) and the editor-in-chief of the online UCLA  Encyclopedia of Egyptology (UEE), a repository for scholarly content  related to Egypt.</span></p><p><span style="font-size:85%;">The Digital Karnak Project was funded in part  with a grant from the <a href="http://www.neh.gov/" target="_blank">National  Endowment of the Humanities (NEH)</a>.  Financial assistance was also  provided by the Steinmetz Family Trust. Staff assistance and computing  infrastructure was provided by UCLA's Institute for Digital Research and  Education (IDRE) and UCLA's Academic Technology Services (ATS).</span></p></blockquote><p><span style="font-size:85%;"></span></p><br /><br /><a href="http://dlib.etc.ucla.edu/projects/Forum/">Digital Roman Forum</a><br /><p><span style="font-size:85%;"></span></p><blockquote><p><span style="font-size:85%;">From 1997 to 2003 the <a href="http://www.cvrlab.org/">Cultural  Virtual Reality Laboratory</a> (CVRLab) created a digital model of the  Roman Forum as it appeared in late antiquity. The notional date of the  model is June 21, 400 A.D.</span></p><p><span style="font-size:85%;">The purpose of the modeling project was  to spatialize information and theories about how the Forum looked at  this moment in time, which was more or less the height of its  development as Rome's civic and cultural center. The digital model  includes over twenty features (buildings and major monuments) filling up  the western zone of the Roman Forum from the Temple of Vesta and Temple  of Antoninus and Faustina on the east to the Tabularium facing the  western slope of the Capitoline Hill.</span></p><p><span style="font-size:85%;">Thanks to archaeological  campaigns that started in the early nineteenth century and which  continue to the present day, these features can be seen in Rome today  and constitute one of the city's most important archaeological sites.  Their state of preservation varies from fair to poor; and the ruins seen  today represent a mixture of different phases in the life of the Forum.  As a result, understanding the Forum is a challenging task not only for  tourists but also for scholars. Almost as soon as the new excavations  started bringing the ancient remains to light, archaeologists such as  Canina, Huelsen, Gatteschi, and Gismondi started to create graphic and  physical reconstructions of how the Forum might have looked at specific  moments in time. The CVRLab digital model, created with the help of an  international Scientific Advisory Committee, is the latest example of  this perennial project.</span></p><p><span style="font-size:85%;">From the time the modeling project was  conceived, the investigators intended to present their results to  students, scholars and the general public. The digital model of the  Forum can be viewed on various hardware and software platforms. These  range from simple static views that can be displayed on a computer  monitor to dedicated visualization theaters costs hundreds of thousands  of dollars or more.</span></p><p><span style="font-size:85%;">With generous support from the National  Science Foundation, the CVRLab was able to create this Web site about  the digital Forum model from 2002 to 2005. The purposes of this site  are: (1) to use the Internet to permit free use and easy viewing of the  digital model by people all over the world; (2) to provide documentation  for the archaeological evidence and theories utilized to create the  model; and (3) to offer basic information about the individual features  comprising the digital model so that their history and cultural context  can be readily understood.</span></p></blockquote><!-- AddThis Button BEGIN --><br /><div><a name="data:post.title" id="data:post.url" onmouseover="'return" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onclick="return addthis_sendto()"><img src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif" alt="Bookmark and  Share so Your Real Friends Know that You Know" style="border: 0pt none;" height="16" width="125" /></a><br /><script type="text/javascript" src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986"></script></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7681363531070363162/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/05/projects-from-ucla-cultural-virtual.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7681363531070363162"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7681363531070363162"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/05/projects-from-ucla-cultural-virtual.html"
         title="Projects from the UCLA Cultural Virtual Reality Laboratory"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
