<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8803873462475252710</id>
   <published>2010-06-23T16:00:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2010-06-23T14:33:06.335-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Good News:  THE GETTY PROVIDES FREE ACCESS TO THE BHA ON ITS WEB SITE</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size:78%;">[Originally posted 4/1/10, updated 6/23/10 with the <a href="http://www.collegeart.org/news/2010/06/23/proquest-takes-over-the-bibliography-of-the-history-of-art-from-the-getty-research-institute/">CAA announcement about ProQues</a>t]</span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.collegeart.org/news/2010/06/23/proquest-takes-over-the-bibliography-of-the-history-of-art-from-the-getty-research-institute/" rel="bookmark" title="Permanent Link to ProQuest Takes over the  Bibliography of the History of Art from the Getty Research Institute"><span style="font-weight: bold;"></span>ProQuest  Takes over the Bibliography of the History of Art from the Getty  Research Institute</a><blockquote><a href="http://www.collegeart.org/news/2010/06/23/proquest-takes-over-the-bibliography-of-the-history-of-art-from-the-getty-research-institute/" rel="bookmark" title="Permanent Link to ProQuest Takes over the  Bibliography of the History of Art from the Getty Research Institute"><span style="font-size:85%;">The </span></a><span style="font-size:85%;"><a href="http://www.getty.edu/research/" target="_blank">Getty  Research Institute</a> (GRI) has announced  an agreement with <a href="http://www.proquest.com/" target="_blank">ProQuest</a>, an  information-technology firm supporting  global research, that will allow  ProQuest to take over the indexing of the <a href="http://library.getty.edu/bha" target="_blank">International  Bibliography of Art</a> (IBA), better known  as the <a href="http://library.getty.edu/bha" target="_blank">Bibliography of the  History of Art</a> (BHA). The agreement will not only  provide a secure  future for a resource considered central to the study of art  history,  but will also assure its continuing development and its accessibility to  researchers around the world... [<a href="http://www.collegeart.org/news/2010/06/23/proquest-takes-over-the-bibliography-of-the-history-of-art-from-the-getty-research-institute/">Read the rest</a>]<br /><br />...BHA was produced jointly by GRI and INIST until  2008. Thereafter, GRI  continued producing records under the new name of IBA  before budgetary  constraints led to the difficult decision to discontinue its  support  earlier this year. At this time, GRI made IBA (as well as the historical  data in BHA and RILA) freely available on its website, so the  historical data  would continue to aid researchers. Thomas Gaehtgens,  GRI director, confirms  that “we will continue to make the historical  BHA and RILA data available on the <a href="http://www.getty.edu/research/conducting_research/bha/" target="_blank"> website</a> free of charge to researchers who access  it.”</span><br /></blockquote><span style="font-size:85%;"></span><h2> </h2> <br />Following <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/03/bad-news-bibliography-of-history-of-art.html">announcements to subscribers</a> that the Bibliography of the History of Art (BHA) had been discontinued, the Getty Research Institute announced today <span style="font-size:100%;">[April 1, 2010]</span>:<br /><a href="http://www.getty.edu/research/conducting_research/bha/"><br />THE GETTY PROVIDES FREE ACCESS TO THE BHA ON ITS WEB SITE</a><blockquote><span style="font-size:85%;">As of April 1, 2010, the Bibliography of the History of Art (BHA) will be available free of charge on the Getty Web site at <a href="http://library.getty.edu/bha">http://library.getty.edu/bha</a>. Free Web access to BHA is an advantage not only to all traditional users of the database but also to such potential users as institutions in developing countries and independent scholars worldwide, who until now have been unable to afford access to the BHA. Since ending its collaboration with the Institut de l'Information Scientifique et Technique (INIST)–CNRS in December 2007, the Getty has been searching for partners to continue the production and distribution of BHA. This process has been complicated, and with no suitable arrangement immediately available, the Getty decided to act on its commitment to the scholarly community by providing access to BHA directly from its own Web site.<br /><br />BHA on the Getty Web site offers both basic and advanced search modules, and can be searched easily by subject, artist, author, article or journal title, and other elements. To search BHA, please visit, <a href="http://library.getty.edu/bha">http://library.getty.edu/bha</a>. Note that the database search includes both BHA (covering 1990-2007) and the <em>International Bibliography of Art</em> (IBA), covering the years 2008 and part of 2009. The <em>Répertoire de la litterature de l'art</em> (RILA), one of the predecessors of BHA, with records that cover 1975–1989, will be online by May 1.<br /></span></blockquote><a name="data:post.title" id="data:post.url" onmouseover="'return" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onclick="return addthis_sendto()"><img src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif" alt="Bookmark and Share so Your Real Friends Know that You Know" style="border: 0pt none;" height="16" width="125" /></a>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8803873462475252710/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/good-news-getty-provides-free-access-to.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8803873462475252710"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8803873462475252710"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/good-news-getty-provides-free-access-to.html"
         title="Good News:  THE GETTY PROVIDES FREE ACCESS TO THE BHA ON ITS WEB SITE"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
