<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-3868787750932032199</id>
   <published>2013-08-11T09:15:00.003-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-08-11T09:15:58.786-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Turkey"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">British Institute at Ankara Pottery Collections Online</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span class="views-field-title"><span class="field-content"><a href="http://www.biaatr.org/collections/index.php">British Institute at Ankara Pottery Collections</a></span></span><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span class="views-field-title"><span class="field-content"><img alt="http://www.biaatr.org/biaadesign/icons/institutename.jpg" class="decoded" src="http://www.biaatr.org/biaadesign/icons/institutename.jpg" /> </span></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Pottery collections</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Institute houses a collection of pottery assembled between the 1940s  and the 1970s. The majority is fragmentary pottery (and occasional  stone items) from surface surveys, such as the Central Anatolian Survey,  but there is also sample material from some important excavations  carried out in Turkey under the auspices of the British Institute such  as Mersin, Hacılar, Beycesultan and Catal Höyük; and some obsidian from  Ashikli Höyük. There are over 1000 boxes of material organised into 3  broad categories: survey, excavation and published material; as well as a  'study' and 'slide' collection. All periods are represented, from the  Neolithic to the Ottoman and although not all types of pottery from  Anatolia may be represented, examples of the vast majority of types can  be found.   <br /><br /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Other materials</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">As well as pottery, a limited range of other archaeological material, in  particular obsidian from Asikli Höyük, and a few scattered stone tools  at a range of survey sites of the 1960s and 70s. This is complemented by  a small geological collection including obsidian nodules from Ian  Todd's pioneering exploration of obsidian sources in Anatolia.  <br /><br /></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Collections database</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Collection database currently includes photographs and provenance  data (ie. source archaeological site) for the majority of the survey  material, with the excavated and study collections to follow soon. The  database was been designed to facilitate greater use of the collection  by scholars from around the world by publicising its contents, and  encouraging further publication or data generation. <br /><br />The web interface uses Google Maps as a mapping tool to show the  position of sites in the database, to the closest village. Clicking on  the yellow site icon opens the site definition page which shows  thumbnail images of the pottery from this site. The site page also shows  nearby sites and provides links to related informtion. This thumbnail  may be enlarged further, and the reference to the storage information of  the item obtained. <br /><br />The system has been designed to enable different material types  to be searched, so although only pottery has been currently included,  the obsidian and squeeze collections may be included in the future.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Browse the database</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"></span><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.biaatr.org/collections/browselist.php?browse=sites">Browse <b>full list of archaeological Sites</b> in the database</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.biaatr.org/collections/browseassemblages.php">Browse all pottery assemblages as thumbnails</a></span>   </li></ul></blockquote><br /><span class="views-field-title"><span class="field-content">&nbsp;</span></span>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/3868787750932032199/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/british-institute-at-ankara-pottery.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3868787750932032199"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/3868787750932032199"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/british-institute-at-ankara-pottery.html"
         title="British Institute at Ankara Pottery Collections Online"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
