<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8041536136759228658</id>
   <published>2011-09-26T09:20:00.003-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-09-26T09:20:31.655-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Digital Dead Sea Scrolls</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Announced today (9/26/2011 01:30:00 AM) in a press release from Google:&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2011/09/from-desert-to-web-bringing-dead-sea.html"&gt;From the desert to the web: bringing the Dead Sea Scrolls online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;h2 class="post-title"&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://dss.collections.imj.org.il/"&gt;The Digital Dead Sea Scrolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;img alt="http://dss.collections.imj.org.il/images/dss_banner.jpg" src="http://dss.collections.imj.org.il/images/dss_banner.jpg" /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Israel Museum welcomes you to the Dead Sea Scrolls Digital  Project, allowing users to examine and explore these most ancient  manuscripts from Second Temple times at a level of detail never before  possible. Developed in partnership with Google, the new website gives  users access to searchable, fast-loading, high-resolution images of the  scrolls, as well as short explanatory videos and background information  on the texts and their history. The Dead Sea Scrolls, which include the  oldest known biblical manuscripts in existence, offer critical insight  into Jewish society in the Land of Israel during the Second Temple  Period, the time of the birth of Christianity and Rabbinic Judaism. Five  complete scrolls from the Israel Museum have been digitized for the  project at this stage and are now accessible online.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;"We are privileged to house in the Israel Museum's Shrine of the Book  the best preserved and most complete Dead Sea Scrolls ever discovered,"  said James S. Snyder, Anne and Jerome Fisher Director of the Israel  Museum. "They are of paramount importance among the touchstones of  monotheistic world heritage, and they represent unique highlights of our  Museum's encyclopedic holdings. Now, through our partnership with  Google, we are able to bring these treasures to the broadest possible  public."&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The five Dead Sea Scrolls that have been digitized thus far include  the Great Isaiah Scroll, the Community Rule Scroll, the Commentary on  Habakkuk Scroll, the Temple Scroll, and the War Scroll, with search  queries on Google.com sending users directly to the online scrolls. All  five scrolls can be magnified so that users may examine texts in  exacting detail. Details invisible to the naked eye are made visible  through ultra-high resolution digital photography by photographer Ardon  Bar-Hama– at 1,200 mega pixels each, these images are almost two hundred  times higher in resolution than those produced by a standard camera.  Each picture utilized UV-protected flash tubes with an exposure of  1/4000th of a second to minimize damage to the fragile manuscripts. In  addition, the Great Isaiah Scroll may be searched by column, chapter,  and verse, and is accompanied by an English translation tool and by an  option for users to submit translations of verses in their own  languages. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;ul class="scrolls"&gt;&lt;li class="nav_right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dss.collections.imj.org.il/isaiah"&gt;Great Isaiah Scroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="nav_right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dss.collections.imj.org.il/temple"&gt;Temple Scroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="nav_right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dss.collections.imj.org.il/war"&gt;War Scroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="nav_right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dss.collections.imj.org.il/community"&gt;Community Rule Scroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="nav_right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://dss.collections.imj.org.il/habakkuk"&gt;Commentary on the Habakkuk Scroll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8041536136759228658/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/digital-dead-sea-scrolls.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8041536136759228658"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8041536136759228658"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/09/digital-dead-sea-scrolls.html"
         title="Digital Dead Sea Scrolls"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
