<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1690861655967948633</id>
   <published>2011-07-26T14:15:00.002-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-07-26T14:15:26.846-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">ANE Placemarks for Google Earth</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.anst.uu.se/olofpede/Links">ANE Placemarks for Google Earth</a><br />From <a href="http://www.anst.uu.se/olofpede/index.htm">Olof Pedersén</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">A preliminary set of placemarks (ANE.kmz) for Google Earth of a  selection of the most important archaeological sites in the Ancient Near  East can be <a href="http://www.anst.uu.se/olofpede/ANE.kmz">downloaded here</a> (as an alternative try right-click or ctrl-click).&nbsp;</span><br /><br />   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><img height="280" src="http://www.anst.uu.se/olofpede/ANEkmz1.gif" width="496" /></span><br />   <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">ANE.kmz works with Google Earth, which has to be downloaded (free at <a href="http://earth.google.com/">earth.google.com</a>).  When opened inside Google Earth, ANE.kmz gives, to the left, an  alphabetic list of ancient sites and, to the right, on the satellite  photo the same sites marked. For the moment, there are some 2500 sites   with modern names; among them some 400  have ancient names. Additions of  more sites are planned. </span><br />   <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ancient name is written without parenthesis. Modern name is within  parenthesis. Most sites have been identified on the satelite photos.  However, a few sites are only placed in the possible area, e.g. in a  village with the right name when the site may be outside (if so marked  with question mark ? after the parenthesis around the modern name).  Question mark after ancient name means that identification is not yet  proven. Question mark efter modern name (but before parenthesis around  the name) means spelling of name uncertain. Two question marks ?? at the  end indicate that it may not be a site but could possibly be a natural  hill.</span><br />   <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>New installation</strong>: With Google Earth already  installed, just double click the ANE.kmz icon. You find all  archaeological sites listed in your left panel of Google Earth under  Places/My Places. They can be rearranged, deleted or extended later on  by yourself. Double click the name of a city in your left panel in order  to go to the site. (Due to a program bug, people having Adobe Photoshop  may experience that this program try to take over the .kmz file. If so  choose open with Google Earth or open the .kmz file from inside Google  Earth.)</span><br />   <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">There are two options after the first session.  <br />    1. You never save when leaving Google earth. Then you keep your  ANE.kmz and double click the ikon each time you want to use it.  <br />    2. The alternative is that you save when leaving Google Earth when  beeing asked. Now you  keep the placemarks in your left panel. If you  use this possibility it is important that you delete the ANE.kmz file  because otherwise you will get duplicate names.</span><br />   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Updating</strong>: Two alternatives:  <br />    1. If you never saved before leaving Google earth you can just throw the old ANE.kmz away and use a new down loaded ANE.kmz.  <br />   2. If you saved, you have all cities listed inside Google Earth. Go  to your left panel and mark My Places (if you want to get rid of all  there) or all the site names from the old ANE list (if you have more to  keep in My Places). Delete what you have marked. Now double click the  new ANE.kmz icon and save when leaving Google Earth, if you want to keep  the new placemarks. If you don't delete the old ones, there will be  double names on every site in Google Earth. Delete the ANE.kmz file if  you saved the placemarkes inside Google Earth.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Until someone else comes up with a better, more permanent  solution, these placemarks may be updated. Any correction or addition  with coordinates could be sent to <a href="mailto:Olof.Pedersen@lingfil.uu.se">Olof Pedersén</a>. No support is offered. </span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1690861655967948633/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/07/ane-placemarks-for-google-earth.html#comment-form"
         title="3 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1690861655967948633"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1690861655967948633"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/07/ane-placemarks-for-google-earth.html"
         title="ANE Placemarks for Google Earth"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
