<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8502554799693075831</id>
   <published>2012-07-11T09:52:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-07-13T08:43:49.074-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ASCSA"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Classics"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Aegean"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">Hesperia Goes Open Access!</title>
   <content type="html">In a notice this morning,  Andrew Reinhard, Director of &lt;a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications"&gt;Publications&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/"&gt;American School of Classical Studies at Athens&lt;/a&gt; has made the following important announcement. Andrew Reinhard and his colleagues in the Publications Department and the Publications Committee of the School’s Managing Committee are to be congratulated for making this important move.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/News/newsDetails/hesperia-provides-open-access-to-more-than-1500-articles"&gt;Hesperia Provides Open Access to More than 1,500 Articles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;07/11/2012&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The American School of Classical Studies at Athens (ASCSA) continues  its strong commitment to open scholarship by providing easy, free access  to past issues of &lt;i&gt;Hesperia&lt;/i&gt;. The quarterly joins nearly 1,200 other international open access journals in ancient studies as listed in &lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html"&gt;The Ancient World Online&lt;/a&gt;. As of July 11th, over 1,500 &lt;i&gt;Hesperia&lt;/i&gt; articles (1932 to 2009) are available as downloadable PDFs on the ASCSA’s &lt;a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/hesp-open-access"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Through a content-sharing agreement negotiated between the ASCSA and &lt;a href="http://www.jstor.org/action/showPublication?journalCode=hesperia"&gt;JSTOR&lt;/a&gt;,  the online host of the journal, all articles beyond the three-year  “moving wall” can be freely distributed on the School’s website for  individual use. This initiative was unanimously endorsed by the  Publications Committee of the School’s Managing Committee.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; “Making &lt;i&gt;Hesperia&lt;/i&gt; open access helps the journal fulfill the  ASCSA’s mission of providing resources for scholarly work, and  disseminating research,” Andrew Reinhard, the ASCSA’s Director of  Publications, said. “We’re providing information on the history and  archaeology of the Greek world to as wide an audience as possible. Our  content is more readily available to anyone who wants to use it.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hesperia&lt;/i&gt; Editor Tracey Cullen agrees. “It is exciting to be able to offer subscribers and non-subscribers alike nearly the whole run of &lt;i&gt;Hesperia&lt;/i&gt; on the ASCSA website. In addition to contributing to scholarship in our field, open access to &lt;i&gt;Hesperia&lt;/i&gt; will draw in new readers and heighten the journal's profile around the world. I'm thrilled.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; The webpage is intended primarily for the use of individuals who do not  have easy access to JSTOR. Users can find specific articles by using  the page’s search box that automatically filters the results. Readers  can access an article by clicking on its “Download” link and reading  on-screen with PDF software (e.g., &lt;a href="http://get.adobe.com/reader/?promoid=BUIGO"&gt;Adobe Reader&lt;/a&gt;),  or they can save the article to a computer, tablet, or other reading  device. Online access is not required to read these articles once they  have been downloaded, and there is no limit to the number of articles  that readers can save for future use.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; “Not everyone has JSTOR access and not everyone has an Internet  connection in the field,” Reinhard said. “Making these articles freely  available without requiring an Internet connection or even a  subscription should help people have the information they need on  whatever device they’re using in the trench, camp, and excavation  house.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; For users with an Internet connection and JSTOR access, ASCSA also hosts a &lt;a href="http://www.ascsa.edu.gr/index.php/publications/hesperia/volumes"&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt; for browsing issues for each volume year for the full run of &lt;i&gt;Hesperia&lt;/i&gt;.  Readers can search here by author, title, site, period, or keyword.  Clicking on an issue number calls up all articles in that issue.  Clicking on an article’s title retrieves metadata about that article and  a stable link to its home on JSTOR.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; The articles on the open access page are free of digital rights management (DRM), but are protected under the Creative Commons &lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/"&gt;BY-NC license&lt;/a&gt; that allows for downloading and sharing articles, and require that the  ASCSA and Hesperia be credited as the source. The articles cannot be  used for commercial purposes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; Each January another year of &lt;i&gt;Hesperia&lt;/i&gt; will be made available  as open access. The 2010 volume year will be posted online in time for  the 2013 AIA/APA joint annual meeting in Seattle.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; Questions about open access &lt;i&gt;Hesperia&lt;/i&gt; can be directed to &lt;a href="http://draft.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=116259103207720939"&gt;Andrew Reinhard&lt;/a&gt;, Director of Publications.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;See also:&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/06/open-linked-hesperia-bibliographic.html"&gt;Open Linked Hesperia Bibliographic Citations&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/open-access-publications-publications.html"&gt;Open Access Publications:  Publications of the American School of Classical Studies at Athens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 100%;"&gt;See the full &lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html"&gt;List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8502554799693075831/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/hesperia-goes-open-access.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8502554799693075831"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8502554799693075831"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/hesperia-goes-open-access.html"
         title="Hesperia Goes Open Access!"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
   <georss:featurename>Souidias 54, Athens 11521, Greece</georss:featurename>
   <georss:point>37.9797501 23.7484549</georss:point>
   <georss:box>37.978185599999996 23.745987399999997 37.9813146 23.7509224</georss:box>
</entry>
