<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-819832869923324809</id>
   <published>2014-01-15T09:30:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2014-01-15T09:56:25.440-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Arabic"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Reception"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Studia graeco-arabica</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;[First posted in AWOL 2 April 2011. Updated 15 January 2014]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/index.php?id=20"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/immagini/testata.jpg" class="decoded" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/immagini/testata.jpg" height="42" width="400" /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Studia graeco-arabica&lt;/i&gt; is the journal on line of the European Research Council Advanced Grant 249431 &lt;a href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Greek into Arabic. Philosophical Concepts and Linguistic Bridges&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  It features critical articles and reviews on the transmission of  philosophical and scientific texts from and into various languages –  Greek, Syriac, Arabic, and Latin – from late Antiquity to the Middle  Ages and Renaissance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/SGA_3-2013-full-text.pdf"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013 (full text)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;                   &lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/Luna_SGA_3-2013-full-text.pdf"&gt;Boéthos de Sidon sur les relatifs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concetta Luna&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The Peripatetic philosopher Boethus of Sidon (mid-first century BC),  a pupil of Andronicus of Rhodes, is well-known for his commentary on  Aristotle’s "Categories", whose fragments are transmitted by later  commentators together with testimonia about it. In his exegesis of the  "Categories", Boethus especially focused on the category of relation  (Cat. 7), on which he wrote a specific treatise, arguing against the  Stoics for the unity of the category of relation. The present paper  offers a translation and analysis of Boethus’ fragments on relation, all  of which are preserved in Simplicius’ commentary on the "Categories".     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/Hugonnard-Roche_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Sur la lecture tardo-antique du Peri Hermeneias d’Aristote: Paul le Perse et la tradition d’ Ammonius&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Henri Hugonnard-Roche&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The aim of this paper is to provide the critical edition, with  translation and commentary, of a short Syriac treatise by Paul the  Persian (6th century) about Aristotle’s Peri Hermeneias. The text is  edited from a unique manuscript, preserved in a convent near Mosul  (Iraq): Notre-Dame des Semences 53. The commentary examines in detail  Paul’s Syriac text by comparison with the Greek commentaries by Ammonius  and Stephanus on the Peri Hermeneias. From this comparison, the evident  influence of the Greek Ammonian tradition on the Syro-oriental  philosophical milieu will become clear. The study will also substantiate  the claim that, in Paul’s eyes, the treatise of Aristotle does not deal  with propositions, seen as the components of the syllogism, but with  the contradictory pairs of propositions. Moreover, Paul approaches the  analysis of contradiction by interpreting the propositions in terms of  their material subject.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/Di-Branco_SGA-3-2013.pdf"&gt;Ismailiti a Bisanzio. Immagini e presenze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marco Di Branco&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    In recent past the already abundant bibliography on the Ismā‘īlī  Nizārī sect, known in the Western world since the 12th century with the  inappropriate and hostile definition of ‘Assassins sect’, was enriched  by fundamental contributions of Farhad Daftary, co-director and head of  the Department of Academic Research and Publications at the Institute of  Ismaili Studies. However, in his work are not even mentioned some  Byzantine sources on the sect, which are of considerable interest, and  that scholarship has taken into account only seldom. The present paper  can be regarded as a sort of small Appendix to Daftary’s work. It  consists of two distinct parts: the first is dedicated to the image of  the Ismāʿīlīs in the Byzantine sources (Anna Comnena, John Phokas and  Niketas Choniates); the second one is an analysis of the dossier  concerning a Fatimid dā‘ī sent to Constantinople.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/Diez_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Les antiquités gréco-romaines entre al-Makīn ibn al-ʿAmīd et ibn Ḫaldūn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Martino Diez&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The Coptic Historian al-Makīn Ǧirǧis ibn al-ʿAmīd (1206 - after  1280) is the author of a universal history known as al-Maǧmūʿ al-Mubārak  (‘The blessed collection’). This work is divided into two parts: a  section on pre-Islamic history, still unpublished, and a summary of  Islamic history, edited by Erpenius in 1625 and completed by Claude  Cahen. The article analyzes the two recensions of the first part of the  Maǧmūʿ through the comparison of three manuscripts, in particular as  regards the sections on Hellenistic, Roman and Byzantine history. After  discussing the particular version of the Testimonium Flavianum which can  be found in the longer recension of the Maǧmūʿ, the article traces the  fortune of al-Makīn in subsequent Islamic historiography, especially  al-Qalqašandī, al-Maqrīzī and Ibn Ḫaldūn.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-Arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/BOCHUM_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Griechische  Wissenschaft in arabischer Sprache. Ein griechisch-arabisches  Fachwörterbuch der internationalenWissensgesellschaft im klassischen  Islam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gerhard Endress, Rüdiger Arnzen, Yury Arzhanov&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The project “Glossarium Graeco-Arabicum” was launched in 1980 at the  Seminar für Orientalistik und Islamwissenschaft (Ruhr-Universität  Bochum, Germany). First supported by the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft  (German Research Foundation) for several years, it forms since 2010 a  part of the ERC Project Ideas “Greek into Arabic. Philosophical Concepts  and Linguistic Bridges” (Advanced Grant 249431).  The object of the project “Glossarium Graeco-Arabicum” is to make  available the lexical, grammatical and conceptual content of the Arabic  translations of Greek scientific and philosophical works, made from the  eighth to the tenth century A.D., and forming the basis of the  scientific activity in Mediaeval Islam. A group organized by Gerhard  Endress (Bochum) and working in cooperation with Dimitri Gutas (Yale  University, New Haven, Conn.) compiled the lexical materials first on  index cards (ca. 80,000), and then started to prepare the Greek and  Arabic Lexicon , presenting the lexical data in a rationalized and systematic way.  This is published in print by E.J. Brill since 1992. The online Database “Glossarium Græco-Arabicum”   makes available the files which have not yet been published in the  analytical reference dictionary GALex, and comprises Arabic roots from  the letter ǧīm to the end of the Arabic alphabet. The database provides  search facilities for Greek words, Arabic words and roots, as well as  the authors and titles of the source texts.       &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/BOZZI_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;G2A:  a Web application to study, annotate and scholarly edit ancient texts  and their aligned translations.  Part I. General model of the  computational philology application&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrea Bozzi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    This paper presents the general model of a Web application for  computational philology and describes the modules implemented by ILC-CNR  in Pisa for the ERC project Ideas “Greek into Arabic. Philosophical  Concepts and Linguistic Bridges” ADG 249431 (acronym: Greek into  Arabic). The main principles on which the model is based are modularity,  flexibility and development of the software according to open source  criteria. These elements make it possible to include additional  components in the modular structure, as well as components essential to  the Greek into Arabic project (modularity), thus allowing the  application to extend its functions to many other philological fields,  from classical and medieval philology to genetic criticism and philology  of ancient printed texts (flexibility). Dissemination of this  application, especially in the research and academic fields, is  guaranteed by the fact that its development is performed using  internationally acknowledged systems of standard mark-up language and  tools with no copyright restrictions (open source). In Part II a  preliminary version of the user manual of G2A Web application is  provided.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/MARCHI_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Part II. Towards a user manual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simone Marchi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The present contribution describes the current operating procedures  of the G2A application. The system is still under development at the  Institute of Computational Linguistics (ILC/CNR, Area della ricerca di  Pisa); therefore, all the functions described in this provisional user  manual should be considered as an exemplification of the general model  described by Andrea Bozzi in Part I.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/BOSCHETTI_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Annotations in collaborative environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Federico Boschetti&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    This article discusses methodological aspects of the Greek into  Arabic Web Application related to the annotation system. Collaborative  environments for the philological studies manage multiple versions both  of the reference edition with digital variants and of linguistic and  exegetical annotations. The system must verify and maintain the  consistency of interrelated information, which can change  asynchronously. Strategies to align different versions of texts and  annotations, in order to update the internal references and notify the  users to verify the content consistency, are illustrated. Structural  aspects that involve the granularity and overlapping of annotations are  discussed, taking into account also that linguistic annotations  automatically generated by morphological parsers can be the basis for  extended comments in natural language. Finally, the article illustrates  which features related to the annotation system are yet implemented in  the G2A Web Application.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/NAHLI_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Computational contributions for Arabic language processing Part I. The automatic morphologic analysis of Arabic texts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ouafae Nahli&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The aim of this paper is to describe our work on the project “Greek  into Arabic”, in which we faced some problems of ambiguity inherent to  the Arabic language. Difficulties arose in the various stages of  automatic processing of the Arabic version of Plotinus, the text which  lies at the core of our project. Part I highlights the needs that led us  to update the morphological engine AraMorph in order to optimize its  morpho-syntactic analysis. Even if the engine has been optimized, a  digital lexical source for better use of the system is still lacking.  Part II presents a methodology exploiting the internal structure of the  Arabic lexicographic encyclopaedia Lisān al-ʿarab, which allows  automatic extraction of the roots and derived lemmas. The outcome of  this work is a useful resource for morphological analysis of Arabic,  either in its own right, or to enrich already existing resources.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/NAHLI-GIOVANNETTI_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Part II. Lisān al-ʿarab as a source of lexical and morphological knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ouafae Nahli, Emiliano Giovannetti&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The following sections illustrate a part of the study on the  morphology of the Arabic language which is carried on within the  framework of the ERC project Greek into Arabic. Philosophical Concepts  and Linguistic Bridges ADG 249431. We used the Arabic lexicographic  encyclopaedia Lisān al-ʿarab and, thanks to the regularity of its  structure, we developed a system for the extraction of morphologically  labelled word sequences, to be exploited for morphological analysis  purposes.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/DEL-GROSSO_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Indexing techniques and variant readings management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angelo Mario Del Grosso&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    This paper illustrates indexing routines developed for the G2A Web  Application, a philological system totally open source designed by the  Team of the ILC-CNR of Pisa within the context of the ERC project Greek  into Arabic. Philosophical Concepts and Linguistic Bridges (Ideas AdG  249431). Section 1 introduces the concept of ‘index’ in this peculiar  field. The indexing process implemented by the ILC-CNR Team for the G2A  Web Application is illustrated in Section 2. Section 3 discusses the  component of textual criticism.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/BOOK-ANNOUNCEMENTS-SYR_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Book Announcements - Syriac Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Henri Hugonnard-Roche, Yury Arzanhov&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/BOOK-ANNOUNCEMENTS_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Book Announcements&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristina D'Ancona, Cleophea Ferrari, Cecilia Martini Bonadeo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;    &lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" height="19" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;    &lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 3 / 2013&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/REVIEWS_SGA_3-2013.pdf"&gt;Reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. Ulacco, M. Zambon, G. Chemi, C. Ferrari, C. D'Ancona, J. Janssens ...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    [Angela Ulacco] M.&amp;nbsp;Regali, Il Poeta e il Demiurgo. Teoria e prassi  della produzione letteraria nel Timeo e nel Crizia di Platone, Academia  Verlag, Sankt Augustin 2012 (International Plato Studies 30), p.&amp;nbsp;213 /  [Marco Zambon] D. Dainese, Passibilità divina, Città Nuova, Roma 2012  (Fundamentis novis, 2), p. 306 / [Germana Chemi] Agostino, La trinità, a  cura di Giovanni Catapano e Beatrice Cillerai, Bompiani (Il pensiero  occidentale), Milano 2012, p. 1315 / [Germana Chemi] Sebastian R.P.  Gertz, Death and Immortality in Late Neoplatonism. Studies on the  Ancient Commentaries on Plato’s Phaedo, Brill, Leiden - Boston 2011,  p.&amp;nbsp;223 / [Cleophea Ferrari] Grundriß der Geschichte der Philosophie  begründet von Friedrich Überweg, völlig neu bearbeitete Ausgabe  herausgegeben von Helmut Holzhey. Philosophie in der islamischen Welt 1  (8.&amp;nbsp;-10.&amp;nbsp;Jahrhundert), herausgegeben von Ulrich Rudolph unter Mitarbeit  von Renate Würsch, Basel 2012, p.&amp;nbsp;612 / [Cristina D'Ancona] Revelation  and Falsification. The Kitāb al-qirā ʾāt of Aḥmad b. Muḥammad  al-Sayyārī. Critical Edition with an Introduction and Notes by Etan  Kohlberg and Mohammad Ali Amir-Moezzi, Brill, Leiden -&amp;nbsp;Boston 2009,  p.&amp;nbsp;vii + 363, Arabic Text, p.&amp;nbsp;٢٠١ - ١ (Texts and Studies on the Qurʾān,  4) / [Marco Di Branco] Le Roman d’ Alexandre à Tombouctou. Histoire du  Bicornu. Le manuscript interrompu, trad. de G.&amp;nbsp;Bohas, A. Saguer et A.  Sinno, Arles, Editions Actes Sud - École Normale Supérieure de Lyon -  Bibliothèque Mamma Haidara, Paris 2012 (Les Manuscrits de Tombouctou),  p.&amp;nbsp;240 / [Cecilia Martini Bonadeo] Olga Lizzini, Avicenna, Carocci  Editore, Roma 2012 (Pensatori, 28), p.&amp;nbsp;339 / [Jules Janssens] Teresa De  Franco, Primati e principi della medicina di Avicenna (Ibn Sina),  Levante Editore, Bari 2009 (Hermes. Collana di Ermeneutica della storia,  1), p. 168 / [Elisa Coda] Angela&amp;nbsp;Guidi, Amour et Sagesse. Les Dialogues  d’amour de Judah Abravanel dans la tradition salomonienne, Brill,  Leiden&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;Boston&amp;nbsp;2011 (Studies in Jewish History and Culture,&amp;nbsp;32),  p.&amp;nbsp;363.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;blockquote class="tr_bq"&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news" style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/studia_graeco-arabica_II_2012_full_text.pdf"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds (Full Text)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/saffrey.pdf"&gt;Prologue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Henri Dominique Saffrey&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/luna.pdf"&gt;La philologie comme science de l’esprit: la contribution d’Alain Segonds à la critique textuelle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Concetta Luna&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/goulet.pdf"&gt;Mais qui était donc le gendre de la sœur de Priscus? Enquête sur les philosophes d’Athènes au IVe siècle après J.-Chr.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Richard Goulet&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    We happen to lack information about philosophical life in Athens  during the IVth century A.D., and the Neoplatonic school of Plutarch,  Syrianus and Proclus is rather loosely connected to earlier  philosophical currents such as Porphyrian or Iamblichean Neoplatonism.  E.R. Dodds once searched for “missing links” in this local intellectual  history. A prosopographical study of a few second rank individuals, like  Priscus the Thesprotian, trained in the Iamblichean school of Aidesius  in Pergamon, or Iamblichus II of Apamea, grandson and nephew of two  direct disciples of Iamblichus I of Chalcis, who both seem to have  taught philosophy in Athens in the second part of the century and who  could have been relatives by marriage, may help to put some flesh on the  bones of a scarce documentation.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/ferroni.pdf"&gt;Due note a Plotino: Enneadi IV 7[2], 8.2 e V 9[5], 12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lorenzo Ferroni&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    This article aims to show how, in two different passages, the text  attested by the Medieval sources can be retained, notwithstanding the  doubts of several scholars who tried to amend it. A closer look at the  text and its syntax allows the reader to follow the course of Plotinus’  arguments and to reach a better understanding of their meaning.      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/chiaradonna.pdf"&gt;Nota su partecipazione e atto d'essere nel neoplatonismo: l'anonimo Commento al "Parmenide"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Riccardo Chiaradonna&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The anonymous commentator on Plato’s "Parmenides" provides a  sophisticated interpretation of Plat., Parm. 142 B 5-6, in which he aims  to show that the One-Being can (under certain conditions) be thought to  participate in the first One above Being (Anonym., In Parm., XI-XII).  In doing so, the commentator sets out two different explanations of the  verb μετέχειν. The first explanation is closely reminiscent of the  Peripatetic doctrine of essential predication, whereas the second one  may contain an adaptation of the Stoic lektón (a theory which Longinus,  Porphyry’s first master, significantly linked to the theory of Ideas).      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/martone.pdf"&gt;La struttura del De Anima di Giamblico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lucrezia Iris Martone&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    Iamblichus’ philosophic positions are increasingly studied nowadays,  after having been clouded by his religious claims in favour of  ‘theurgy’. The De Anima proves to be crucial in order to evaluate his  philosophy. However, this work is only fragmentarily recorded, in the  order given by Stobaeus. This article advances a new tentative order of  the fragments, different from Festugière’s one, that is endorsed in the  2002 edition by Finamore and Dillon.      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/zambon.pdf"&gt;"A servizio della verità": Didimo il Cieco 'lettore' di Aristotele&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Marco Zambon&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The present survey investigates the quotations, references, and  mentions of Aristotle’s name and the use of his doctrines in Didymus the  Blind’s writings. It is clear from this that the latter had direct  knowledge of the Organon and probably also of the Nicomachean Ethics. It  is also possible that Didymus had studied other works of Aristotle, but  there is less evidence of this. Almost all of the explicit quotations  are found in the commentaries on the Psalms and the Ecclesiastes, i.e.  in Didymus’ lectures; on the contrary, the commentaries composed to  circulate in written form make no explicit reference to Aristotle.      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/ronconi.pdf"&gt;Le corpus aristotélicien du Paris gr. 1853 et les cercles érudits à Byzance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Filippo Ronconi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    Parisinus gr. 1853, a key witness to the Corpus Aristotelicum, is  usually believed to be the medieval copy of an ancient Corpus.  Nevertheless, the analysis of its codicological, paleographic and  textual features strongly suggests that it is built up out of smaller  items, probably copied in different milieux from different exemplars,  and combined in a single manuscript by an unknown scholar in tenth  century Constantinople.      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/hugonnard-roche.pdf"&gt;Le commentaire syriaque de Probus sur l’Isagoge de Porphyre. Une étude préliminaire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Henri Hugonnard-Roche&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The commentary on Porphyry’s "Isagoge" by Probus (VIth century) is  the only one  important Syriac commentary preserved of that period, but  the major part of the text remained so far inedited. The aim of this  paper is to set out the whole text from the manuscripts and to give an  idea of its contents by putting it in its historical context. The paper  examines briefly the relationship between Probus’ commentary and the  Greek commentaries by Ammonius, Elias and David, and shows that the  Syriac text fits into the Alexandrian tradition.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/baffioni.pdf"&gt;Il manoscritto Ambrosiano arabo "&amp;amp; 105 sup." e la trasmissione delle opere di logica greca in arabo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Carmela Baffioni&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    This article contains general remarks on the manuscript &amp;amp; 105  sup. preserved in the Biblioteca Ambrosiana, Milan. It contains (i) a  version of Porphyry’s "Isagoge"; (ii) a titleless text; and (iii) a  treatise "On virtues" considered as pseudo-Aristotelian by R. Traini.  The translation of the "Isagoge" is anonymous and defective. Up to now,  al-Dimašqī’s translation is known, which Abū l-Faraǧ ibn al-Ṭayyib may  have used for his commentary, recognized in the Bodleian manuscript  Marsh 28. The version provided in the Ambrosiana manuscript seems to  differ from al-Dimašqī’s, and may be earlier. A solution to the problem  is found in the second text contained in the manuscript. It is a  translation of the "De Interpretatione" up to 17 b 14, and it perfectly  coincides with the fragment in the Berlin manuscript Syr. 88, edited by  Hoffmann in 1869. The identity between these texts that appear as  testimonies of a version different from the one by Isḥāq ibn Ḥunayn, and  directly derived from Syriac, allows to hypothesize that the  ‘Porphyrius Ambrosianus’ can also be a copy of the version of the  Isagoge preserved in the Berlin manuscript, as is shown by some formal  and stylistic similarities. Further studies will establish whether the  authorship of these versions can be reported to a single author, who may  have influenced Isḥāq ibn Ḥunayn. The numerous similarities of the  ‘Porphyrius Ambrosianus’ with Ibn al-Ṭayyib are also remarkable: the  latter may have known that version. It is to be noted, finally, that the  third text contained in the Ambrosiana manuscript is also linked to Ibn  al-Ṭayyib, and is found in the Berlin manuscript too. The Ambrosiana  manuscript might be a partial copy of the manuscript Syr. 88.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/dibranco.pdf"&gt;Un’ istituzione sasanide? Il Bayt al-ḥikma e il movimento di traduzione&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Marco Di Branco&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The nature and precise activitiy of the bayt al-ḥikma (House of  Wisdom) is matter of debate. Earlier scholarship connected to it the  translations from Greek of scientific and philosophical works, a  position challenged by D.&amp;nbsp;Gutas, who presents this library as a part of  the Sasanian administrative apparatus adopted under the early ‘Abbāsids  with no direct involvement in the translations from Greek. This paper  claims that there is no hard evidence pointing to a Sasanian origin of  this institution, and contends that some scholars working in it had an  active role in the translation movement from Greek into Arabic.      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/endress.pdf"&gt;Platonizing  Aristotle. The Concept of ‘Spiritual’ (rūḥānī) as a Keyword of the  Neoplatonic Strand in Early Arabic Aristotelianism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gerhard Endress&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    Working with the assumption that translation is interpretation, it  is shown in this article that rūḥ and its cognate words translate not  only πνεῦμα, but also the words for the intellectual activity (e.g.,  νοερός), and even the words for the divine realm, a move that paves the  way to the Neoplatonized Aristotle of the Arabic tradition.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/d_ancona.pdf"&gt;Le traité de Plotin Sur les trois substances qui sont des principes dans le corpus néoplatonicien arabe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cristina D'Ancona&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The paper examines the Arabic version of Plotinus’ treatise "On the  Three Principal Hypostases" (V 1[10]). First, a survey of the works that  contain this version is presented: the "pseudo-Theology" of Aristotle  and the “Sayings of the Greek Sage”. Then, a passage is examined, which  features in both works. It deals with the generation of Intellect from  the One, describing the Intellect as the “first image” of the One. This  topic features also in passages of the "Theol." and the “Sayings” that  antecede the translation itself. This implies that the author of these  passages was already acquainted with a Plotinian text that, in the flow  of both works as they have come down to us, comes later. The author lays  emphasis on the idea of Intellect as the “first image” of the One,  transforming it into the topic of the immediate creation of Intellect,  and of the creation of everything else through Intellect. This doctrine,  that will be inspiring for Avicenna, lies at the core of the "Liber de  Causis".     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/martinibonadeo.pdf"&gt;Il concetto di 'essere' dall’Aristotele greco alla lingua araba&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cecilia Martini Bonadeo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The problem of the translation into Arabic of the Greek  philosophical terminology and in particular of the verb 'to be', and the  reflection on the possible conditioning that every natural language can  operate in a completely unconscious way in thinking and in the  formulation of concepts was faced by Arabic-speaking philosophers well  before by the modern linguists. By analyzing the Arabic direct and  indirect tradition of "Metaphysics Delta" 7, in which Aristotle speaks  of the different meanings of being, τὸ ὄν, this study tries to test the  awareness of these problems in the early translators of Greek  philosophical and scientific heritage into Arabic language, such as the  Christian Usṭāṯ, translator of the circle of al-Kindī, and in the  following generations of philosophers such as al-Fārābī, Avicenna and  Averroes.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/zonta.pdf"&gt;'Sostanza',  'Essenza' e 'Quiddità' nelle diverse lingue delle letterature  filosofiche medievali: una proposta di comparazione storico-linguistica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mauro Zonta&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    The linguistic history of three main Aristotelian philosophical  terms, ‘substance’, ‘essence’ and ‘quiddity’, in the Medieval written  languages of Europe and of Near and Middle East has not yet been  reconstructed in detail. Here, a tentative reconstruction of it is  suggested, through a comparison of their different use in Syriac,  Coptic, Classical Ethiopic (ge‘ez), Armenian, Georgian, Arabic, Middle  Persian, Sogdian and Sanskrit, as well as in Latin and Medieval Hebrew.  From this reconstruction, the evident influence of Greek on European and  Near Eastern philosophical terminology is clear, but also the probable  influence of some Sanskrit and Middle Persian terms on Medieval Arabic  philosophical language is pointed out.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/sebti.pdf"&gt;La question de l’authenticité de l’Épître des états de l’âme (Risāla fī aḥwāl al-nafs) d’Avicenne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meryem Sebti&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    Avicenna's Risāla fī aḥwāl al-nafs is quite a problematic text. A  large part of this epistle is identical with the psychological part of  the Kitāb al-Naǧāt. Some scholars think that this epistle has been  written before the Naǧat and was inserted by Avicenna afterwards in this  book; others, on the contrary, consider that it has been extracted from  it. In this paper, chapters I, XIII and XVI of this epistle are  inspected in detail, thus allowing to establish that they are not  genuinely Avicennian. We therefore consider that the Risāla fī aḥwāl  al-nafs, as we know it today, has not been put together by Avicenna  himself. The epistle is composed by chapters extracted from the Naǧāt to  which three chapters – not written by Avicenna – have been added.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/"&gt;Alexander of Aphrodisias in Themistius’ Paraphrase of the De Caelo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Elisa Coda&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    This paper examines some fragments of Alexander of Aphrodisias’ lost  commentary on Aristotle’s De Caelo preserved in Themistius’ paraphrase  of this work. Its aim is to make available the list of Themistius’  explicit quotations of Alexander on the basis of the Hebrew text of the  paraphrase, checked against the manuscript Firenze, Biblioteca Nazionale  Centrale, II.II.528. It also examines in detail a selection of these  passages. It will appear that some of Alexander’s fragments, as  preserved by Themistius, can be recovered in their original wording and  meaning only on the basis of the Hebrew text. The first two passages,  discussed in section 1, are meant to substantiate this claim. The third  passage, discussed in section 2, raises a doctrinal question. In the  Appendix, I provide a list of Alexander’s passages explicitly quoted by  Themistius. For each quotation, the reference to the folios and lines of  the Florence MS is given. This is especially necessary, in  consideration of the differences between the Hebrew text as edited and  as preserved in the MSS.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/guidi.pdf"&gt;Un  néophyte entre l’Italie et la France au milieu du XVIe siècle: la  “Réponse de Ludovico Carretto à un talmudiste” (ms. Paris BnF hébr. 753,  ff. 1r-19v)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Angela Guidi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    This article deals with some aspects of the intellectual activity of  the Jew convert to Christianity Ludovico Carretto (alias Todros  ha-Cohen, c.1500 - post 1553), especially by examining and editing  previously unstudied manuscript material. The author reconstructs some  aspects of Carretto’s philosophic and kabbalist background, suggesting  his dependence from Christian authors as Francesco Zorzi, Petrus Galatin  or Cornelius Agrippa. The study of Carretto’s response to an anonymous  Jew contained in the ms. Paris BnF hébr. 753 brings to light some new  pieces of information on Jewish reaction to the Christian use of Hebrew  texts.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 2 / 2012. In memoriam Alain-Philippe Segonds&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/marzillo.pdf"&gt;Attempt of a New Etymology for the Orphic divinity Phanes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Patrizia Marzillo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    In his own copy of Estienne’s "Poiêsis philosophos", Scaliger  laconically comments on fr. 241 Bernabé, inscribing Joseph’s epithet of  Gn 41, 45 in Hebrew. Through a reconstruction of Scaliger’s original  intention and of the linguistic associations he built, a new etymology  for the Orphic divinity Phanes is proposed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/SGA_1_2011.pdf"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/SGA_1_2011.pdf"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 1 / 2011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 1 / 2011&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/1Cufalo_ultimo.pdf"&gt;Scolî medievali e tradizione antica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Domenico Cufalo&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This paper examines the relationship between some scholia to the  IIId book of Plato’s Republic, Proclus’ commentary on it, and the  so-called Chrestomathia, a work that the manuscripts attribute to the  Neoplatonic philosopher himself. The conclusion is that the relationship  between the three texts is highly problematic, and that we cannot think  of a simple and direct derivation from one another. The author of the  scholia probably made use of texts different from those that have come  down to us, or alternatively he has reworked his sources in a personal  way.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 1 / 2011&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/2SGA_I_ultimo.pdf"&gt;Platonic and Neoplatonic Terminology for Being in Arabic translation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cristina D'Ancona&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Arabic version of the Enneads is the earliest datable text in  which appears the term "anniyya", that features in Avicenna’s  metaphysics and lies in the background of the Latin definition of the  Causa prima as esse tantum, typical of the Liber de Causis. This paper  examines some examples of the use of "to be" in the Arabic translation  of the Enneads. It also discusses the description of the First Cause as  ‘pure Being’ or ‘first Being’ in the Arabic Plotinus, and compares it  with the Divine Names of the pseudo-Dionysius.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text_container" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;div class="icona"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="text"&gt;&lt;div class="data_text"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 1 / 2011&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/3wafae_utlimo.pdf"&gt;Yaḥyā ibn ‘Adī sulla differenza fra la logica greca e la grammatica araba&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ouafae Nahli&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This paper examines the Treatise on the "Difference between the two  fields of philosophical logic and Arabic grammar" (Maqāla fī tabyīn  al-faṣl bayna ṣina‘atay al-manṭiq al-falsafī wa-l-naḥw al-‘arabī) by Abū  Zakariyā’ Yaḥyā ibn ‘Adī, providing also the Italian translation of it.  It will appear that Yaḥyā ibn ‘Adī’s approach is based on Fārābī’s  ideas about the relationship between logic and the sciences of language.  Even more important is the fact that the difference established by  Yaḥyā ibn ‘Adī’s between logic and grammar both as for the subject  (mawḍū‘) and as for the scope (ġarad) counts as the source for  Avicenna’s distinction between subject (mawḍū‘) and scope (ġarad) of the  metaphysics.     &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="icona" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="icona" src="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/fileadmin/templates/icone/ico_pdf.gif" height="19" width="24" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="data_text" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;Studia graeco-arabica 1 / 2011&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="titolo_news" style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: xx-small;"&gt;&lt;a alt="pdf download" href="http://www.greekintoarabic.eu/uploads/media/4bookannouncements_sito_01.pdf"&gt;Book Announcements &amp;amp; Reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;See the full &lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html"&gt;List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js#username=xa-4b4cc6be5f7e0135" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/819832869923324809/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/04/new-open-access-journal-studia-graeco.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/819832869923324809"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/819832869923324809"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/04/new-open-access-journal-studia-graeco.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Studia graeco-arabica"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
