<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2225551059738056101</id>
   <published>2013-04-06T08:31:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-04-06T08:38:01.529-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Philology Project Announcement</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseusupdates/2013/04/04/the-open-philology-project-and-humboldt-chair-of-digital-humanities-at-leipzig/">The Open Philology Project and Humboldt Chair of Digital Humanities at Leipzig</a><br />             <div class="entry-meta">       <span class="meta-sep">by</span> <span class="author vcard"><a class="url fn n" href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseusupdates/author/gcrane/" title="View all posts by Gregory  Crane">Gregory  Crane</a></span> <span class="meta-prep meta-prep-author">Posted on</span> <a href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseusupdates/2013/04/04/the-open-philology-project-and-humboldt-chair-of-digital-humanities-at-leipzig/" rel="bookmark" title="4:44 pm"><span class="entry-date">April 4, 2013</span></a></div><div class="entry-meta"><span class="entry-date">[At <a href="http://sites.tufts.edu/perseusupdates/">Perseus Updates</a>] </span></div><div class="entry-meta"><div class="entry-content">      <blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Initial Research Plan (April 2013)<br />Alexander von Humboldt Chair of Digital Humanities<br />The University of Leipzig</span><br /> <blockquote><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><strong>Abstract</strong>: The Humboldt Chair of Digital  Humanities at the University of Leipzig sees in the rise of Digital  Technologies an opportunity to re-assess and re-establish how the  humanities can advance the understanding of the past and to support a  dialogue among civilizations. Philology, which uses surviving linguistic  sources to understand the past as deeply and broadly as possible, is  central to these tasks, because languages, present and historical, are  central to human culture. To advance this larger effort, the Humboldt  Chair focuses upon enabling Greco-Roman culture to realize the fullest  possible role in intellectual life. Greco-Roman culture is particularly  significant because it contributed to both Europe and the Islamic world  and the study of Greco-Roman culture and its influence thus entails  Classical Arabic as well as Ancient Greek and Latin. The Humboldt Chair  inaugurates an <strong>Open Philology Project</strong> with three  complementary efforts that produce open philological data, educate a  wide audience about historical languages, and integrate open  philological data from many sources: the <strong>Open Greek and Latin Project</strong> organizes content (including translations into Classical Arabic and modern languages); <strong>the Historical Language e-Learning Project</strong> explores ways to support learning across barriers of language and culture as well as space and time; <strong>the Scaife Digital Library</strong> focuses on integrating cultural heritage sources available under open licenses.</span></blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Humboldt Chair of Digital Humanities at Leipzig will create the <strong>Open Philology Project</strong>.  In this we advance a digital successor to that philology which sees in  language a source for what Augustus Boeckh in 1822 termed “the  understanding of all antiquity, including the events of both the  physical and intellectual world.”[1] Philology brings the past to life  as deeply and as broadly as possible through the use of surviving  linguistic sources. From the human perspective philology constitutes a  set of language-based critical scholarly skills — not only annotating  (annotation is the basic genre), but also comparing, connecting,  interpreting, proving or rejecting hypotheses, finding evidence;  critical apparatuses and commentaries often preserve condensed fruits of  such reasoning, and Open Philology doesn’t let the scholarly heritage  of manuscript and print culture vanish, converting it into digital form  and using it as a training field for next generations.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Open Philology Project will initially focus particularly upon  pre-modern society but its methods and goals apply to any society for  whom traces of their languages survive. Philology provides an  opportunity to advance the intellectual life of individual societies  and, equally important, dialogue across civilizations, transcending not  only barriers of space and time but of language and culture. Digital  technology plays a critical role as a catalyst because — and only  because — it allows us to re-imagine how we can more fully achieve, and  indeed transform our ability to achieve, these ancient goals of  philology. This is not a digital philology or digital humanities  project. The Open Philology Project is about philology.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">To address the vast challenge of an Open Philology that embraces all  historical languages, the Humboldt Chair begins by advancing within a  European and a global space the role of that Greco-Roman culture out of  which Europe largely emerged. Greco-Roman culture has also contributed  significantly to the Islamic world and Europe depended upon Arabic  sources. Our goal in this activity is not only to increase the  intellectual accessibility of European cultural heritage but also to  foster exchange of cultural heritage sources such as Persian, Sanskrit,  Classical Chinese, Egyptian from the earliest forms through Coptic, and  the Cuneiform Languages of the Ancient Near East, and Classical Mayan  from the Western Hemisphere. As a platform for this activity, the Open  Philology Project builds upon, and helps develop, the Perseus Digital  Library, working with colleagues in Europe, North America and elsewhere  to expand open collections and services and to reach an increasingly  global audience.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The greatest challenge of humanistic scholarship lies, in our view,  in making available the human cultural heritage to the global community.  Digitization is a necessary but, by itself, insufficient step in this  process. Human cultural heritage must be represented in a way that  supports intellectual access across barriers of language and culture.  This requirement in turn has implications for the technologies but also  for the rights regime that we choose. Open data provides the best  strategy by which to promote the circulation of sources within a global  context. Collections that are protected behind subscription barriers may  serve the interests of specialist communities. Collections that cannot  be freely modified and re-circulated may be useful for reference. But  scholarship in general and philology in particular must build upon open  data if it is to realize its intellectual and social obligations to  advance the common understanding of human culture. The Humboldt Chair is  therefore committed to open source publication, with machine-actionable  Creative Commons licenses requiring attribution and sharing of data and  allowing commercial reuse (CC-BY-SA) as the preferred mode of  distribution.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The larger Open Philology Project begins with three specific,  complementary activities, addressing the challenge of creating  comprehensive open resources, providing the education needed to  understand and to contribute to those resources, and integrating open  resources from many different sources into an integrated computational  framework for analysis, annotation, and preservation.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">First, the <strong>Open Greek and Latin Project</strong> makes Greek and Latin sources freely accessible, both digitally and intellectually, to a global public. Second, <strong>the Historical Language e-Learning Project</strong> provides distributed e-learning of historical languages such as Greek  and Latin so that as many as possible may penetrate as deeply as they  choose into the sources from which the present has been fashioned.  Third, support from the Humboldt Foundation allows us to contribute,  after years of planning, to the <strong>Scaife Digital Library</strong>.  The SDL develops methods to aggregate and integrate from various  sources open data, textual and archaeological alike, in any medium,  about human cultural heritage, including, but not limited to, the  Greco-Roman world.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">All three of these projects focus on the production, analysis, and  preservation of machine-actionable annotations. All data about  historical records is based upon transcriptions, whether from  text-bearing objects or from sound recordings, which are themselves  annotations that describe the textual content from a region of a written  surface or a time interval in a recording. We will continue to make  arguments in the digital successors to notes, articles and monographs  but we should increasingly integrate into, and use as the foundation  for, those arguments machine actionable links to the sources upon which  they are based. These links include not only citations to particular  sources (e.g., a machine actionable link to a particular reading in a  particular edition of Aeschylus) but also to aggregate data (e.g., the  results of a search posed as they appeared at a particular time). In the  end, born-digital notes, articles and monographs — if they preserve  labels inherited for the form of a book — may preserve a family  resemblance to their predecessors but they will surely evolve into  something qualitatively different as the adapt to the different gravity,  if not fundamentally different physics, of a digital space.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><br />1. The Open Greek and Latin Project.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The ultimate goal is to represent every source text produced in  Classical Greek or Latin from antiquity through the present, including  texts preserved in manuscript tradition as well as on inscriptions,  papyri, ostraca and other written artifacts. Over the course of the next  five years, we will focus upon converting as much Greek and Latin,  available as scanned printed books, into an open, dynamic corpus,  continuously augmented and improved by a combination of automated  processes and human contributions of many kinds. The focus upon Greek  and Latin reflects both the belief that we have an obligation to  disseminate European cultural heritage and the observation that recent  advances in OCR technology for Greek and Latin make these intertwined  languages ready for large-scale work.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Open Greek and Latin Project aims at providing at least one  version for all Greek and Latin sources produced during antiquity  (through c. 600 CE) and a growing collection from the vast body of  post-classical Greek and Latin that still survives. Perhaps 150 million  words of Greek and Latin, preserved in manuscripts, on stone, on papyrus  or other writing surface, survive from antiquity. Analysis of 10,000  books in Latin, downloaded from Archive.org, identified more than 200  million words of post-classical Latin. With 70,000 public domain books  listed in the Hathi Trust as being in Ancient Greek or Latin, the amount  of Greek and Latin already available will almost certainly exceed 1  billion words.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Where existing corpora of Greek and Latin have generally included one  edition of a work, Open Greek and Latin Corpus is designed to manage  multiple versions of, and to represent the complete textual history of, a  work: every manuscript, every papyrus fragment, and every printed  edition are all versions within the history of a text. In the short run,  this involves using OCR-technology optimized for Classical Greek and  Latin to create an open corpus that is reasonably comprehensive for the  c. 100 million words produced through c. 600 CE and that begins to make  available the billions of words produced after 600 CE in Greek and Latin  that survive.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Open Greek and Latin Project assumes the following modules:</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">A. The <strong>Philological Workflow Module</strong> enables a  digital representation of a written source, available in a 2D or 3D  form, to be converted into machine actionable text, corrected, and  annotated with an increasing range of information (named entities,  morphology, syntax, and other linguistic features, alignments between  different versions of the same text, whether in the same language or  translated across multiple languages, text re-use detection, including  quotation, paraphrase and citation). Automated methods include Optical  Character Recognition, Text Alignment, Syntactic Parsing, etc. In each  case, human annotation can augment automated annotations or substitute  for them altogether where automated methods are not yet able to produce  adequate initial results (e.g, manual transcription of inscriptions and  medieval manuscripts).</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">B. The <strong>Distributed Review Module</strong> provides a range of  options by which to assess and represent the reliability produced,  whether by automated systems or by human contributors, as part of the  Philological work flow. In many cases annotations can be released even  when their reliability is not necessarily high (e.g., noisy  OCR-generated text). The point is to identify annotations that most  require subsequent attention, whether manual correction or action of  some other kind (e.g., poor OCR data may reflect the need to create a  new scan of a printed book). The Distributed Review Module assumes that  multiple annotations may be equally trustworthy (i.e., experts back  different interpretations) and can track inter-annotator disagreement  among experts. The Distributed Review Module provides default values but  also allows for different weights to be placed upon different  validations (e.g., include all readings in a particular version of a  text, whether these are readings in a particular manuscript or the  readings chosen and emendations proposed by a particular editor, include  all prosopographical identifications proposed by one particular  scholar). The Distributed Review Module should support searching by both  text characteristics (specific passages, authors), annotator  characteristics (expert, novice, native language etc.), and annotation  characteristics (emendations, grammatical or interpretive comments,  degree of inter-annotator disagreement, etc.). But it should also permit  browsing the history of annotation by passage, annotator, magnitude of  disagreement etc.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">C. The <strong>Philological Repository Module</strong> can preserve  all published philological data, including the transcriptions and all  subsequent annotations (e.g., identifying a transcribed word as being in  Latin, a place name, in the accusative case etc.) as well as the  provenance of each annotation (e.g., the annotation is born-digital and  was published by a particular individual at a given time or the  annotation was extracted from a print book by a particular author and  published at a given time, with or without human verification, and with  an estimated accuracy). The repository is based upon the Canonical Text  Services/CITE Architecture for textual sources developed by researchers  at the Center for Hellenic Studies within the larger framework developed  by the DataConservancy.org.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">D. The <strong>e-Portfolio Module</strong> aggregates and distributes  particular subsets of user contributions for particular audiences. The  e-Porfolio Module can identify any published contributions according to  type, date, and author (e.g., all syntactic analyses published by a  particular person during a particular time interval). The e-Portfolio  Module can also make selected materials that are not yet published  available to selected audiences (e.g., an editorial board or the  admission committee for a degree program). The Perseids Project from  Tufts University provides a starting point for this work.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><br />2. The Historical Language e-Learning Project.</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Anyone, anywhere, regardless of their linguistic or cultural  background, whether they are a student in a formal curriculum or not,  should be able to learn as much of a historical language as they need to  work directly in original-language primary materials. Work in this  context entails not only learning but contributing early and in  increasingly sophisticated ways: students can add new, or correct  existing, data as they learn to type in an unfamiliar language, while  they can, in the language of gaming, “level up” to tasks such as  linguistic annotation of new materials and the production of aligned,  modern language translations, and see their growing proficiency  concretely visualized in a way that permits them to compare it to that  of others and documents it for use in e-portfolios and other records of  their achievement.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In the short run, building upon existing collections and services, we  will support students working with Greek, Latin and Classical Arabic  texts in a system readily localized for speakers of multiple modern  languages (with Croatian, English, German and French emerging as initial  languages of interest). The Historical Language e-Learning Project is  based upon the existence of extensible richly annotated corpora.  Learners draw from the start on existing richly annotated corpora and on  images of sources such as manuscripts and inscriptions. They use  morpho-syntactic annotation, dictionary links, and aligned modern  language translations, so that they immediately work with primary  sources in the original. They learn grammar by comparing their  morpho-syntactic analyses with vetted analyses already available, by  creating their own aligned translations, and by using annotations and  alignments to develop active as well as passive mastery of morphology,  syntax, and vocabulary. They demonstrate advanced ability by expanding  the corpus of richly annotated materials, proposing new annotations of  their own and reviewing annotations proposed by others.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Ancient Greek, Latin and Classical Arabic Large collections such as  Gallica, Google Books, and the Internet Archive have already made  billions of words in Greek and Latin available to a global audience — a  far larger collection than the small handful of advanced researchers can  document and a far broader collection in terms of genre and style than  the classical corpora on which current programs in Greek and Latin still  focus. While the amount of openly licensed Classical Arabic is not yet  as extensive, more than enough sources are available and require  documentation and analysis. We need to train a new generation of  students, who can directly analyze sources in the original languages and  make substantive contributions earlier and on a wider range of sources  than has previously been feasible.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Traditional programs of Ancient Greek and Latin are not designed to  support students who first develop an interest in these languages during  their undergraduate careers — by the time students are able to begin  interacting proficiently with the primary sources, they are ready to  graduate. Traditional class schedules are rigid and rarely can an  institution offer more than one section of an ancient language. As for  Classical Arabic, few institutions offer any formal instruction at all —  Modern Language Association statistics report only 285 students  enrolled in Classical Arabic in the United States in 2009.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">At the same time, Ancient Greek, Latin, and Classical Arabic must  also compete for students with fields where students regularly  contribute as members of laboratory teams and can often expect to  develop their own research projects as undergraduates. The strongest  academic programs not only demand that students master complex  disciplinary knowledge but also provide students with an opportunity to  use that knowledge to make substantive contributions and to develop  significant research projects of their own.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Open Greek and Latin creates an inexhaustible range of substantive  activity to which any student of these languages can aspire — whether  working on manuscripts of well-known authors (e.g., the Homer Multitext  Project), creating the first modern language translations of Greek and  Latin sources (e.g., Tufts’ Medieval Latin), or adding critical  linguistic annotation (e.g., the Perseus Greek and Latin Treebanks).</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Historical Language e-Learning project depends upon the following:</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">A. <strong>Global Editions of Historical Languages</strong> include  all features of a traditional edition (including textual notes) but are  designed to make primary sources available to the widest possible  audience. Global editions are richly encoded source materials that  include enough annotation so that readers with a general understanding  of grammar and of language are able to work directly with primary  sources in a historical language that they have not studied. Core  elements to this infrastructure include morphological and syntactic  analyses, links to machine readable dictionaries (ideally with data  about word sense of a given word in a given context), and one or more  aligned modern language translations that themselves have substantial  annotation and are designed to facilitate machine translation into many  other modern languages.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">B. <strong>Preliminary Source Texts</strong> are digital texts that  do not yet have the mature annotations needed for global editions.  Students of a language can aspire to begin adding new annotations within  the opening weeks of study, working at first with each other and with  their instructors but ultimately working to level up to roles with more  trust and responsibility as they demonstrate their increasing skills. It  is both a goal and a necessity to engage students as collaborators,  because we believe that this is a good thing in itself, because we  believe that this increases learning, and because so many historical  sources are already available that we cannot depend upon a handful of  professionals to analyze and annotate them all.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">C. <strong>Machine Actionable Models</strong> of Language Competence  provide methods by which to assess knowledge of historical languages at  every level, from introductory exposure to the language through  standardized examinations (e.g., the US-based National Latin exam, the  German <a href="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graecum">Graecum</a> and&nbsp;<a href="http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latinum">Latinum</a>)  to the various PhD level examinations (e.g., US PhD programs in Greek  and Latin commonly have combined reading lists of between 500,000 and  1,000,000 words of Greek and Latin). Where the city of Arpino holds the  Certamen Ciceronianum Arpinas, a multinational competition for students  from various nations — each of whom can compete in their own national  language — we can create an on-going contest, where students from around  the world and from widely disparate backgrounds can meet to compare  their skills and compete to shed light upon Greco-Roman culture. Machine  Actionable Models of Language Competence can be configured for various  purposes and pedagogical perspectives. The Competence Models also  provide mechanisms for evaluation of competence across national  languages — examinations on morphology and syntax provide a powerful  measure of competence and can be effectively localized in various  national languages — whether the student speaks Arabic or Croatian,  English or Lithuanian. The Distributed Review Module provides an  environment for assessment of language competence as well as for  advanced publications.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">D. <strong>Localized Learning Materials</strong> include grammars,  lexica, and translations in a national language. Localized Learning  Materials need to be able to be shared across, and customized for, many  different languages. Within Europe alone, Greek and Latin, for example,  are taught in more than thirty different national languages.[2] We need  not only to maintain learning materials in dozens of languages but also  to provide learning materials in languages where Greek and Latin are not  part of formal academic curricula. To accomplish this we must represent  as much information about the language in machine actionable form that  can be efficiently represented in many languages. We also need to  provide an architecture that supports customization for particular  languages, especially the creation of aligned translations that contain  from the start links between the source text and the modern language  translation.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">E. <strong>Dynamic Syllabi</strong> can be analyzed to track the  linguistic phenomena that students have encountered (e.g., vocabulary,  grammar) and the content that they have covered. As students pursue  different dynamic syllabi at different times, they can track their  overall background and necessary background information needed to pursue  subsequent courses. Instructors in structured classes can generate  personalized background readings and examinations that reflect both what  students brought with them to, and what they covered in, the class. The  e-Portfolio Module uses Dynamic Syllabi to accomplish these goals.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">F. <strong>Personalized E-learning Tools</strong> analyze individual  behaviors of particular learners and provide personalized analyses and  suggestions, reflecting the strengths and learning styles of particular  students. Personalized e-learning tools allow learners not only to track  their progress towards target proficiencies and but also to personalize  the target proficiencies as well: students of Homer will have different  targets than those of the New Testament or of Plato, while students  aspiring to fluent comprehension will have different needs than  intellectual historians who wish to explore word usage or linguists  interested in syntactic phenomena. The goal is to provide as much  feedback as possible, as quickly as possible, and as closely adapted to  the needs and interests of each learner as possible.</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong><br />3. The Scaife Digital Library (SDL)</strong></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Scaife Digital Library (SDL) commemorates Ross Scaife (March 31,  1960 – March 15, 2008) who did pioneering work for the study of  Greco-Roman culture in a digital age, who was committed to collaborative  scholarship and who was a champion of open data. The SDL is designed as  a service, as an experiment, and as a space for research. An increasing  amount of Ancient Greek, Latin, Classical Arabic and other sources are  available under appropriate open licenses. The SDL builds upon the  services and collections listed above. The SDL provides a mechanism by  which to compare these services and collections with those available  elsewhere, allowing research at the Humboldt Chair to explore new  methods while making its own work more visible.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">As a service, the SDL will aggregate as much content in these  languages as possible, converting, where necessary and feasible, into  interoperable formats. The goal of this service is to provide a single  space to represent all published Ancient Greek, Latin, and Classical  Arabic. In this context, publication entails release under an open  license. Proprietary collections are neither public nor published.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">As an experiment, the SDL will track how many sources in how many  historical languages and of how many types it can identify and integrate  and then track this data over time. This experiment attempts to measure  both our ability to find materials and the change in what is available.  It is our hope that the growth in available resources in languages  beyond Greek, Latin, and Arabic will greatly outstrip the ability of the  SDL to aggregate and analyze them.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">As a research space, the SDL collects not only metadata but also  source materials into a single environment. Within this space  researchers can explore customized collections (e.g., all available  versions and translations of the Odes of Horace or the aligned corpus of  Classical Arabic translations and Greek sources) or simply analyze all  available Greek. While the SDL may collect as widely as possible from  open collections representing cultures from around the world, the SDL  intends to provide the most comprehensive possible coverage and services  for students of Ancient Greek, Latin, and Classical Arabic.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[1] Augustus Boeck, “Oratio nataliciis Friderici Guilelmi III.”  (1822): “Itaque ubi, quae et qualis philologia meo iudicio sit,  quaeritis, simplicissima ratione respondeo, si non latiore, quae in ipso  vocabulo inest, potestate accipitur, sed ut solet ad antiquas litteras  refertur, universae antiquitatis cognitionem historicam et  philosophicam.”</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">[2] <a href="http://www.eduhi.at/gegenstand/EuroClassica/?TITEL=EuroClassica+in+Europe&amp;modul=europamap">http://www.eduhi.at/gegenstand/EuroClassica/?TITEL=EuroClassica+in+Europe&amp;modul=europamap</a></span><br />            </blockquote></div><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="entry-date">&nbsp;</span></span>      </blockquote></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2225551059738056101/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/04/open-philology-project-announcement.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2225551059738056101"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2225551059738056101"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/04/open-philology-project-announcement.html"
         title="Open Philology Project Announcement"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
