<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8152198135233479513</id>
   <published>2009-02-11T12:04:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2009-02-11T12:16:01.845-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="ASOR"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#"
             term="Alexandria Archive Institute"/>
   <title type="text">2008 ASOR Open Archaeology Prize</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[The <a href="http://www.alexandriaarchive.org">Alexandria Archive Institute</a> recently <a href="http://www.alexandriaarchive.org/openup.php">announced</a> the winners of the 2008 ASOR Open Archaeology Prize:<br /><br /><blockquote>2008 ASOR Open Archaeology Prize<br /><br />Winners of the <a href="http://www.alexandriaarchive.org/OpenArchPrize.html">2008 ASOR Open Archaeology Prize competition</a> were announced on November 21, 2008 at the annual ASOR meeting in Boston. The printed prize announcements can be found on page 31 of the <a href="http://www.asor.org/pubs/news/58_4.pdf">Winter 2008 ASOR newsletter</a>.<br /><br />First prize ($500) was awarded to the <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/">Abzu</a> web site, led by Charles E. Jones, Head Librarian at the <a href="http://www.nyu.edu/isaw">Institute for the Study of the Ancient World, New York University</a> and Research Associate, <a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/">The Oriental Institute, University of Chicago</a>. Launched in 1994, Abzu collects and manages open access scholarly material relating to the ancient Near East and Mediterranean world, including the rich corpus of ETANA Core Texts, which are available for free for noncommercial teaching and research. In addition to standard search functions, Abzu provides several different ways to track recently entered material, such as <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzu/rss/">news feeds</a>, a <a href="http://www.bloglines.com/blog/AbzuNew">clip blog</a> and a <a href="http://www.widgetbox.com/widget/abzu-bibliography">widget</a>. It also allows for the re-presentation and re-formatting of material indexed in it in the continuing series "AWOL - The Ancient World Online", beginning at the <a href="http://ancientworldbloggers.blogspot.com/2008/04/awol-ancient-world-online-1.html">Ancient World Bloggers Group Blog</a>. Abzu is self sustaining with selection and editorial control having been integrated into the workflows of the editor at the Research Archives, Oriental Institute, the Blegen Library at the American School of Classical Studies at Athens, and at the Library of the Institute for the Study of the Ancient World.<br /><br />Second prize ($200 in books, co-sponsored by <a href="http://www.oxbowbooks.com/home.cfm/Location/DBBC">David Brown Book Company</a>) was awarded to the <a href="http://www.bade.psr.edu/">Badè Museum of Archaeology web site</a>, led by Aaron Brody (Pacific School of Religion). The Badè Museum’s web site was recently overhauled to allow for virtual outreach to a limitless audience, helping educate beyond the brick-and-mortar walls of the Museum's galleries, and bringing transparency to the Museum’s holdings. The web site provides access to reusable content from archaeological excavations at Tell en-Nasbeh, conducted by WF Bade in the 1920s and 1930s under the auspices of Pacific School of Religion. The new web site provides digital versions of the contents in the Museum’s exhibits, overviews of research projects and facilitates the ordering of traveling exhibit materials. By openly licensing all content with Creative Commons licenses, the Bade team has ensured that these free and open resources can be downloaded for reuse by anyone. The photographs and short movies are of particular interest, and Aaron informs us that many more resources will be coming on line in the near future.</blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8152198135233479513/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/02/2008-asor-open-archaeology-prize.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8152198135233479513"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8152198135233479513"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/02/2008-asor-open-archaeology-prize.html"
         title="2008 ASOR Open Archaeology Prize"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
