<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2730733590721455036</id>
   <published>2013-10-23T07:37:00.003-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-10-23T07:37:54.432-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Micropasts: A community platform for conducting, designing and funding research into our human past</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://micropasts.org/">Micropasts: A community platform for conducting, designing and funding research into our human past</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://micropasts.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/cs12.jpg" class="shrinkToFit decoded" height="129" src="http://micropasts.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/cs12.jpg" width="200" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Micropasts</strong>&nbsp;is a web platform that brings  together&nbsp;full-time archaeologists, archaeological societies and other  interested members of the public to collaborate on new kinds of research  about our human history. It is a place where archaeological enthusiasts  not only can create high-quality research data together, but also  can&nbsp;collaboratively design and fund entirely new research projects.&nbsp;In  particular, we want to encourage better kinds of archaeology by  improving the ways that people traditionally distinguished as  ‘academics’, ‘professionals’ and ‘volunteers’ cooperate with one  another&nbsp;(as well as with others out there who as yet have&nbsp;no more than a  passing interest in archaeology).</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Through the&nbsp;<strong>Micropasts</strong> platform, we will develop and support a range of crowd-sourcing and crowd-funding&nbsp;projects. By joining <strong>Micropasts</strong>,  you can help research, fund and/or design as many projects as you like,  with as much or as little personal commitment as you wish. Some  existing projects are about creating 3D models of archaeological  artefacts, enriching old photographic archives or transcribing old  archaeological excavation records, to name just a few that we have come  up with so far. Other new projects will need your help with financing  before they can begin, whilst yet others might be research topics that  you want &nbsp;to propose yourself (as an individual, as part of an organised  archaeological society or in tandem with other interested people that  you meet online).&nbsp;We cannot yet say &nbsp;which projects will prove popular  and which ones will not, and we hope that many as yet unanticipated  agendas will be&nbsp;dreamt up collectively. In any case, we are keen for  your ideas and your contributions wherever we can get them!</span><br /><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><em>This project’s initial stages have been funded by a UK Arts and  Humanities Research Council grant, and involve a collaboration between  the UCL Institute of Archaeology, The British Museum and the Portable  Antiquities Scheme.&nbsp;The platform is currently under construction and we  will be adding content and functionality over the coming few months. If  you would like to be put on a list of early possible contributors, then  please <a href="http://micropasts.org/contact-us/" title="Contact us">contact us</a>.</em></span></blockquote><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2730733590721455036/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/10/micropasts-community-platform-for.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2730733590721455036"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2730733590721455036"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/10/micropasts-community-platform-for.html"
         title="Micropasts: A community platform for conducting, designing and funding research into our human past"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
