<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8084912642708195448</id>
   <published>2012-12-05T16:20:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2012-12-05T16:20:20.307-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">A Long Way from Home: Diaspora Communities in Roman Britain </title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/diaspora_ahrc_2011/">A Long Way from Home: Diaspora Communities in Roman Britain</a><br />Hella Eckardt, Gundula Müldner, Mary Lewis, 2012<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">This project explored the cultural and biological experience of  immigrant communities in Roman Britain. It has long been known from  epigraphic and historical sources that Britain was home to a wide range  of immigrants during the Roman period, with most of the evidence  referring to imperial officials and military personnel. Using a range of  scientific techniques, we have identified possible migrants in the  burial record of Roman Britain.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Evidence for diaspora communities was analysed through an innovative  combination of material culture, skeletal and isotope research. We  selected a range of sites (mainly York, where there is historical and  archaeological evidence for African individuals, but also Poundbury Camp  (Dorset), Catterick (Yorkshire), Gloucester and Lankhills (Winchester))  for this study. In terms of methodology, we employ  osteological/forensic methods to assess ancestry based on skeletal  traits, and isotope analysis to assess geographic origins (oxygen and  strontium) and diet (carbon and nitrogen). Further osteological work  focused on the health of the populations examined. Our results show that   a significant number of individuals sampled can be classed as  non-local, with a smaller proportion coming from outside the UK.  Contrary to popular perceptions, there are women and children amongst  these migrants. In many cases the possible immigrants can not be  identified from their burial rite, but there are also examples where  grave goods (such as ivory bracelets) may relate to an individual's  origin. In many societies migration can have a negative impact on  health, but at Gloucester it could be shown that there were no  significant differences between immigrants and locals in terms of  health. While possible immigrants and locals in many cases consumed  similar foods, our work has identified cases where migrants can be  identified through the consumption of certain foods (in particular fish  and millet).</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">All the results from this project have now been published, and the  ADS resource provides references to these publications and details on  the skulls and teeth examined. It is ordered by site, and then by type  of data.  An overview of the project work and a discussion of the wider  theoretical issues addressed by our research can be found in:</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Hella Eckardt, with C. Chenery, S. Leach, M. Lewis, G. Müldner and  E. Nimmo 2010. A long way from home - diaspora communities in Roman  Britain in: H. Eckardt (ed.) Roman diasporas - archaeological approaches  to mobility and diversity in the Roman Empire. JRA Suppl. 78. JRA  Suppl. Portsmouth: JRA, 99-130.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">As part of our outreach programme, we worked with the archaeological illustrator Aaron Watson (<a href="http://www.monumental.uk.com/">http://www.monumental.uk.com/</a>),  who produced stunning reconstruction images, some of  which will be  used by the Yorkshire Museum in their new exhibition on the People of  Roman York (<a href="http://www.yorkshiremuseum.org.uk/Page/Index.aspx">http://www.yorkshiremuseum.org.uk/Page/Index.aspx</a>).  We also collaborated with Caroline Lawrence, the famous children's' author (<a href="http://www.romanmysteries.com/pages/50-Home_Page">http://www.romanmysteries.com/pages/50-Home_Page</a>) to produce a series of short stories to be used by the Yorkshire Museum.</span><br />                                                         </blockquote><ul class="dlMenu"><li>  <blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/diaspora_ahrc_2011/index.cfm">Introduction</a></span></blockquote></li><li>  <blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/diaspora_ahrc_2011/overview.cfm">Overview</a></span></blockquote></li><li>     <blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://archaeologydataservice.ac.uk/archives/view/diaspora_ahrc_2011/downloads.cfm">Downloads</a></span></blockquote></li></ul><div id="archiveheader">      </div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8084912642708195448/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/12/a-long-way-from-home-diaspora.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8084912642708195448"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8084912642708195448"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/12/a-long-way-from-home-diaspora.html"
         title="A Long Way from Home: Diaspora Communities in Roman Britain "/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
