<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7056176193938176481</id>
   <published>2009-01-14T13:57:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2009-01-14T14:53:55.198-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">International Conference on Geoarchaeology &amp; Archaeomineralogy</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/">International Conference on Geoarchaeology &amp; Archaeomineralogy</a> 29-30 October 2008 - Sofia Bulgaria<br /><br /><blockquote><ol><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/01Rapp.pdf">Should archaeomineralogy now follow geoarchaeology into the family of organized scholarly fields?</a> - George (Rip) Rapp</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/02Zagorchev.pdf">Earth sciences and culture:  natural and cultural heritage in the International Year of Planet Earth</a> - Ivan Zagorchev</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/03Pawlikowski.pdf">Stone raw materials as indicators of human contact during the Stone Age</a> - Maciej  Pawlikowski</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/04Gurova&amp;Ivanova.pdf">The rock shelter Arkata, Eastern Rhodopes:  preliminary archaeological report</a> - Maria Gurova, Stefanka Ivanova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/05Gurova&amp;Nachev.pdf">Formal Early Neolithic flint toolkits: archaeological and sedimentological aspects</a> - Maria Gurova, Chavdar Nachev </li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/06Crandell.pdf">Regarding the procurement of lithic materials at the Neolithic site at Limba (Alba County, Romania (sources of local and imported materials</a> - Otis N. Crandell</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/07Stoyanova&amp;Kunchev.pdf">Quarry sources of stone implements from the Azmak Tell near Stara Zagora (South Bulgaria)</a> - Victoria Stoyanova, Kuncho Kunchev</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/08Anastassova.pdf">Stone tools from the Early Neolithic site Dobroslavsti, Sofia Region</a> - Elka Anastassova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/09Stavrakeva.pdf">Chemical and petrographical characteristics of pottery fragments from the Neolithic and Chalcolithic site Bulgarchevo, Blagoevgrad Region</a> - Dobrinka Stavrakeva</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/10Tsonev.pdf">The social  dimension of  distance in prehistory: a jadeite axe case from Bulgaria</a> -  Tsoni Tsonev</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/11Gaydarska&amp;Chapman.pdf">The aesthetics of colour and brilliance – or  why were prehistoric persons interested in rocks, minerals, clays and pigments?</a> - Bisserka Gaydarska, John Chapman</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/12Kostov&amp;Pelevina.pdf">Complex faceted and other carnelian beads from the Varna Chalcolithic necropolis: archaeogemmological analysis</a> -<br />Ruslan I. Kostov, Olga Pelevina</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/13Zidarov.pdf">Green bone pin from Pietrele: possible evidence for intentional colouration of bone artifacts during the Copper Age in the Balkans</a> - Petar Zidarov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/14Ivanova&amp;Kuleff.pdf">Archaeometric investigations of amber from the late Bronze Age and the Iron Age from the territory of present Bulgaria </a>- Silviya Ivanova, Ivelin Kuleff</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/15Biagi&amp;Starnini.pdf"> The Bronze Age  Indus quarries of the Rohri Hills and Ongar in Sindh (Pakistan)</a> - Paolo Biagi, Elisabetta Starnini</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/16Ajdanlijsky-et-al1.pdf"> Mineralogical peculiarities of  the heavy mineral fraction from pottery fragments and the sediments from the archaeological site “Ada Tepe”, Kroumovgrad District</a> -  George Ajdanlijsky, George Nehrizov, Elitza Ilieva, Dimitar Zlatanov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/17Gregor.pdf">Household and burial ceramics of Early Iron Age from SW Slovakia: a mineralogical and petrographical study </a>- Miloš Gregor, Radoslav Čambal, Katarína Harmadyová</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/18Lazarov.pdf">The challenges facing the diamond edge in its contact with the precious stone when engraving gems (intaglios and cameos)</a> -  Stephan Lazarov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/19Iordanidis-et-al.pdf">A preliminary provenance study of marble artefacts from Aiani, ancient Upper Macedonia, Greece</a> - Andreas Iordanidis</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/20Dimitrova.pdf"> Pottery production in  ancient Greece</a> - Christina Dimitrova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/21Gluhak&amp;Hofmeister.pdf">Provenance analysis of Roman millstones: mapping of trade areas in Roman Europe</a> - Tatjana M. Gluhak, Wolfgang Hofmeister</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/22Nenova-et-al.pdf">Petrographic study of artefacts from a temple of Sabasius in the village of Porominovo, Kyustendil District, Western Bulgaria</a> - Petia Nenova, Oleg Vitov, Ivanka Staykova, Lydia Staykova-Alexandrova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/23Petrova&amp;Petrov.pdf"> Architectural-decorative details in  the  Basilica N4 at the town of Sandanski (ancient Parthicopolis), South-West Bulgaria</a> - Svetla Petrova, Peter I. Petrov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/24Shevchenko&amp;Cherevko.pdf"> On the problem of mineral raw materials of architectural monument of the X   century: the Desiatinna Virgin Church in the city of Kyiv</a> - Natalia A. Shevchenko, I.  A. Cherevko</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/25Macheva.pdf">Determination of the provenance of the archaeological monument “Samuilov Kamak”</a> - Lubomira Macheva</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/26Won-in-et-al.pdf">Preliminary study  of  the age of  the  Lanna  period by  thermoluminescence dating:  a  case study from  the Wiang Kaen ancient site, Chiang Rai, Northern Thailand</a> -  Krit Won-in, Pornsawat Wattanakul, Pisutti Dararutana, Sorapong Pongkrapan, Isao Takashima, Narumol Ruangrunsri, Fongsaward S. Singharajwarapan, Thiva Supajanya, Krisanapol Vichapan</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/27Larsson&amp;Veiga.pdf">Ming porcelain from the Santa Clara-a-velha Monastery in Coimbra, Portugal. First results using a portable µ-EDXRF spectrometer</a> - Mathilda Larsson, João Pedro Veiga</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/28Strack.pdf">A study on the origin of emeralds in Mogul objects at the State Hermitage Museum, St. Petersburg</a> - Elisabeth Strack</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/29Stoyanova-et-al.pdf"> Study of the composition of stone tobacco pipe from the archaeological reserve “Pautalia-Velbuzhd-Kyustendil”, Bulgaria</a> - Rossita Stoyanova, Oleg Vitov, Irina Marinova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/30Cavallo&amp;Pandit.pdf">Geology and petrography of ochres and white clay deposits in Rajasthan State, India</a>  - Giovanni Cavallo, Manoj Pandit</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/31Fol.pdf">The rock as a topos of faith. The interactive zone of the rock-cut monuments – from Urartu to Thrace</a> - Valeria  Fol</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/32Kostov.pdf">Geological and mineralogical background of the megalithic and rock-cut sites in Bulgaria and some other European countries </a>- Ruslan I. Kostov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/33Kolev-et-al.pdf">Orientations of dolmens in Bulgaria</a> - Dimitar Kolev, Lyubomir Tsonev, Antonio C. Gonzalez Garcia, Veselina Koleva</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/34Iliev.pdf">Observations upon the constructional connections of the dolmens in Bulgaria</a> - Stanislav Iliev</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/35Markov.pdf">The ancient Thracian megalithic sanctuary “Markov Kamak” at Tsarev Peak in Rila Mountain: semantic and functional analysis</a> - Vassil Markov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/36Raduncheva.pdf"> Prehistoric rock sanctuaries in the Eastern Rhodopes and some other mountain regions in Bulgaria</a> - Ana Raduncheva</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/37Ivanova.pdf"> Early human presence and rock-cut structures in the Eastern Rhodopes</a> - Stefanka Ivanova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/38Marinova&amp;Nenova.pdf">Petrography and geological setting of a Thracian rock-hewn sanctuary to the South of the village of Raven, Momchilgrad District, Eastern Rhodopes</a> - Irina Marinova, Petya Nenova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/39Zlatkova.pdf">Rock-cut structures in the Eastern Rhodopes and their relation to prehistoric mining</a> - Maria  Zlatkova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/40Dimitriadis.pdf">Looking for metals: megalithic monuments between reality and mythology</a> - George Dimitriadis</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/41Avramova.pdf"> “Special” stones in prehistoric practices: cases from Bulgaria</a> - Maya Avramova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/42Tsintzov.pdf">Distribution and typology of gold artefacts from the Bronze Age in the alluvial sediments in Bulgaria </a> - Zdravko Tsintsov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/43Christov1.pdf">On the age of some gold artefacts from the  Kraishte  Region in South-West Bulgaria</a> - Martin Christov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/44Christov2.pdf">Preliminary observations on the gold spirals from the ritual structures near Dubene, Karlovo Region</a> -  Martin Christov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/45Gonthier.pdf">Métallurgie précieuse dans l’empire d’Orphée</a> - Erik Gonthier</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/46Delfino.pdf">Some aspects of prehistoric and protohistoric metallurgy in Liguria (North-West Italy)</a> - Davide Delfino</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/47Zaykov-et-al.pdf"> Composition of gold and silver objects from the South Urals burial mounds (XV-II c. BC)</a> - Victor V. Zaykov, Anatolii M. Yuminov, Alexandеr D. Tairov, Dmitrii G. Zdanovich, Eugenii I. Churin, Vasilii A. Kotlyarov, Elisaveta V. Zaykova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/48Goshko&amp;Manichev.pdf"> Genetic interrelation of ores, slags, and  nonferrous metals from  archaeological monuments of Ukraine</a> - Tatjana Yu. Goshko, Vyacheslav I. Manichev</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/49Kuparadze-et-al.pdf">Ancient Georgian iron metallurgy and its ore base</a> - David M. Kuparadze, Dimitri V. Pataridze, Thomas N. Kerestedjian</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/50Avdev&amp;Tsankov.pdf">Ancient gold mining at the Southern slopes of the Vitosha and Verila Mountains</a> -  Stoyan Avdev,  Christian Tsankov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/51Nenov.pdf">Geoarchaeological monuments of ancient mining in Sredna Gora Mountain</a> - Todor Nenov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/52Chilikov&amp;Protochristov.pdf">Electrochemical properties of the Kazichene treasure</a> - Dimitar Chilikov, Christo Protochristov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/53Tonkova.pdf">Archaeological evidence for the exploitation of gold ore deposits at the villages of Kolyo Marinovo (Sarnena Sredna Gora) and Babyak (Western Rhodopes) in Antiquity</a> - Milena Tonkova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/54Vasileva.pdf">Archaeometric study of Iron Age copper alloy artefacts from the South-East Bulgaria</a> - Miglena Vasileva</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/55Baltakov.pdf">Culture layers as geological objects</a> - Georgi Baltakov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/56Pawlikowski-et-al.pdf"> The investigation of geoarchaeological layers of  Krakow city, Poland</a> -  Maciej Pawlikowski, Marta Wardas, Joanna Such</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/57Ajdanlijsky-et-al2.pdf">The foraminiferal analysis as a method for determination of source material for the pottery fragments from the “Ada Tepe” archaeological site, Kroumovgrad District (Eastern Rhodopes)</a> - George Ajdanlijsky, Boris Valchev, George Nehrizov, Dimitar Zlatanov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/58Boyadziev.pdf">Real arrows or “darts from heaven”? Some ideas on the interpretation of belemnites from Neolithic and Chalcolithic sites in Bulgaria</a> - Kamen Boyadjiev</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/59Ognjanova-Rumenova.pdf">Palaeoenvironment and archaeology: the use of diatom analysis in archaeology</a> - Nadja Ognjanova-Rumenova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/60Dobrev.pdf">Faulting and rock deformations established at the ruins of Perperikon (Eastern Rhodopes) and their relation to recent seismic activity</a> - Nikolai Dobrev</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/61Apostolova.pdf">Palaeogeographic conditions in the Black Sea area during the Neolithic and Chalcolithic according to archaeological research</a> - Krassimira Apostolova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/62Peev.pdf">Underwater sites in the area of Cape Shabla (North-East Bulgaria)</a> - Preslav Peev</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/63Preshlenov.pdf">Morphodynamics of the coastal zone of the Nessebar Peninsula (Bulgaria): archaeological and geological benchmarks</a> - Christo Preshlenov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/64Manichev.pdf">Geological aspect of the problem of dating the Great Egyptian Sphinx construction</a> - Vjacheslav I. Manichev, Alexander G. Parkhomenko</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/65Kenderova.pdf">Geomorphological survey of the area of archaeological site Bosilkovo (Banite municipality), South Bulgaria</a> - Rossitsa Kenderova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/66Baltakova.pdf">Geomorphological research of the paleoenvironment in the area of ancient villa “Armira” (I-IV century AD) near Ivaylovgrad, South-East Bulgaria (preliminary results)</a> - Ahinora Baltakova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/67Shopov-et-al.pdf">Potential and limitations of the archaeo-geophysical techniques</a> - Yavor Shopov, Diana Stoykova, Antoniya Petrova, Valentin Vasilev, Ludmil Tsankov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/68Tonkov1.pdf">Resistivity survey of Thracian burial mounds</a> - Nikola Tonkov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/69Tonkov2.pdf">Geophysical survey of the Thracian site at Halka Bunar locality in the area of the Chirpan Heights </a>- Nikola Tonkov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/70Cukavac-et-al.pdf">Reconstruction of buried objects by implementation of ground penetrating radar technique: example on Roman tomb in Brestovik (Serbia)</a> - Milena Cukavac, Goran Klemčić, Časlav Lazović</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/71Kovacheva.pdf"> Specific magnetic mineralogy of baked clay archaeological artefacts. Archaeomagnetic dating</a> -Mary Kovacheva</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/72Ranguelov&amp;Bozhkova.pdf">Archaeoseismology in Bulgaria</a> - Boyko Ranguelov, Anelia Bojkova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/73Ranguelov-et-al.pdf">The archaeological site – possible evidence about multihazard ancient events</a> - Boyko Ranguelov, Elina Mircheva, Igor Lazarenko, Radostina Encheva</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/74Radev&amp;Sultanov.pdf"> Research methods and methodological problems during restoration of prehistorical pottery. Part I</a> - Dimcho Radev, Alexander Sultanov</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/75Povarennykh.pdf">A new rock feature – cryptic structure (frustumation): possible implication to conservation and preservation of rock-made artefacts</a> - Mikhail Povarennykh</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/76Matova.pdf">Geoenvironmental problems for world cultural heritage in North-East Bulgaria</a> -Margarita Matova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/77Gergova.pdf">Geoarchaeological studies in the Sboryanovo National Reserve (North-East Bulgaria)</a> -Diana Gergova</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/78Gergova&amp;Katevski.pdf">Archaeology and geophysics in the Sboryanovo National Reserve (North-East Bulgaria)</a> - Diana Gergova, Ilijan Katevski</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/79Kabakchieva.pdf">The Big Mound and ancient villa Armira – archaeological data on earthquakes in the Eastern Rhodopes</a> - Gergana Kabakchieva</li><br /><li><a href="http://mgu.bg/geoarchmin/naterials/80Dobrev-%D0%B5t-al.pdf">Monitoring of cracks affecting the “Madara Horseman”  rock  bas-relief, North-East Bulgaria</a> -Nikolai Dobrev, Elka Avramova-Tacheva, Blahoslav Košťák</li><br /></ol><br /></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7056176193938176481/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/01/international-conference-on.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7056176193938176481"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7056176193938176481"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/01/international-conference-on.html"
         title="International Conference on Geoarchaeology &amp; Archaeomineralogy"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
