<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5880805904899938602</id>
   <published>2011-05-27T15:35:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-05-27T15:35:10.300-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Meta: SPARC introduces Open-access Journal Publishing Resource Index</title>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href="tp://www.arl.org/sparc/media/11-0526.shtml"&gt;SPARC introduces Open-access Journal Publishing Resource Index&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;New resource helps streamline launch and operation of open-access &lt;br /&gt;journals&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;For immediate release&lt;br /&gt;May 26, 2011&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;For more information, contact:&lt;br /&gt;Jennifer McLennan&lt;br /&gt;(202) 296-2296&lt;br /&gt;jennifer [at] arl [dot] org&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Washington, D.C. – SPARC (the Scholarly Publishing and Academic Resources Coalition) today released a free online &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.arl.org/sparc/partnering"&gt;Open Access Journal Publishing Resource Index&lt;/a&gt; with information and documents to support the &lt;/i&gt;launch  and operation of an open-access journal. Materials in the index will  help libraries, presses, and other academic units on campuses as they  work together to make the work of their researchers more widely  available.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;This new resource is launched in conjunction with the SPARC Campus-based Publishing Resource Center (&lt;a href="http://www.arl.org/sparc/partnering"&gt;http://www.arl.org/sparc/partnering&lt;/a&gt;),  which delivers a guide to critical issues in campus-based publishing  partnerships, case studies, a bibliography and resource list, an index  of collaborative initiatives (operated in partnership with Columbia  University Libraries), and access to the LIBPRESS online discussion  forum (operated by the University of California). The Center is overseen  by an editorial board representing library and university press staff  who are actively engaged in creating and managing publishing  partnerships.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The new index complements the rich existing resource center by  pointing to relevant sections in existing open-access journal publishing  guides and to sample journal proposals, policies, bylaws, and other  documentation to help with planning, development, and collaboration  issues. Topics covered include:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; New Journal Planning&lt;br /&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Journal Publishing Program Policies&lt;br /&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Governance&lt;br /&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Editorial&lt;br /&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Marketing &amp;amp; Promotion&lt;br /&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Technical Platforms&lt;br /&gt;•&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Sustainability Planning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Relevant sections of existing  open-access publishing guides, including those by David Solomon, Carol  Sutton, Kevin Stranack, Jan Velterop, Howard Goldstein and Raym Crow,  and others are indicated under each topic area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;By highlighting samples and best practices, the index will help give  campuses the tools they need to develop and maintain long-term,  successful open-access publishing ventures. “As campus-based publishing  gets more ambitious in scope, it’s important to build on the successes  and challenges of earlier initiatives and adopt best practices,” said  Raym Crow, senior consultant at SPARC. “Ultimately, campus-based  publishing can offer universities greater control over the intellectual  products they help create. SPARC is pleased to provide another tool to  support libraries and publishers in sustainable, professional,  open-access publishing.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Lee C. Van Orsdel, Dean of  University Libraries at Grand Valley State University, says faculty are  beginning to consult librarians for advice on journal publishing  options, including open-access models, and the SPARC site is a welcome  resource. “We’re deepening our knowledge as quickly as possible, but  it's a whole new area of expertise for most of us,” she said. “It will  save us time and increase the probability that we can get to the right  solution when advising our faculty on their best options.”&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The editorial board invites contributions from other campuses to help  build this resource and expand the bibliography – especially with  primary research papers on collaboration issues. “SPARC hopes this will  seed an effort where people will give documents to share, making it a  community hub,” said Crow. Members of the board and how to contact the  managing editor with suggestions are detailed on the Center home page.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The &lt;i&gt;Open Access Journal Publishing Resource Index is available online at &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.arl.org/sparc/partnering"&gt;http://www.arl.org/sparc/partnering&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;SPARC&lt;br /&gt;SPARC (Scholarly Publishing and Academic Resources Coalition), with  SPARC Europe and SPARC Japan, is an international alliance of more than  800 academic and research libraries working to create a more open system  of scholarly communication. SPARC’s advocacy, educational and publisher  partnership programs encourage expanded dissemination of research.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5880805904899938602/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/05/meta-sparc-introduces-open-access.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5880805904899938602"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5880805904899938602"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/05/meta-sparc-introduces-open-access.html"
         title="Meta: SPARC introduces Open-access Journal Publishing Resource Index"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
