<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-287901412203705151</id>
   <published>2011-01-14T17:18:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2011-01-14T17:18:02.407-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New at ARTstor</title>
   <content type="html">A new collection at ARTstor relating to Antiquity&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.artstor.org/what-is-artstor/w-html/col-judith.shtml" title="Go to the Judith and Holofernes collection page"&gt;Judith and Holofernes (Jessica E. Smith and Kevin R. Brine Charitable Trust)&lt;/a&gt; collection&lt;br /&gt;[January 14, 2011]&lt;br /&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;&lt;img alt="Artemisia Gentileschi, Judith and Her Maidservant, c. 1612. Galleria Palatina, Palazzo Pitti, Florence. © 2006, SCALA, Florence / ART RESOURCE, N.Y." height="230" src="http://www.artstor.org/images/global/judith1.jpg" title="Artemisia Gentileschi, Judith and Her Maidservant, c. 1612. Galleria Palatina, Palazzo Pitti, Florence. © 2006, SCALA, Florence / ART RESOURCE, N.Y." width="184" /&gt;         ARTstor is sharing a new themed collection of approximately 300  images based on the Biblical story of Judith and Holofernes across many  periods and a wide range of media, including the unprecedented  publication of narrative sequences in stained glass, relief sculpture  and book illustrations. Sponsored by a grant from the Jessica E. Smith  and Kevin R. Brine Charitable Trust, the collection complements the  approximately 330 existing images in various other collections in the  Digital Library that depict figures and events from the Old Testament's &lt;em&gt;Book of Judith&lt;/em&gt;. According to the &lt;em&gt;Book of Judith&lt;/em&gt;,  the widow Judith saved the besieged city of Bethulia by decapitating  the enemy general Holofernes, thereby enabling her Israelite countrymen  to defeat the invading Assyrians. The powerful appeal to the visual  imagination of the Judith narrative has inspired and challenged Western  scribes, illustrators, draftsman, painters, and sculptors for two  millennia. Judith was portrayed by both Dante in &lt;em&gt;The Divine Comedy&lt;/em&gt; and Chaucer in &lt;em&gt;The Canterbury Tales&lt;/em&gt;;  medieval depictions of the narrative cycle may be found in stained  glass windows at Sainte-Chapelle in Paris and relief sculptures at the  Notre-Dame Cathedral in Rouen; Renaissance and baroque depictions of  Judith abound, including works by artists such as Sandro Botticelli,  Michelangelo Merisi da Caravaggio, Lucas Cranach the Elder, Donatello,  Artemisia Gentileschi, Lorenzo Ghiberti, Giorgione, Andrea Mantegna,  Michelangelo, Peter Paul Rubens, Titian, and Paolo Veronese; and in the  20th century, the theme was treated by Austrian expressionists, French  surrealists, and contemporary feminist and conceptual artists. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Judith and Holofernes collection in ARTstor is part of a larger project –&lt;a href="http://workshops.nypl.org/judith" target="_blank" title="Go to the Foto Reali Archive page"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Judith Project: Expanding the Boundaries of Disciplinarity Through Collaborative Scholarly Practice&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;–  initiated by the Trust to enhance scholarship on The Book of Judith  through multidisciplinary collaboration and the application of  technology. As part of this project, approximately 30 international  scholars were selected by the Trust and an academic panel to participate  in the &lt;em&gt;Sword of Judith Conference&lt;/em&gt; held at the New York Public Library on April 17-18, 2008 (see K. Brine, E. Ciletti and H. Lëhnemann (editors), &lt;em&gt;The Sword of Judith: Judith Studies across the Disciplines&lt;/em&gt;,  Open Book Publishers, 2010). Participants presented their ongoing work  for collaboration and exchange at the conference and subsequently  continued their research in libraries and museums in the United States,  Europe, and the Middle East. Research has been conducted on Judith as a  subject in classical and baroque music and dance; the emergence of the  theme of Judith in Yiddish literature; the resurgent interest in Judith  in the 19th and 20th centuries; the relationship of The &lt;em&gt;Book of Judith&lt;/em&gt;  to the Jewish and Christian canons; the Mary/Judith typology; and the  interpretation of Judith in Jewish, Christian, and secular literature,  manuscript illuminations, and works of art. ARTstor and the New York  Public Library jointly created a website and wiki to serve as a  bibliographic reference tool and scholarly commons that will provide  scholars with new avenues for creative multidisciplinary collaboration  on the Judith theme. Both the wiki and the corpus of images in the  ARTstor Digital Library are intended to persist beyond the formal  conclusion of the project and be available for ongoing study and  scholarship.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="http://library.artstor.org/library/welcome.html"&gt;Log In to ARTstor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 100%;"&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-edit.g?blogID=116259103207720939&amp;amp;postID=2386735939976246321" id="data:post.url" name="data:post.title"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bookmark and    Share so Your Real Friends Know that You Know" height="16" src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif" style="border: 0pt none;" width="125" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/287901412203705151/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/01/new-at-artstor.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/287901412203705151"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/287901412203705151"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/01/new-at-artstor.html"
         title="New at ARTstor"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
      <gd:image rel="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#thumbnail"
                width="32"
                height="32"
                src="//lh5.googleusercontent.com/-8nLHiUNNG5o/AAAAAAAAAAI/AAAAAAAABVw/5TF3PbnVxzg/s512-c/photo.jpg"/>
   </author>
   <thr:total>0</thr:total>
</entry>
