<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-192871254560613554</id>
   <published>2013-12-16T22:16:00.003-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-12-16T22:54:45.034-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Early Warnings: Classical Studies from The C.H. Beck catalogue</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://listserv.crl.edu/wa.exe?A2=ind1312&amp;L=LIBLICENSE-L&amp;F=&amp;S=&amp;P=69223"><span style="font-size: small;">Open Access to Classical Studies from The C.H. Beck catalogue</span></a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: 10pt;"><a href="http://www.openedition.org/">OpenEdition</a> is pleased to announce the arrival of German publisher <a href="http://rsw.beck.de/rsw/default.asp">C.H. Beck</a> on OpenEdition Books, the digital platform for open access academic publishing. C.H. Beck collections <a href="http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/don%27t_count_your_chickens_before_they%27re_hatched">will be available</a> on OpenEdition Books in April 2014.<br /><br />The C.H. Beck catalogue on OpenEdition will initially include around 30 books drawn from its classical studies series (<a href="http://www.worldcat.org/oclc/1770618">Zetemata: Monographien zur klassischen Altertumswissenschaft</a>) and papyrus studies series (<a href="http://www.worldcat.org/oclc/781603360">Münchener Beiträge zur Papyrusforschung und antiken Rechtsgeschichte</a>). Two-thirds of the books will come from the classical studies series, which examines topics such as philology, history, epistemology and theology in the works of writers and philosophers of Ancient Greece and Rome. The papyrus studies series contributes to scholarship on the law, politics, economy and administration of ancient civilisations, notably the Ptolemaic and Hellenistic periods.<br /><br />Most of the books will be available in Open Access Freemium: free HTML, with PDF, ePub and eReader formats available exclusively to subscribing institutions and through digital bookstores.<br /><br />About<br /><br /><a href="http://rsw.beck.de/rsw/default.asp">C.H. Beck</a> is one of Germany’s oldest and most prestigious publishing houses. It has a backlist of more than 9,000 titles and 70 journals, covering disciplines as diverse as law, history, theology, classical studies, literary scholarship, and economics. Based in Munich, the company also has offices in Warsaw, Prague, Basel, Bucharest and Bratislava. It has been publishing electronic publications since the<br />late 1980s.<br /><br />OpenEdition is a leading digital portal for the humanities and social sciences. Run by the Centre for Open Electronic Publishing (Cléo) and supported by French research organisations, its four publishing platforms – Revues.org (journals), Hypotheses (academic blogs), Calenda (calls and announcements), OpenEdition Books (monographs and multi-author works) – receive almost 3 million visits a month. Launched in early 2013, OpenEdition Books provides access to over 1000 publications from 27 international publishers.<br /><br />Contact<br /><br />Lisa George, Communication Officer (English, French)<br />lisa.george@openedition.org / +33 (0)4 13 55 03 46<br /><br />Dr. Andrea Brill, Ansprechpartnerin C.H. Beck (German)<br />andrea.brill@beck.de / +49 (0)89 381 89 337<br /></span></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/192871254560613554/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/12/early-warnings-classical-studies-from.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/192871254560613554"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/192871254560613554"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/12/early-warnings-classical-studies-from.html"
         title="Early Warnings: Classical Studies from The C.H. Beck catalogue"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
