<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1877072299523590813</id>
   <published>2013-06-01T10:42:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-06-01T10:42:13.295-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Pedagogy"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Language"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Greek"/>
   <title type="text">Ancient Greek Tutorials</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/ancient_greek_start.html">Ancient Greek Tutorials</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/graphics/AGTtopgraphicU.gif" class="decoded" height="31" src="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/graphics/AGTtopgraphicU.gif" width="400" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Ancient Greek Tutorials, by Donald J.  Mastronarde with the assistance of the Berkeley Language Center of the  University of California, Berkeley.   <br />©1999-2005 The Regents of the University of California.</span> </span></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"> <br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">This site is made available to all users by the courtesy of the <a href="http://www.ucpress.edu/" target="_top">University of California Press</a><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/null">. Although much of it is based on a specific textbook for ancient Greek (see under </a><a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/welcomeU.html#credits">Credits</a>), the tutorials should be helpful to anyone learning ancient Greek from any textbook. </span></span><br /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;">Since the Berkeley Language Center is ceasing media duplication, it  is no longer possible to order a CD-ROm of these tutorials. Instead, as  of September 2009, for users who want to use the tutorials without being  connected to the internet, Release 1.5 has been prepared as a ZIP  archive that may be downloaded. The archive is about 20MB and will  expand to over 50MB on your computer. To download, <a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/AGTdownload.zip">click here</a>.</span></span><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/null" name="description"></a></span></span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF MODULES</span></span></span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">About the two versions:</span>As of January  15, 2013, only the Unicode version is hosted here, and this site is  tailored to the first edition of the textbook. The older (pre-Unicode,  GreekKeys) version has been removed. If you are using the second edition  of the textbook, then you should go to the revised version of this  site, located at <a href="http://atticgreek.org/" target="_blank">http://atticgreek.org</a>.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />    <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Pronunciation Guide</span> provides information  and examples for the pronunciation of the sounds of ancient Attic Greek.   Text-based in Unicode version, image-based in GreekKeys version.  Sounds are embedded and preloaded in Unicode version, individually  downloaded in older version.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Pronunciation Practice</span> provides examples of  pronunciation of over 100 basic Greek words (taken from the early  chapters of the textbook referred to under <a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/welcomeU.html#credits">Credits</a> below). Text-based in Unicode version, image-based in GreekKeys  version. Sounds are embedded and preloaded in Unicode version,  individually downloaded in older version.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Accentuation Tutorial</span> presents information  and examples to help in the understanding and mastery of the  accentuation system of ancient Attic Greek.  Text-based in Unicode  version, image-based in GreekKeys version.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Accentuation Practice</span> presents interactive  exercises to test and develop mastery of the accentuation system of  ancient Attic Greek. Identical in both versions, with image-based Greek  in the exercises.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Principal Parts</span> presents various drills for  principal parts (the full set of principal parts of over 250 verbs in the textbook are available; random drills and drills by alphabetic  set and verb type set are also available).  Identical in both versions,  with image-based Greek.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Vocabulary</span> presents over 1000 basic words  of Greek vocabulary, with choice of mode of action (study mode or drill  mode, Greek to English or English to Greek) and drill by alphabetic and  random sets as well as by units. Text-based in Unicode and GreekKeys  versions.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Verb Drill</span> presents Greek verb forms for  identification. There are about 1500 verb forms in the database. In  addition to drill by unit (matched to the book, but providing more forms  than in the Exercises), drill by random set and drill by sets defined  by type of form are available.  Text-based in Unicode and GreekKeys  versions.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Noun Drill</span> is a shorthand name for a  declensional drill including forms of nouns, adjectives, and pronouns.  There are about 900 forms in the database.  In addition to drill by unit  (matched to the book, but providing more forms than in the Exercises),  drill by random set and drill by sets defined by type of form are  available.   Text-based in Unicode and GreekKeys versions.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">English-Greek</span> provides drill in composing  Greek inflectional forms, using an on-screen keyboard (or in the Unicode  version, there is an option of direct input from the user's physical  keyboard). There are over 800 forms  available. Some of the items  correspond to similar exercises in the book, but there are also many  forms not in the printed exercises. Two modes of drill are available. In  the more elementary mode, the user's entry is corrected letter by  letter, and it is not possible to go on to the subsequent letter until  the current letter is correct. In the more challenging mode, the user  enters the whole answer and then asks to be checked; if the answer is  wrong, some guidance is given as to the error and the user can try to  fix the answer or ask to see the answer. Text-based in Unicode version  and in GreekKeys versions.&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />  <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="color: #993300;">Paradigms</span> presents verb paradigms and noun,  adjective, and pronoun paradigms. Text-based in Unicode version (html),  image-based in GreekKeys version (PDF).&nbsp;</span></span><br /><br />   <span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-family: inherit;"><a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/welcomeU.html#welcome">Introduction</a> | <a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/welcomeU.html#description">Description of Modules</a> | <a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/welcomeU.html#fonts">Fonts and Browser Settings</a>  | <a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/welcomeU.html#problems">Known Problems</a> | <a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/ancgreek/welcomeU.html#credits">Credits</a></span></span><br /></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">And see also AWOL's&nbsp; list of</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/09/open-access-textbooks.html">Open Access Textbooks and Language Primers Relating to the Ancient World </a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1877072299523590813/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/06/ancient-greek-tutorials.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1877072299523590813"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1877072299523590813"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/06/ancient-greek-tutorials.html"
         title="Ancient Greek Tutorials"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
