<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-500608700154864729</id>
   <published>2011-08-08T14:19:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2014-01-03T13:17:09.854-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Cuneiform Digital Library Notes</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">First posted in AWOL&nbsp; <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/08/open-access-journals-cuneiform-digital.html">31 August 2009</a>.&nbsp; Updated 3 January 2014]</span><br /><br /><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/">Cuneiform Digital Library Notes</a><br />&nbsp;ISSN 1546-6566<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/"><img alt=" " border="0" height="78" hspace="0" src="http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/ashmolean/cdli_blue.jpg" vspace="0" width="250" /></a> </div></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/"><i>Cuneiform Digital Library Notes</i></a> is a non-profit, electronic bulletin board for cuneiform studies. We  have set ourselves the task of publishing in this online journal short  notices of a high academic standard which also try to utilize the  potential of electronic publication.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Notes are supported by a number of institutions, chief among them  the University of California, Los Angeles, and the Max Planck Institute  for the History of Science, Berlin. Primary academic supervision of the  Journal derives from the <i>Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative</i> (<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/index.html"><i>CDLI</i></a>).</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">  </span><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">About the Notes</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">  </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><i>Cuneiform Digital Library Notes</i> is an electronic journal  constituted in conjunction with the organization and work of the  Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative to afford contributors to that  effort the opportunity to make known to an international community the  results of their research into topics related to those of the CDLI.  </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <i>CDLN</i> is a moderated e-bulletin board for Assyriology and is conceived as a notepad publication of the <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/Pubs/cdlj.html">Cuneiform Digital Library Journal</a> and the <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/Pubs/cdlb.html">Cuneiform Digital Library Bulletin</a>. The <i>CDLJ</i> seeks substantive contributions dealing with the major themes of the  Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative, that is, with text analyses of 4th  and 3rd millennium documents (incorporating text, photographs, data,  drawings, interpretations), early language, writing, paleography,  administrative history, mathematics, metrology, and the technology of  modern cuneiform editing. Articles in the <i>CDLB</i> are shorter  contributions of two to five pages that deal with specific topics,  collations, etc., and do not attempt to offer synthetic treatments of  complex subjects. The <i>CDLN</i> assumes the role of a bulletin board for the quick publication and internet distribution of short notices of at most one page.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <i>CDLN</i> is hosted by the <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/index.html">Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative</a>, LA/Berlin, and is in the editorial care of <a href="http://www.orinst.ox.ac.uk/staff/eanes/kwagensonner.html">Klaus Wagensonner</a> (University of Oxford).</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"> </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">Authors who are interested in submitting contributions to the <i>CDLN</i> should read the <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/Pubs/edpol.html">editorial policies</a> and the <a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/Pubs/guide_index.html">guidelines for authors</a> of the larger journals <i>CDLJ&amp;B</i>. In line with the publication policies of the <i>CDLJ&amp;B</i>, all contributions to the <i>Notes</i> will be linked to the online resources of the CDLI and other stable URL  addresses. In contrast to the peer-review process instituted by the  editorial board of the larger journals, however, contributions to the  CDLN will as a rule be moderated and posted by staff at UCLA; they will  not be entered into a downloadable PDF fine-print version, with the  exception of those contributions that contain high-resolution graphics  (the usual means of paper prints of the contributions will be through a  corresponding link located at the bottom of each note); and they will  have a preprint period of just fifteen days (the date of note  "archivization" is also at the bottom of each entry).&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Please report any problems, comments or suggestions to <a href="mailto:cdlj@ucla.edu">cdlj@ucla.edu</a></span></blockquote><div class="menuwrapper" id="menuwrapper">    <ul><li><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/#">General</a>            </li><li><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/#">Links</a>            </li><li><a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/pubs/cdln/#">Archive</a>            </li></ul></div><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span>See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></div><br /><script src="http://s7.addthis.com/js/250/addthis_widget.js?pub=xa-4a3fbb0e7571e986" type="text/javascript"></script>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/500608700154864729/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/08/open-access-journal-cuneiform-digital.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/500608700154864729"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/500608700154864729"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/08/open-access-journal-cuneiform-digital.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Cuneiform Digital Library Notes"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
