<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-2386735939976246321</id>
   <published>2010-12-22T11:30:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2010-12-22T11:27:31.089-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New at ARTstor</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[&nbsp;New collections at ARTstor relating to Antiquity<br /><br /><a href="http://www.artstor.org/what-is-artstor/w-html/col-langdale-cyprus.shtml">Allan Langdale: Cyprus Archive</a><br />[December 22, 2010]<br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">ARTstor is collaborating with Allan Langdale to share more than 3,300  images of the historical architecture of Cyprus. This collection was  compiled between 2006 and 2008 and focuses on the lesser known and, in  some cases, endangered architecture and archaeological sites of northern  Cyprus. The archive includes Bronze Age sites such as Enkomi and the  Tombs of the Kings, and the early Christian basilicas of Salamis. The  bulk of the collection consists of dozens of examples of the Byzantine  architecture of the region, including examples largely unavailable to  researchers since the embargoes imposed on North Cyprus in 1974. There  are detailed sets of images of the better-known buildings, such as the  Panagia Kanakaria, and a number of medieval churches of Nicosia  (Lefkosa), such as the St. Sophia Cathedral and the St. Nicholas  Cathedral (the Bedestan). The most comprehensive portion of the  collection focuses on the Lusignan Gothic churches of Famagusta,  including the cathedrals of St. Nicholas, St. George of the Greeks, St.  George of the Latins, and Saints Peter and Paul. </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Allan Langdale is an art historian, photographer, and filmmaker  whose current research interests are in Cyprus, where he has done work  on the medieval and Venetian monuments of Famagusta. </span></blockquote><a href="http://library.artstor.org/library/welcome.html">Log In to ARTstor</a><br /><br /><a href="http://artstor.wordpress.com/2010/04/16/now-available-final-images-of-classical-sculptures-from-the-berlin-state-museums/">Final images of Classical sculptures from the Berlin State Museums</a><br />[April 23, 2010]<br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;">The Prussian Cultural Properties Foundation (Stiftung Preussischer  Kulturbesitz) and ARTstor have collaborated to digitize key works of  Classical sculpture from the Berlin State Museums (Staatliche Museen zu  Berlin). Now held in the Pergamon Museum and Altes Museum in Berlin, the  collection of Classical Antiquities (Antikensammlung) is one of the  most important collections of Classical art in the world. This final  release includes approximately 170 images of Greek, Hellenistic, and  Roman sculptures, bringing the collection total in ARTstor to nearly 580  images.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;">To view the Classical Sculptures (Berlin State Museums) collection:  go to the ARTstor Digital Library, browse by collection, and click  “Classical Sculptures (Berlin State Museums);” or enter the keyword  search: smb berlin</span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;">For more detailed information about this collection, visit the <a href="http://www.artstor.org/what-is-artstor/w-html/col-sculpture-berlin.shtml" target="_blank" title="Go to the Berlin State Museums collection page">Classical Sculptures (Berlin State Museums)</a>  collection page.</span></blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span><br /><a href="http://library.artstor.org/library/welcome.html">Log In to  ARTstor</a><br /><br /><a href="http://artstor.wordpress.com/2010/04/07/now-available-additional-plans-of-ancient-and-medieval-buildings-and-archaeological-sites-from-bryn-mawr-college/">Plans of Ancient and Medieval Buildings and Archaeological Sites</a>  (Bryn Mawr College)<br />[April 8,2010]<br /><span style="font-size: 85%;"></span><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: 85%;">The final set of images depicting plans of archaeological sites and  architectural monuments contributed by Bryn Mawr College are now  available in the Digital Library, bringing the collection total to  nearly 8,000 images. This third release for the Plans of Ancient and  Medieval Buildings and Archaeological Sites (Bryn Mawr College)  collection includes site plans of Ancient and Classical sites in the  Near East and Europe, primarily Greece, Italy, and Turkey, from the 10th  century BCE through the 6th century CE.</span><br /><span style="font-size: 85%;">With a collection of over 200,000 slides and 50,000 digital images, <a class="popup" href="http://www.brynmawr.edu/library/visualresources/" target="_blank" title="Open  Visual Resources Center at Bryn Mawr website in a new window"> the Visual Resources Center at Bryn Mawr  College</a>  supports the image needs of several academic departments,  including the History of Art, Archaeology, Classics, and Growth and  Structure of Cities. Within the collection, there is a set of  approximately 8,000 black-and-white slides depicting archaeological and  building site plans. These slides reflect Bryn Mawr College's current  and historical academic strengths in Archaeology and Art History,  particularly relating to the Classical and Ancient Near East, as well as  Medieval Europe. Through a partnership with ARTstor, Bryn Mawr College  will be contributing several collections to the Digital Library,  including this collection of site plans for key Ancient and Medieval  architectural monuments and archeological sites. <a href="http://www.artstor.org/what-is-artstor/w-html/col-lantern-bryn-mawr.shtml" title="Go to the Classical Antiquity Lantern Slide Collection page">The  Classical Antiquity Lantern Slide Collection</a> and the <a href="http://www.artstor.org/what-is-artstor/w-html/col-bryn-mawr-melli.shtml" title="Go to the Mellink Archive collection page">Mellink Archive</a>  from Bryn Mawr College are also available in ARTstor. </span></blockquote><a href="http://library.artstor.org/library/welcome.html">Log In to ARTstor</a><br /><br /><span style="font-size: 100%;"><div><a href="http://draft.blogger.com/post-edit.g?blogID=116259103207720939&amp;postID=2386735939976246321" id="data:post.url" name="data:post.title" onclick="return addthis_sendto()" onmouseout="addthis_close()" onmouseover="'return"><img alt="Bookmark and    Share so Your Real Friends Know that You Know" height="16" src="http://s7.addthis.com/static/btn/lg-share-en.gif" style="border: 0pt none;" width="125" /></a></div></span>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/2386735939976246321/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/new-at-artstor.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2386735939976246321"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/2386735939976246321"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/04/new-at-artstor.html"
         title="New at ARTstor"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
