<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-230819715784827261</id>
   <published>2013-04-04T10:45:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-04-04T10:45:39.367-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Palestine"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Jerusalam"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Israel"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="History"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="archaeology"/>
   <title type="text">Jerusalem Virtual Library: The Academic Database on Historic Jerusalem</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.jerusalem-library.org/">Jerusalem Virtual Library: The Academic Database on Historic Jerusalem</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.jerusalem-library.org/pics/intro1.gif" class="decoded" height="53" src="http://www.jerusalem-library.org/pics/intro1.gif" width="400" /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Jerusalem Library, initiated in 2001 by Prof. Sari Nusseibah,  President of Al-Quds University and Prof. Ronnie Ellenblum of The Hebrew  University of Jerusalem, is meant to be a comprehensive resource for  the history of Jerusalem. The library, hosted together by the two  universities, enables free access to digitized historical materials and  primary sources about Jerusalem. The collections are based on the  archives of the Jewish National Library, the Israel Antiquities  Authority and the collections of al-Quds University. </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">To date, most of the historical sources are kept in national, religious,  municipal and private archives and are not accessible to all. Physical  and non-tangible barriers prevent potential readers, in Jerusalem and  elsewhere from exploring the vast and complicated history of the city.  The virtual library is meant to overcome these barriers </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Library makes use of innovative content-oriented IT tools and  enables a more convenient, home-based search in the documents  themselves. The biggest part of the collections are books, maps,  photographs, engravings and inscriptions published for the first time  before the beginning of the 20th century.  </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The material is scanned, OCR'd and thoroughly indexed.  The indexing was  carried out by a group of Palestinian and Israeli students who were  supervised by specialists specializing in Classical Languages, Arabic  and Islamic Studies, Hebrew and Jewish Studies, Geography History and  Christianity, </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The basic idea of the library is to enable the user to retrieve indexed  extracts of various fields. Efforts were made to include topics such as  gender, feelings, various stages in life, love, war, hatred,  inter-community relations and other topics which are usually not  included in traditional indexes. These features will enable the Library  users to directly access historical data, thus eliminating the external  narrator or historian as the interpreter of history.    </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Creating such an academic unbiased approach to the history of  Jerusalem is a challenging task for while Jerusalem is the contested  capital of two peoples, it is also a spiritual center for each of the  world's three monotheistic religions and a universal symbol of hope and  holiness. Through the Library, Jerusalem will be made accessible not  only to its own residents and the countries that shoulder responsibility  for its future, but to the entire world.     </span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/230819715784827261/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/04/jerusalem-virtual-library-academic.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/230819715784827261"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/230819715784827261"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/04/jerusalem-virtual-library-academic.html"
         title="Jerusalem Virtual Library: The Academic Database on Historic Jerusalem"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
