<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8583251213274566941</id>
   <published>2013-08-16T08:42:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-08-16T08:58:44.547-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Early Warnings:  AIA Archive to be Publicly Accessible for the First Time in 135 Years</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.archaeological.org/news/13353?utm_source=MailerMailer&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=AIA+Archives+to+Become+Publicly+Accessible&amp;utm_campaign=AIA+e-Update">Archaeological Archive to be Publicly Accessible for the First Time in 135 Years</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>PRESS RELEASE&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </b>August 14, 2013</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>Contact:&nbsp;</b>Elizabeth Christian</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Archaeological Institute of America </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">656 Beacon Street</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Boston, MA 02215</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Tel: 617.353.9361 </span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">E-mail: <a href="mailto:echristian@aia.bu.edu">echristian@aia.bu.edu</a></span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>RE: &nbsp;Archaeological Archive to be Publicly Accessible for First Time in 135 Years</b></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Archaeological Institute of America, North America’s largest and  oldest non-profit organization devoted to archaeology, will make the  extensive archival materials of its 135-year history available online,  thanks to a grant from the Leon Levy Foundation.&nbsp; The project will  include the complete inventorying of the AIA Archive, digitization and  translation of all documents, and deposition of the entire digital  Archive at the AIA’s host institution Boston University, where it will  be universally available via open access.</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">AIA President Elizabeth Bartman applauded the grant: “The Leon Levy  Foundation’s generous support will facilitate not only an understanding  of our institutional past but also of what was, at the time of the AIA’s  founding in 1879, a new discipline of study.&nbsp; At its heart, a study of  the AIA is an exploration of intellectual history.”</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The vast AIA Archive includes such materials as founding documents  (including those related to the AIA’s Congressional charter);  presidential correspondence; minutes of board meetings; formal and legal  reports; AIA publications (the early <i>Papers</i>, the <i>American Journal of Archaeology</i>, and <i>Art and Archaeology</i>, later renamed <i>Archaeology</i>);  as well as materials from annual meetings, lectures, and site  preservation efforts. In addition, papers record the AIA’s early  archaeological work in Assos (Turkey), Crete, Croton (Italy), Cyrene  (Libya), and Tarsus (Turkey), and document the AIA’s role in the  foundation of the American School of Classical Studies at Athens, the  American School of Classical Studies in Rome (later the American  Academy), and the School of American Archaeology.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Systematizing and digitizing the AIA Archive fulfills a long-desired  goal of making it broadly available to archaeologists, scholars, and the  general public.&nbsp; Susan Heuck Allen, AIA member and author of several  books that are based on primary research in the Archive, notes that the  Leon Levy Foundation gift will offer scholars the opportunity “to dig  into the Institute’s own stratigraphy to understand the development of  our discipline and the context of the United States and its  excavations.”</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Leon Levy Foundation is a leader in&nbsp;providing funding to  catalogue and make accessible important cultural archives; it has long  supported the excavation of the ancient seaport of Ashkelon and the  publication of archaeological fieldwork. It recently granted lead  support to a new collaboration between the British Museum and the Penn  Museum that will produce a dynamic online resource to the archaeology of  the ancient kingdom of Ur.&nbsp;Work on the Archive is expected to begin  immediately and the entire collection will be available in the fall of  2016.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>About AIA</b></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Archaeological Institute of America (AIA) promotes archaeological  inquiry and public understanding of the material record of the human  past to foster an appreciation of diverse cultures and our shared  humanity. The AIA supports archaeologists, their research and its  dissemination, and the ethical practice of archaeology. The AIA educates  people of all ages about the significance of archaeological discovery  and advocates the preservation of the world's archaeological heritage.  Learn more by visiting <a href="http://draft.blogger.com/null">www.archaeological.org</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><b>About the Leon Levy Foundation</b></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Leon Levy Foundation, founded in 2004, is a private,  not-for-profit foundation created from the estate of Leon Levy, an  investor with a longstanding commitment to philanthropy. The  Foundation's overarching goal is to support scholarship at the highest  level, ultimately advancing knowledge and improving the lives of  individuals and society at large. <a href="http://www.leonlevyfoundation.org/" target="_blank">www.leonlevyfoundation.org</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.archaeological.org/news/13353?utm_source=MailerMailer&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_content=AIA+Archives+to+Become+Publicly+Accessible&amp;utm_campaign=AIA+e-Update#sthash.hU7kLPn0.dpuf">See more</a></span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8583251213274566941/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/early-warnings-archaeological-archive.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8583251213274566941"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8583251213274566941"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/early-warnings-archaeological-archive.html"
         title="Early Warnings:  AIA Archive to be Publicly Accessible for the First Time in 135 Years"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
