<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4164180518743714578</id>
   <published>2014-01-14T09:15:00.001-05:00</published>
   <updated>2014-01-14T09:15:48.531-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Photography"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Description and Travel"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Archaeoloy"/>
   <title type="text">Non-Professional Archaeological Photographs-project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.npaph.com/">Non-Professional Archaeological Photographs-project</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.npaph.com/NPAPHLogo.fw.png" class="decoded" src="http://www.npaph.com/NPAPHLogo.fw.png" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The NPAPH-project has the aim to trace former students and volunteers  who joined an  excavation prior to the 1980s, to collect and digitise  their photographic  documentation, and, finally, to make it accessible  to the public via digital archives. Furthermore, the project pleads for  an international collaboration between archaeological institutions in  order to  connect these digital archives  and bring them under the  attention of the public by the use of this website.</span><br /><br />          <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Context</strong></span><br />     <span style="font-size: x-small;">As  the discipline of archaeology has developed significantly  during the last six  decades, it is inevitable that the views on how the  progress and finds of an  excavation should be recorded, have changed  as well. All  the developments that have influenced archaeological  recording suggest that  there may be a hiatus between what  archaeologists actually recorded in the past  and what we nowadays  expect them to have documented at the time. It is the basic assumption  of this project that the former 'non-professionals' - participants  of  excavations who were not part of the trained staff, but who supported  the dig  as part of their continual education or out of interest, e.g.  students and volunteers - may be the ones who  are able to fill in the  possible gap in the official documentation published by  the academic  staff, including in the area of archaeological photography.</span><br /><br />     <span style="font-size: x-small;">The project will <em>in the first instance</em> focus on the  period 1950-1980. This period is very interesting, because the lack of  ubiquitous  multimedia, poor photographic recording techniques and the  high costs of the reproduction  of photographs in those days generally  restricted the amount of official  documentation. By choosing the middle  of the last century as starting-point,  the presence of students and  volunteers at an excavation is more likely and the  chance that former  non-professionals are still alive is fairly high, which would  simplify  the tracing considerable. The  tracing will be possible, on the one  hand, with the aid of registers that are  kept in universities and  archaeological institutions, containing personal details  of former  participants,&nbsp;and, on the  other hand, with the aid of the internet and  social media.&nbsp;</span><br /><br />     <span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>Join the NPAPH-project!</strong></span><br /><br />     <span style="font-size: x-small;"> Based  on the reasons described at the section 'Principles', it  will be useful for archaeological  institutions to trace  non-professional photographs of their excavations, to digitise  and  place them in an accessible digital archive for both scholars and the  general  public, and to participate in the NPAPH-project. It  will be  worth the effort! After all, ‘digging’ into the archaeological past in   this way will not only be beneficial to present archaeological research,  but it  will also be an inspiring assignment for our students and  volunteers of today,  to assist in the process of tracing, collecting  and digitising photographs.</span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.npaph.com/index.html">Home</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.npaph.com/Principles.html"> Principles</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.npaph.com/Partners.html">Participants</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.npaph.com/Excavations.html">Excavations</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.npaph.com/Archives.html">Archives</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.npaph.com/ublications.html">Publications</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.npaph.com/Contact.html">Contact</a></span></li></ul></blockquote><br />]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4164180518743714578/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/01/non-professional-archaeological.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4164180518743714578"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4164180518743714578"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2014/01/non-professional-archaeological.html"
         title="Non-Professional Archaeological Photographs-project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
