<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-5115103761130647413</id>
   <published>2012-10-09T11:44:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-08-07T08:10:50.756-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Early Warning: California Classical Studies: Open-Access Digital Publication Project</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://calclassicalstudies.org/">California Classical Studies</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">Open-Access Digital Publication Project Launched</span></h2><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <a href="http://classics.berkeley.edu/">Department of Classics of the University of California, Berkeley</a>,  is pleased to announce the initiation of new publication series  entitled <b><a href="http://calclassicalstudies.org/">California Classical Studie</a>s</b>. The series is  intended to provide a peer-reviewed open-access venue for disseminating  basic research, data-heavy research, including archaeological research,  and highly specialized research of the kind that is either hard to place  with the leading publishers in Classics or extremely expensive for  libraries and individuals when produced by a leading academic publisher.  It aims to promote open access to such scholarship both in the interest  of university library budgets and in the interest of attaining the  widest possible dissemination of up-to-date, peer-reviewed classical  scholarship.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The three-year startup phase of the project is supported by a grant  of $99,000 from the <a href="http://www.mellon.org/grant_programs/programs/scit">Andrew W. Mellon Foundation (Scholarly Communications and Information Technology)</a>. <a href="http://ucbclassics.dreamhosters.com/djm/">Donald Mastronarde</a> will lead an editorial board drawn from faculty in Classics and Ancient  History and Mediterranean Archaeology at UC Berkeley and from other  institutions in the western United States. No affiliation with UC will  be required for submissions. Online open access and Print on Demand  copies will be provided through participation in the publishing partners  program of UC’s <a href="http://www.cdlib.org/">California Digital Library</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Apart from aiming to publish 15 titles in the first three to four  years, the startup phase will also test different workflows for  production and assess the impact of various pricing models for Print on  Demand and ebook versions. Some works will have images, plans, datasets,  or other material offered only online. While every work will be  available in full for page view from the date of first appearance, the  series will experiment with the feasibility of shorter and longer  embargo periods, or no embargo period, before free download of a full  PDF is made available. Finally, the project is intended to find a path  to sustainability, which will depend partly on how much revenue can be  generated from sales and how far down production costs can be driven,  but also on the willingness of institutions, administrators, and  individual scholars with access to research grants to make an initial  investment in open-access scholarly communication rather than bear the  costs of library purchases and especially of ongoing licensing fees for  digital material controlled by major publishers.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">California Classical Studies will also republish under the open-access model some previous scholarship, including Leslie Kurke’s<i> <a href="http://www.worldcat.org/oclc/246756454">The Traffic in Praise</a></i> (1990), one or two major out-of-print commentaries on classical texts,  and coherent collections of a selection of a scholar’s articles. In the  initial phase, most authors are expected to be tenured scholars who  believe in promoting the open-access model, but the series also plans to  sponsor a competition for one or two distingished first books by junior  scholars, with all costs of production borne by the grant.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Current members of the editorial board are Donald Mastronarde  (chair), Alessandro Barchiesi (Stanford and Siena/Arezzo), Todd Hickey,  Emily Mackil, Robert Morstein-Marx (UC Santa Barbara), Ted Peña, and Kim  Shelton.</span></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">And see now: <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/08/california-classical-studies-launched.html">California Classical Studies Launched</a></div><br />&nbsp; ]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/5115103761130647413/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/early-warning-california-classical.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5115103761130647413"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/5115103761130647413"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/early-warning-california-classical.html"
         title="Early Warning: California Classical Studies: Open-Access Digital Publication Project"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
