<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8730787142197817380</id>
   <published>2010-03-08T11:51:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2012-06-02T15:16:43.488-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">HESTIA: the Herodotus Encoded Space-Text-Imaging Archive</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/Arts/hestia/">HESTIA: the Herodotus Encoded Space-Text-Imaging Archive</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">In the fifth book of his <span class="name">History</span>, Herodotus  describes a meeting between Cleomenes, king of Sparta, and Aristagoras,  tyrant of Miletus, who has come to Lacedaemon to solicit support for a  revolt of Ionian Greeks from Persian control. Having brought with him 'a  bronze tablet on which a chart of the whole land was engraved' (5.49)  and to which he repeatedly referred, Aristagoras was doing well until  Cleomenes asked how many days' journey the proposed expedition would  take his army from the sea. When the response came back 'three months',  Cleomenes bade his Milesian guest depart Sparta before sunset.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The story raises several key issues relevant to the representation and conception of space  in Herodotus' <span class="name">History</span>.  First, the example presents a decentred world: though the dialogue  takes place in the Spartan heartland of Greece, the reader is invited to  imagine a land far distant even from the Greek settlements in Asia  Minor. Second, that distance is conceived in terms of a journey, three  months from the sea; that is, space is portrayed as a phenomenon which  is experienced rather an abstract notion. Third, the idea of space as  something lived and relative lays emphasis on human agents as  focalisers: the arguments of the worldly Aristagoras (tyrant of a city  at the hub of trade routes on the margins of the Persian empire) fall on  the deaf ears of the king of a land-bound people (whose very territory,  the Peloponnesos, signifies an 'island'): different peoples have  different conceptions of space. Fourth, in spite of the rival spatial  perceptions of the two characters, Herodotus represents a horizon of  networks, by virtue of which decisions made in one place reverberate  through the whole region. Lastly, the role of the narrator in the  construction of space introduces the issue of narrativity, particularly  since Herodotus glosses Aristagoras' visual display of space with his  own discursive representation of that space (5.52-4)...</span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"> <br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">... HESTIA intends to rely on the latest geo-referencing techniques in the  e-resource Classics community, while contributing to their efforts to  disseminate the latest research to a broader audience. The importance of  space and time, and their representation, has emerged as a key area in  the so-called 'arts and humanities e-science' agenda, co-ordinated by  the <a href="http://ahessc.ac.uk/">Arts and Humanities e-Science Support Centre</a> at King's College, London. The 'mashupping' technique, pioneered by the <a href="http://pleiades.stoa.org/">Pleiades project</a> at the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill  offers a methodology  and potential collaboration for the digitalisation of spatial data in  Herodotus.</span><br /><ul><li><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/Arts/hestia/index.html" id="nav-index">Home</a></li><li class="currentsection"><span class="youarehere" id="nav-project">About</span></li><li><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/Arts/hestia/team/index.html" id="nav-team">Team</a></li><li><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/Arts/hestia/activities/index.html" id="nav-activities">Activities</a></li><li><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/Arts/hestia/findings/index.html" id="nav-findings">Technologies</a></li><li><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/Arts/hestia/outcomes/index.html" id="nav-findings">Outcomes</a></li><li><a href="http://www.open.ac.uk/Arts/hestia/contact/index.html" id="nav-findings">Co</a></li></ul></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8730787142197817380/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/03/hestia.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8730787142197817380"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8730787142197817380"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/03/hestia.html"
         title="HESTIA: the Herodotus Encoded Space-Text-Imaging Archive"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
