<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1840555661920033989</id>
   <published>2011-05-31T09:43:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-05-31T11:12:51.240-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Assyrian Empire Builders</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.ucl.ac.uk/sargon/">Assyian Empire Builders: Governors, diplomats and soldiers in the service of Sargon II, king of Assyria</a><br /><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">In the second half of the eighth century BC, Assyria was the most powerful state in the Middle East: regions far beyond the Assyrian heartland in the north of modern-day Iraq, demarcated by the triangle formed by the ancient cities of Assur, Nineveh and Arbail, were annexed as provinces to form an empire that stretched from the Mediterranean Sea to the Persian Gulf, from the fringes of the Arabian desert to western Iran and central Anatolia.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">About 1,200 letters and letter fragments survive of the correspondence of king Sargon II (721-705 BC) with his governors and magnates. They were retrieved in the shape of the original clay tablets during excavations in the royal cities of Kalhu (modern Nimrud) and Nineveh (modern Mossul). This corpus of letters between a king and his high officials, the largest known from antiquity, gives first-hand insight into the mechanisms of communication between the top levels of authority in an ancient empire.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The four crucial edited volumes of this correspondence in the Assyrian and Babylonian dialects are:</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">S. Parpola, The Correspondence of Sargon II, Part I: Letters from Assyria and the West (State Archives of Assyria 1), Helsinki 1987</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">G. B. Lanfranchi and S. Parpola, The Correspondence of Sargon II, Part II: Letters from the Northern and Northeastern Provinces (State Archives of Assyria 5), Helsinki 1990</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A. Fuchs and S. Parpola, The Correspondence of Sargon II, Part III: Letters from Babylonia and the Eastern Provinces (State Archives of Assyria 15), Helsinki 2001</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">M. Dietrich, The Neo-Babylonian Correspondence of Sargon and Sennacherib (State Archives of Assyria 17), Helsinki 2003</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">With the kind permission of the authors and the Neo-Assyrian Text Corpus Project, this project brings together translations and transliterations of all 1,200 of these texts, adding explanatory and supplementary materials in order to provide the historical context.</span></blockquote><br /><span style="font-size: small;">Assyrian Empire Builders and <a href="http://knp.prs.heacademy.ac.uk/">Knowledge and Power</a> are portals to <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/07/state-archives-of-assyria-online-saao.html">State Archives of Assyria Online</a> </span><br /><span style="font-size: small;"> </span><br /><div class="post-header"></div><span style="font-size: small;"> and are components of <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/07/open-richly-annotated-cuneiform-corpus.html">The Open Richly Annotated Cuneiform Corpus (ORACC).</a></span>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1840555661920033989/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/05/assyrian-empire-builders.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1840555661920033989"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1840555661920033989"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/05/assyrian-empire-builders.html"
         title="Assyrian Empire Builders"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
