<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-8358211901528843000</id>
   <published>2011-04-01T09:55:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-04-01T14:16:10.219-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">ETANA Updated</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.etana.org/home">ETANA:  Electronic Tools and Ancient Near Eastern Archives</a><br /><br /><div style="text-align: center;">On 31 March 2011, <a href="http://www.etana.org/">ETANA</a> launched a new interface.</div><div style="text-align: center;"><br /></div><div align="center" style="margin: 0pt 2px 0pt 6px;"><img border="0" height="178" src="http://www.bibliotecapleyades.net/sitchin/gallery/z_etana.jpg" vspace="10" width="575" /></div><div style="text-align: center;">&nbsp;<span style="font-size: xx-small;">The Myth of Etana</span></div><blockquote style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">ETANA is a multi-institutional collaborative project initiated in  August 2000, as an electronic publishing project designed to enhance the  study of the history and culture of the ancient Near East.  Funded  initially by a planning grant from the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, then  by a larger digitization grant from the same foundation, the ETANA web  portal  was launched in 2002.  The founding institutions and  associations that conceived and implemented this project were:</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">American Oriental Society</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">American Schools of Oriental Research</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Case Western Reserve University</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Cobb Institute of Archeology</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Oriental Institute (University of Chicago)</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Society of Biblical Literature</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Vanderbilt University Divinity School</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Vanderbilt University Library</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Vanderbilt University Press</span></li></ul><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Mellon grant funded the conversion of <a href="http://www.etana.org/abzubib">Abzu</a> from a collection of  static html pages to a database delivery platform, the digitization of  almost 200 volumes of core materials for the study of the Ancient Near  East, and the development of the web portal.&nbsp;</span></blockquote><blockquote style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">ETANA&nbsp; has  digitized, and continues to digitize, <a href="http://www.etana.org/coretexts">Core Texts</a> selected as valuable for  teaching and research relating to ancient Near Eastern studies. We have  selected primarily editions that are outside of copyright, or with the  permission of copyright holders. While the new electronic editions we  have produced are under copyright, the ETANA project chooses to make  these freely available for noncommercial teaching and research purposes.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">See the <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/04/open-access-monographs-etana-core-texts.html">full listing of ETANA Core Texts at AWOL</a>.</span></blockquote><blockquote style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Early on discussions began among the advisory panel of the need for  an archival repository for archaeological data.  It was with this need  in mind that the ETANA partners sought and received a National Science  Foundation grant in 2004, to develop software to create electronic  mappings to allow searching across excavation sites.  The prototype  “<a href="http://www.etana.org/projects">Digbase</a>” structure was designed at Virginia Tech by Professor Ed Fox  and his students, with Professor James Flanagan and Joanne Eustis,  University Librarian both of Case Western University, serving as the  principal investigators of the grant. </span><span style="font-size: x-small;">ETANA is&nbsp;</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"> now working with the  <a href="http://alexandriaarchive.org/">Alexandria Archive Institute</a> to develop a more robust platform for the ETANA-DL data.</span></blockquote><blockquote style="font-family: inherit;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"> Additional Core Texts were digitized as a part of USAID grant to assist  Iraqi universities rebuild their archaeology programs and collections.    Stony Brook University in New York State has digitized 181 cuneiform  text publications and archaeological site reports, including  dissertations relating to archaeology in Iraq. Prof. Elizabeth Stone was  the Principal Investigator for this grant.  Vanderbilt Divinity Library  also digitized additional Core Texts for ETANA, using a grant from the  Cooperative Digital Resources Initiative (CDRI).  This small grant  allowed for the addition of 30 additional volumes to the Core Texts  corpus.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />Professor Jack Sasson of Vanderbilt University conceived of the <a href="http://www.etana.org/etact">eTACT  database</a>, based on discussions at the Muenster Rencontre in 2006, a  collection of English language translations of Akkadian texts, which was  added to the ETANA portal in 2007.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/8358211901528843000/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/04/etana-updated.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8358211901528843000"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/8358211901528843000"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/04/etana-updated.html"
         title="ETANA Updated"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
