<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7896493959010495915</id>
   <published>2012-01-29T20:27:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2012-01-29T20:27:23.406-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">News from the CDLI: Mellon-funded digitization of the Geneva cuneiform collection</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div><b>Mellon-funded digitization of the Geneva cuneiform collection</b></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">We  are delighted to announce a successful digitization collaboration  between the Musées d’Art et d’Histoire of Geneva (MAH) and the Andrew W.  Mellon Foundation-supported research project "Creating a Sustainable  Digital Cuneiform Library (CSDCL)."</span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">Under the  general direction of the Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative (CDLI -  Los Angeles/Berlin), CSDCL is dedicated to the digital capture,  persistent archiving and web dissemination of major cuneiform  collections in the US, Europe and the Middle East. The 950 cuneiform  artifacts of the MAH, originally collected by the noted Swiss  Assyrioliogist Alfred Boissier (1867-1945, PhD 1890 at Leipzig under F.  Delitzsch) and acquired by the Museum in 1938, represent a significant  archive of texts in a major Swiss collection. In communications dating  back to early 2008 between one of us (<span class="il">Englund</span>)  and Antoine Cavigneaux of the University of Geneva, the capture of the  MAH cuneiform collection was discussed and a plan for this collaboration  presented by Cavigneaux to the Museum early in 2011. With the support  of Geneva graduate student Émilie Pagé-Perron, CDLI's catalogue  documenting the MAH collection, then numbering 391 entries of published  texts dating to the 3rd millennium BC as well as to the Old Assyrian  period, was supplemented with the full electronic catalogue of artifacts  supplied by the Museum. Once an agreement of cooperation was signed  between CDLI and MAH, CSDCL's Max Planck Institute for the History of  Science (Berlin) postdoctoral researcher Ludek Vacin arranged for two  capture missions to Geneva, that took place in July and November of  2011. Following fatcross-processing and cleansing in Los Angeles of the  raw images created by Vacin, these files have now been posted to the  CDLI website, and can be viewed at &lt;<a href="http://cdli.ucla.edu/collections/mah/mah_fr.html" target="_blank">http://cdli.ucla.edu/<wbr></wbr>collections/mah/mah_fr.html</a>&gt;.  Pagé-Perron and Emmert Clevenstine of the University of Geneva are  correcting the bibliographical and text content references in the MAH  catalogue, and the imaging of some few remaining texts by Ms.  Pagé-Perron will complete the formal capture of the originals.</span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">MAH  enthusiastically joined this effort to make available its complete  cuneiform collection to the world-wide community of web researchers and  informal learners. This new web content will assist cuneiform  specialists in the collation of existing &nbsp;editions, including ca. 290 Ur  III records published by H. Sauren in MVN 2 (1974); 52 Old Assyrian  texts by P. Garelli in RA 59-60 (1965-1966); 20 Ur III letters by E.  Sollberger, TCS 1 (1966), as well as 8 ED IIIb accounts by the same  author in Genava 26 (1948); and 30 texts from various periods by W.  Deonna in Genava 17 (1939) (in JCS 5 [1951], Sollberger published  catalogue treatments of a large number of still unedited MAH tablets).  We believe that general access to images of all text artifacts  establishes the broadest possible foundation for integrative research on  MAH and related cuneiform inscriptions by the scholarly community, and  we are particularly keen to assist specialists in the preparation of  scholarly editions of the nearly 500 documents currently listed as  "unpublished unassigned" in our catalogue entries (&lt;<a href="http://tinyurl.com/6ugtndn" target="_blank">http://tinyurl.com/6ugtndn</a>&gt;)</span><wbr></wbr><span style="font-size: x-small;">.&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">We  are confident that our adherence in this collaboration to the  principles of open access expressed, for instance, in the "Berlin  Declaration on Open Access to Knowledge in the Sciences and Humanities,"  promulgated by the German Max Planck Society (&lt;<a href="http://oa.mpg.de/lang/en-uk/berlin-prozess/berliner-erklarung/" target="_blank">http://oa.mpg.de/lang/en-uk/<wbr></wbr>berlin-prozess/berliner-<wbr></wbr>erklarung/</a>&gt;),  best serves all in the Humanities, but particularly those in the fields  of dead language research so dependent on access to source materials  for their work. In opening to world-wide inspection cuneiform  collections such as that located in Geneva, we join other cultural  heritage and research institutions in CDLI's 'extended family' who  believe that humanists should make every effort to fulfill their  curatorial and scholarly responsibilities to permanently archive, and to  make available to the public all artifacts of shared world history that  are in their immediate, or indirect care.</span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">For the Musées d’Art et d’Histoire:&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jean-Luc Chappaz, Conservateur, Musées d'art et d'histoire de la Ville de Genève</span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">For the Cuneiform Digital Library Initiative:&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">Robert K. <span class="il">Englund</span>, Director, CDLI, and Professor of Assyriology, UCLA&nbsp;</span></div><div><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jürgen  Renn, Co-Director, CDLI, Executive Director, Max Planck Institute for  the History of Science, Berlin, and Professor, Humboldt University</span></div></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7896493959010495915/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/01/news-from-cdli-mellon-funded.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7896493959010495915"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7896493959010495915"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/01/news-from-cdli-mellon-funded.html"
         title="News from the CDLI: Mellon-funded digitization of the Geneva cuneiform collection"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
