<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-9061685712088289827</id>
   <published>2013-10-21T10:30:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2013-10-21T10:30:32.814-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Week 2013</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[Today begins the sixth annual <a href="http://www.openaccessweek.org/">Open Access Week</a>:<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><img alt="http://www.eifl.net/system/files/resize/201301/header_865x180-481x100.jpg" class="decoded" height="65" src="http://www.eifl.net/system/files/resize/201301/header_865x180-481x100.jpg" width="320" /> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Open Access Week,</span> a global event now entering its sixth year, is an opportunity for the  academic and research community to continue to learn about the potential  benefits of Open Access, to share what they’ve learned with colleagues,  and to help inspire wider participation in helping to make Open Access a  new norm in scholarship and research.</span></div><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />“Open Access” to information – the free, immediate, online access to the  results of scholarly research, and the right to use and re-use those  results as you need – has the power to transform the way research and  scientific inquiry are conducted. It has direct and widespread  implications for academia, medicine, science, industry, and for society  as a whole.</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />Open Access (OA) has the potential to maximize research investments,  increase the exposure and use of published research, facilitate the  ability to conduct research across available literature, and enhance the  overall advancement of scholarship. Research funding agencies, academic  institutions, researchers and scientists, teachers, students, and  members of the general public are supporting a move towards Open Access  in increasing numbers every year. Open Access Week is a key opportunity  for all members of the community to take action to keep this momentum  moving forward.</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Get involved.</span> Participating in  Open Access Week can be as simple or involved as you like. It can also  be a chance to let your imagination have full rein and come up with  something more ambitious, wacky, fun.</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br />OA Week is an invaluable chance to connect the <span style="font-weight: bold;">global</span> momentum toward open sharing with the advancement of policy changes on the <span style="font-weight: bold;">local</span> level. Universities, colleges, research institutes, funding agencies,  libraries, and think tanks have used Open Access Week as a platform to  host faculty votes on campus open-access policies, to issue reports on  the societal and economic benefits of Open Access, to commit new funds  in support of open-access publication, and more.</span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br style="font-weight: bold;" /></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-weight: bold;">Learn more about what you can do.</span></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">FIRST, sign up at <a href="http://www.openaccessweek.org/">http://www.openaccessweek.org</a> for access to all the support and resources you need, and to connect with the worldwide OA Week community.<br /><br />For examples of how others are advancing Open Access and taking action during The Week, click here if you’re a: <a href="http://www.openaccessweek.org/profiles/blogs/research-funders-ideas">RESEARCH FUNDER</a> | <a href="http://www.openaccessweek.org/profiles/blogs/researchers-ideas">RESEARCHER/FACULTY MEMBER</a> | <a href="http://www.openaccessweek.org/profiles/blogs/administrators-ideas">ADMINISTRATOR</a> | <a href="http://www.openaccessweek.org/profiles/blogs/publishers-ideas">PUBLISHER</a> | <a href="http://www.openaccessweek.org/profiles/blogs/students-ideas">STUDENT</a> | <a href="http://www.openaccessweek.org/profiles/blogs/librarians-ideas">LIBRARIAN</a> </span></blockquote><span style="font-size: small;">At the time of <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/10/administrative-open-access-week-2012.html">Open Access week 2012</a> AWOL <span style="font-family: inherit;"><span>was approaching one million <span><span>p</span>age views</span></span></span>, and had surpassed 5200 subscribers by  email. As of today (21 October 2013) AWOL</span> has had 1,809,830 page views, and has 6203 subscribers by email.]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/9061685712088289827/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/10/open-access-week-2013.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9061685712088289827"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/9061685712088289827"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2013/10/open-access-week-2013.html"
         title="Open Access Week 2013"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
