<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-7168491971293675700</id>
   <published>2012-03-21T23:50:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-07-17T08:58:23.164-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New Book from the Oriental Institute: Pesher Nahum: Texts and Studies in Jewish History and Literature from Antiquity through the Middle Ages Presented to Norman (Nahum) Golb.</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/news/">Announced today</a>:<br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><img align="right" alt="book cover" src="http://oi.uchicago.edu/i/saoc66_5.jpg" /></span><br /><h3> <span style="font-size: x-small;">SAOC 66.<br /><br /><cite>Pesher Nahum: Texts and Studies in Jewish History and Literature  from Antiquity through the Middle Ages Presented to Norman (Nahum) Golb.</cite></span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /><br />Edited by Joel L. Kraemer and Michael G. Wechsler with the participation of Fred Donner, Joshua Holo, and Dennis Pardee.</span></h3><div class="buy"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a class="purch" href="http://www.oxbowbooks.com/bookinfo.cfm/ID/160469" title="Purchase Book">Purchase Book</a> <a class="download" href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/pdf/saoc66.pdf" title="Download PDF">Download PDF</a> <a class="terms" href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/epi.html">Terms of Use</a></span> </div><ol><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Portrait of the Scholar. Joel L. Kraemer</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">A Jewish Wool Merchant in Tenth-Century Mosul Defends Resorting to  “the Sages of the Nations”: An Early Encounter between Jewish Bible  Exegesis and Graeco-Arab Philosophy. Haggai Ben-Shammai</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Some Semantic Shifts in Medieval Judaeo-Arabic. Joshua Blau</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Kippurim, Expiation, Purity, and Impurity: The Well of the Past and the Abyss of Oblivion. Rachel Elior</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">An Epistle on Esoteric Matters by David II Maimonides from the Geniza. Paul B. Fenton</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Sending Funds to Judah ha-Levi. Mordechai A. Friedman</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Emergence and Development of Scholarship on Medieval Judaeo-Arabic in Spain. Maria Angeles Gallego</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Food Commerce in Egypt as Portrayed in Eleventh-Century Geniza Letters. Moshe Gil</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Gershom b. Judah and the Italian Roots of Early Ashkenazic Jewry. Joshua Holo</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Carl Hermann Kraeling: A Reminiscence. Walter E. Kaegi</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">When Did the Palestinian Yeshiva Leave Tiberias? Benjamin Z. Kedar</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">“Many Days without the God of Truth”: Loss and Recovery of Religious Knowledge in Early Karaite Thought. Eve Krakowski</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Adam and Eve or Adam and Noah? Judaeo-Arabic and Hebrew Versions of the Same Books. Daniel J. Lasker</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Historicizing Prophetic Literature: Yefet ben ‘Eli’s Commentary on  Hosea and Its Relationship to al-Qumisi’s Pitron. Meira Polliack</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Jewish Liturgical Divisions of the Torah and the English Chapter  Division of the Vulgate Attributed to Stephen Langton. Paul Saenger</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Biblical Hermeneutics in Abraham Bar Hayya’s Hiyya’s) “Book of  Intercalation”: Reading Science and Philosophy into the Bible. Israel M.  Sandman</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Corporal Modesty in Judaism and Islam. Norman A. Stillman</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">An Aramaic Apocalypse (4Q246) and the Perils of Premature Consensus. Anthony J. Tomasino</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ten Newly Identified Fragments of Saadia’s Commentary on Esther: Introduction and Translation. Michael G. Wechsler</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Murabba’at and the First Jewish Revolt. Michael O. Wise<br />  Indexes<br />  Hebrew Section</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">‘Aluqa as “Nothing” and Its Use in Polemics with the Karaites: A Study of Saadia’s Commentary on Proverbs 30:10–17. Nahem Ilan</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Biblical Hebrew Names for Settlements, Countries, and Ethnic Groups in the Middle Ages. Elinoar Bareket</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Ten Newly Identified Fragments of Saadia’s Commentary on Esther:  The Judaeo-Arabic Text (with an Appendix Containing a Fragment of Judah  ibn Bal’am’s Commentary on Esther). Michael G. Wechsler</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">The View of Abraham ibn Ezra on the Durative Nature of Universal Creation. Abraham Lipshitz</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">History and History‐Writing in Chronicles in the Light of Biblical,  Ancient Near Eastern, and Graeco‐Roman Cultures. Isaac Kalimi</span></li></ol><span style="font-size: x-small;">Contained herein are 25 articles (20 in English, 5 in Hebrew) that,  like the academic oeuvre of volume’s honoree, span a broad array of  topics within the fields of Hebraica, Judaica, Islamica, and Biblica.  The specific categories represented and the contributions they contain  are: biography (Joel L. Kraemer presents a portrait of the honoree;  Walter E. Kaegi shares personal reminiscences of Carl Herman Kraeling);  text editions and translations, with analysis (Haggai Ben-Shammai  analyzes and presents a partial editio princeps of one of the early  Judeao-Arabic endeavors to achieve a rapprochement between biblical and  Graeco-Arab philosophy; Paul B. Fenton analyzes and publishes the editio  princeps of a newly identified esoteric epistle from the hand of David  II Maimondies; Mordechai A. Friedman analyzes and offers some new  insights on four Geniza letters concerning the transfer of money to the  well-known litterateur Judah ha-Levi; Israel M. Sandman analyzes and  presents a critical edition of four fragments from Abraham Bar Hayya’s  Book of Intercalation that represent his harmonization of science and  biblical exegesis; Michael G. Wechsler presents an editio princeps of 10  newly identified fragments of Saadia Gaon’s commentary on the book of  Esther as well an analysis and translation of those fragments,  accompanied by an inventory of all known fragments of Saadia’s  commentary on that book); grammar/lexicography (Joshua Blau surveys  certain vocables in Classical Arabic that sometimes have a different  meaning in Judaeo-Arabic), exegesis, philosophy, theology, and polemics  (Elinoar Bareket surveys the factors underlying the tendency of medieval  Jewish writers to identify the names of biblical people and places with  contemporary equivalents; Rachel Elior examines the Jewish “realm of  memory” surrounding the Day of Atonement; Nahem Ilan analyzes Saadia  Gaon’s interpretation of Proverbs 30:10–17 with a view to his  anti-Karaite polemical tendency, providing as well a structural outline  of Saadia’s introduction to Proverbs; Eve Krakowski considers the  Karaite view of the history of the biblical text and the relevance of  this view to their own collective self-conception, including a critical  reassessment of the view that the Karaites were influenced by certain  Dead Sea Scroll texts; Abraham Lipshitz critically assesses the notion  that Abraham ibn Ezra held to a Philonic view of an infinitely durative  rather than completed act of creation; Meira Polliack analyzes the  relationship between Yefet b. Eli and Daniel al-Qumisi in their  exegetical approaches to biblical prophecy); history of modern  scholarship (Maria Angeles Gallego presents an overview of the stages of  modern European research -- beginning in the 18th century -- on  medieval Judaeo-Arabic, with specific emphasis on Iberian Spanish  scholarship), Jewish socio-cultural history (Moshe Gil provides a  glimpse into the state of food commerce in the Geniza community from the  evidence of merchants’ letters; Joshua Holo considers the evidence for  Gershom b. Judah’s Italian extraction and its relevance for  understanding the origin of Ashkenazic Jewish culture; Benjamin Z. Kedar  evaluates the evidence for the timing of the relocation of the Tiberian  Yeshiva first to Ramla and then to Jerusalem; Norman A. Stillman  provides a comparative survey of the Islamic and Jewish perspectives on  corporal modesty); textual criticism (Daniel J. Lasker surveys and  assesses the history of a specific textual variation in Judah ha-Levi’s  Book of the Kuzari); codicological-textual history (Paul Saenger  analyzes the relationship between chapter divisions of the Pentateuch in  Christian -- especially Latin -- Bibles and those in Jewish tradition);  Dead Sea Scrolls (Anthony J. Tomasino critically evaluates the  formation and supporting data for the current consensus regarding the  messianic nature of 4Q246; Michael O. Wise analyzes the content and  dating of the manuscripts from Murabba’at and considers their  contribution to our knowledge of various personalities who lived during  the First and Second Jewish Revolts); and historiography (Isaac Kalimi  assesses the historiographical method of the writer of the book of  Chronicles in light of both inner-canonical and extra-biblical  considerations). Also included is a comprehensive bibliography of the  honoree’s works as well as discrete indexes of manuscripts, biblical  references, classical and medieval works, and general items.</span><br /><ul><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Studies in Ancient Oriental Civilization 66</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Chicago: The Oriental Institute of the University of Chicago, 2012</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">ISBN: <a class="libx-autolink" href="http://bobcat.library.nyu.edu/primo_library/libweb/action/search.do?fn=go&amp;ct=search&amp;vid=NYU&amp;mode=Basic&amp;indx=0&amp;dum=true&amp;vl%28freeText0%29=1885923872&amp;undefined=all_items&amp;vl%281UIStartWith0%29=contains&amp;vl%28212921975UI0%29=isbn&amp;scps=scope:%28NS%29,scope:%28CU%29,scope:%28%22BHS%22%29,scope:%28NYU%29,scope:%28%22NYSID%22%29,scope:%28%22NYHS%22%29,scope:%28GEN%29,scope:%28%22NYUAD%22%29" style="border-bottom: 1px dotted;" title="libx-autolink">978-1-885923-87-5</a></span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;">Pp. xxiv + 360 + 56* (Hebrew); frontispiece (Norman Golb), 2 figures, 13 plates, 2 tables</span></li><li><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="pubprice">$49.95</span></span></li></ul><div class="rev"><br /></div></blockquote><div style="text-align: center;">For an up to date list of all Oriental Institute publications available online see:</div><div style="text-align: center;"><a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2010/10/oriental-institute-open-access.html">The Oriental Institute Open Access Publications</a></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/7168491971293675700/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/03/new-book-from-oriental-institute-pesher.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7168491971293675700"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/7168491971293675700"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/03/new-book-from-oriental-institute-pesher.html"
         title="New Book from the Oriental Institute: Pesher Nahum: Texts and Studies in Jewish History and Literature from Antiquity through the Middle Ages Presented to Norman (Nahum) Golb."/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
