<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-4233160593837884607</id>
   <published>2009-07-01T09:01:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2009-07-01T09:12:32.702-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">New Open Access Book: The Archaeology and Geography of Ancient Transcaucasian Societies</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://oi.uchicago.edu/research/pubs/catalog/oip/oip134.html">The Archaeology and Geography of Ancient Transcaucasian Societies, Volume 1.<br />The Foundations of Research and Regional Survey in the Tsaghkahovit Plain, Armenia</a><br /><br />Adam T. Smith, Ruben S. Badalyan, Pavel Avetisyan<br />With contributions by Alan Greene and Leah Minc<br />Oriental Institute Publications, Volume 134<br />Chicago: The Oriental Institute, 2009<br />ISBN-13: 978-1-885923-62-2<br />Pp. xlvi + 410; 72 figures, 82 plates, 7 tables<br />$90.00<blockquote><span style="font-size:85%;">Until recently, the South Caucasus was a virtual terra incognita on<br />Western archaeological maps of southwest Asia. The conspicuous absence<br />of marked places — of site names, toponyms, and topography — gave the<br />impression of a region distant, unknown, and vacant. The Joint<br />American-Armenian Project for the Archaeology and Geography of Ancient<br />Transcaucasian Societies (Project ArAGATS) was founded in 1998 to<br />explore this terrain. Our investigations were guided by two overarching<br />goals: to illuminate the social and political transformations central to<br />the region’s unique (pre)history and to explore the broader intellectual<br />implications of collaboration between the rich archaeological traditions<br />of Armenia (former U.S.S.R.) and the United States.<br /><br />This volume provides the first encompassing report on the ongoing<br />studies of Project ArAGATS, detailing the general context of<br />contemporary archaeological research in the South Caucasus as well as<br />the specific context of our regional investigations in the Tsaghkahovit<br />Plain of central Armenia. The book opens with detailed examinations of<br />the history of archaeology in the South Caucasus, the theoretical<br />problems that currently orient archaeological research, and a<br />comprehensive reevaluation of the material bases for regional chronology<br />and periodization.<br /><br />The work then provides the complete results of our regional<br />investigations in the Tsaghkahovit Plain, including the findings of the<br />first systematic pedestrian survey ever conducted in the Caucasus.<br />Thanks to the results presented in this volume, and Project ArAGATS’s<br />ongoing excavations in the area, the Tsaghkahovit Plain is today the<br />best-known archaeological region in the South Caucasus. The present<br />volume thus provides archaeologists with both an orientation to the<br />prehistory of the South Caucasus and the complete findings of the first<br />phase of Project ArAGATS’s field investigations.<br /><br />To order the printed book, in North America contact The David Brown Book<br />Company, PO Box 511, Oakville, CT 06779, Toll Free: 1-800-791-9354, Fax:<br />860-945-9468, e-mail: queries@dbbconline.com. In Europe and elsewhere,<br />contact Oxbow Books, Park End Place, Oxford, OX1 1HN, UK, Tel: (+44) (0)<br />1865-241-249, Fax: (+44) (0) 1865-794-449, e-mail: oxbow@oxbowbooks.com.<br />Website: <a href="http://www.oxbowbooks.com/">www.oxbowbooks.com</a>.</span></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/4233160593837884607/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/07/new-open-access-book-archaeology-and.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4233160593837884607"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/4233160593837884607"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/07/new-open-access-book-archaeology-and.html"
         title="New Open Access Book: The Archaeology and Geography of Ancient Transcaucasian Societies"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
