<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1092479623412845010</id>
   <published>2011-05-03T11:19:00.000-04:00</published>
   <updated>2011-05-03T11:19:54.637-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">American Institute of Indian Studies Center for Art and Archaeology Archive</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="bigblue"><a href="http://dsal.uchicago.edu/images/aiis/"><span style="font-size: small;">American Institute of Indian Studies </span><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span style="font-size: small;">Center for Art and Archaeology Archive</span></span></a></div><div class="bigblue"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><br /></span></div><div class="bigblue"><blockquote>  <span style="font-size: x-small;">The web presentation of the AIIS photographic archive is a joint venture  of the AIIS and the Digital South Asia Library project. The data  included been collected and edited by AIIS staff in Gurgaon.   Programming and database design have been undertaken by DSAL project  staff in Chicago.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The original AIIS collection is organized into four separate  collections,  architecture, sculpture, paintings and numismatics.  The  web version of the AIIS photograph archive has combined these four  collections into one for ease of searching and display.  There is an  option to limit a search to one or more of these original designations.</span></blockquote><blockquote>  <blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <b>architectural</b>  database model is designed to  provide specific information about an  architectural monument:   structural details, decorative motifs, technical details, materials,  etc.  Any monument, structural or rock-cut, that possesses describable  architectural features should be analyzed according to fields in this  database model.  In addition, sculptural and painted details in situ  should be described along with the monument itself, using the same  architecture model.  Rock-cut monuments containing elements that can be  described in architectural, sculptural, and painting terms also should  be indexed using the architecture model.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <b>sculpture</b> database model is designed to provide  detailed analysis of detached round and relief sculpture.  The kinds of  information contained in the sculpture database model include  descriptions of the subjects and iconographical features (attributes,  mudras, asanas, and subordinate elements).  Detached sculpture from a  known monument but now in a public or private collection should be  analyzed using the sculpture model.  In addition, sculpture lying loose  at a site which does not necessarily belong to a monument located at the  site also should be analyzed according to the sculpture model.  In this  latter case, the location should be noted in the PRESENT LOCATION  field.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <b>painting</b> database model includes specific fields  for analysis of paintings and illustrated folios of manuscripts.  Wall  paintings (murals and frescoes) that have been removed to public or  private collections should be described using the painting model.   However, wall paintings in situ (such as those at Ajanta) should be  described with the monument where they are located using the  architectural model.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The <b>numismatic</b> database model is designed to accommodate specific information about coins. </span></blockquote></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The structure of the various databases is rather similar,  many of the fields are in all four databases. For the web implemnation  we have grouped the following fields together for searching purposes. </span></blockquote><blockquote>  <blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">A <b>subject</b> search will look through data in the  following fields: monument, religious affiliation, style, period,  patron, index category, subject, context, materials, monument type,  medium. </span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">A <b>location</b> search will look through data in the following fields: country, state, district, site, monument, complex, present location. </span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">A <b>date</b> search will look through data in the following fields: photo date, AIIS period, CE date. </span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">An <b>identification number</b> search will look through data in the following fields: accession number, negative number, museum number.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">An <b>affliation</b> search will look through data in the  following fields: documentation reference, photographer, protected by,  donor, religious affiliation, patron.</span></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">The quick search will look through data in the following  fields: monument, religious affiliation, style, period, patron, index  category, subject, context, materials, monument type, medium, country,  state, district, site, monument, complex, present location.</span></blockquote></blockquote><blockquote><span style="font-size: x-small;">All of the information included in this database originally  was written on individual index cards. The herculean task of entering  the data from the index cards into a database was done by staff at the  AIIS offices in Gurgaon under the careful direction of Sushil Sharma. </span></blockquote></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1092479623412845010/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/05/american-institute-of-indian-studies.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1092479623412845010"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1092479623412845010"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/05/american-institute-of-indian-studies.html"
         title="American Institute of Indian Studies Center for Art and Archaeology Archive"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
