<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-141253487382987199</id>
   <published>2013-12-17T19:00:00.000-05:00</published>
   <updated>2013-12-17T18:59:04.525-05:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egyptology"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Armenia"/>
   <category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Egypt"/>
   <title type="text">Open Access Journal: Armenian Egyptology Centre Newsletter</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<span style="font-size: xx-small;">&nbsp;[First posted in AWOL <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2009/10/more-open-access-journals_31.html">31 October 2001</a>. Most recently updated 17 December&nbsp; 201<span style="font-size: xx-small;">3</span>]</span><br /><a href="http://armenianegyptologycentre.wordpress.com/our-famous-aec-newsletter/"><br /></a><br /><div style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://draft.blogger.com/blogger.g?blogID=116259103207720939" imageanchor="1" style="clear: right; float: right; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-left: 1em;"></a><a href="http://armenianegyptologycentre.wordpress.com/our-famous-aec-newsletter/">Armenian Egyptology Centre Newsletter [AEC Newsletter]</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><a href="http://armenianegyptologycentre.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/image387.jpg"><img alt="" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-47" height="200" src="http://armenianegyptologycentre.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/image387.jpg?w=211&amp;h=300" title="image387" width="142" /></a><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"></span> </blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">Our “<strong>AEC Egyptology Newsletter</strong>” is read since  October 2011 by 2200+ readers from 51 nations – including over 1700  scholars. To receive it directly in PDF format by e-mail please  subscribe at : egyptology_AT_ysu.am and indicate: “<strong>Subscribe</strong>” in your e-mail. Subscription is FREE! Academic Publishers! Please advertise! Mail egyptology_AT_ysu.am for advertising rates.</span><br /></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><div style="text-align: center;"><div style="clear: left; float: left; margin-bottom: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"> </div></div></blockquote></div><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><strong>SUMMARY OF NEWSLETTERS’ CONTENT</strong></span></blockquote><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.academia.edu/5435501/AEC_Egyptology_No._30_December_15_2013_" title="AEC Egyptology Newsletter No. 30 (December 15th, 2013)">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 30 (December 15, 2013)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.academia.edu/4576222/AEC-Egyptology-No-29-September-20-2013">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 29 (September 20, 2013)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="https://www.academia.edu/4576213/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_No._28" title="AEC Egyptology Newsletter No. 28 (July 28, 2013)">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 28 (July 28, 2013)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.academia.edu/3413672/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_27_27th_April_2012_">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 27 (April 27, 2013)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.academia.edu/2449061/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_No._26_January_23_2013">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 26 (January 26, 2013)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Special issue : Preliminary evaluation of new system to vocalize  Ancient Egyptian by seven international scholars linked to the centre  (see previous newsletter).</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.academia.edu/2233007/Red_AEC_Newsletter_-_New_system_to_vocalize_ancient_Egyptian">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 25 [labelled wrongly as 24] (December 3rd, 2012)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Special issue announcing the development of a new system to vocalize ancient Egyptian by Dr. C. T. de Vartavan.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/1667262/AEC_Egyptology_Newslett..._Series_-_28-05-2012.pdf">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 24 (May 28, 2012)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Edito and rest of newsletter: Uniting with our Georgian colleagues.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/1551965/AEC_Newsletter_No_23_-_3rd_New_Series_-_01-04-2012">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 23 (1st of APRIL 2012)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Edito: The Art of Egyptology.&nbsp; Building new tools to evolve:  Hierocheck, Pre inauguration snapshot view of AEC’s Hierocheck 1.0,  Bibliography on the Plants of Ancient Egypt. SAIS—Special Book offer.&nbsp; A  bew donation system to sustain us.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/1489047/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_No._22_February_27_">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 22 (27th of FEBRUARY 2012)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">EDITO:&nbsp;&nbsp;AFTER MAKING NATIONAL NEWS…TIME FOR DEEP GRINDING!&nbsp;The  Maldivian Destruction – An event for Egyptians and Egyptologists to  notice and bear seriously in mind! The burning of the Institut d’Egypte  confirmed to be intentional! Sarah Belzoni – some new additional  biographical notes. The Sarcophagus Project brought to a halt due to  lack of funds! Young Egyptian student fights for her rights by going  naked.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/1239966/AEC-Newsletter_No_21_-_21_December_2011">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 21 (21st of DECEMBER 2011)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">EDITO:&nbsp;CURATORS! DIGITIZE! DIGITIZE! DIGITIZE! AND SPREAD!&nbsp;&nbsp;AEC  enters 2012 in full electronic gear! € 1000000 donation for the  Hieroglyphic Dictionary and other Egyptology projects! Bravo Dimitri! A  snapshot of the new Ancient Egyptian-French Dictionary. By the way,  ‘hieroglyphic’ or ‘hieroglyph’? The Social Agenda of AEC. [Shame  on&nbsp;L’Express,&nbsp;Shame on FNAC,&nbsp;Shame on Taschen].</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/1095594/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_20_25_October_2011_">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER No. 20 (25TH of OCTOBER 2011)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">EDITO:&nbsp;A NEW SECOND WIN OF SCIENTIFIC COMPETITION AND 2000  NEWSLETTER-READERS PUT AEC ON TURBO MODE! -&nbsp;Update concerning the  reconstruction of Khonsu-Ms’ sarcophagus. Visit of Prof. Paul John  Frandsen (Denmark) to AEC. 3 p. Reconstruction of Nefertiti’s face by  digital artist. British man mummified like an ancient Egyptian! AEC  Statistics! 2000+ readers, 3100+ publications &amp; 8000+ plant photos!  Advances in Egyptology No. 2 (2011) is now out! New version of Serge  Rosmorduc’s JSesh available for free download! 4 p. Unexpected  Egyptological greetings from Georgia!</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/943844/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_No_19_9th_of_September_2011_">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER NO 19 (9TH OF SEPTEMBER 2011)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Edito : WHY EGYPTOLOGY? CALL FOR FINANCIAL HELP TO REBUILD KHONSU-MS’  SARCOPHAGUS! Excavations to resume in Egypt despite revolution. Staying  on top of research concerning prehistoric human migrations. Spontaneous  answer to the reading of this issue’s Edito sent on 03 September 2011  21:17 by Ingeborg Waanders (Holland). Senior Researcher in AEC. Sent:  To: Vartavan. Subject: Re: Text for proofing pleasssssseeee!!!!  Rectification over a recent discoveryrelevant to the center’s  specializations.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/601256/AEC-Newsletter_No_18_18th_of_May_2011_2_">AEC-NEWSLETTER NO 18 (18TH OF MAY 2011)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">MOST UNEXPECTED ? : “Pre – Old Egyptian….did not initially belong to  the Afro-Asiatic stock”!&nbsp; The « Point of Synthesis »-shift again  demonstrated as the future path of academic research! Kammerzell’s “The  Sound of Dead Language – Reconstructing Egyptian Phonology ” (1998).  Extracts from Satzinger’s “The Egyptian Connection: Egyptian and the  Semitic Languages” (2002). Biographical notes concerning the scholars  cited in this newsletter.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/531957/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_17_April_17_2011">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER 17 (APRIL 17, 2011)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The “Ancient Egyptian/Indo-European” bridge can help us vocalize  hieroglyphs! Cognates equally seen by Hodge and Ray. Carlton Taylor  Hodge (1917-1998) – Biography. The “Indo-Semitic” theory explained.  Future Flora of Ancient Egypt now well engaged! The Second Revised and  Extended Edition of the Codex of Ancient Egyptian Plant remains is out!</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352773/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_16_16.11.2010_">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER&nbsp; 16 (NOVEMBER 16, 2010)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Edito: “Gs” what? “fdw” is “fedwor”, i.e. “four” – and “dwty?/djouot”  is twenty! The current common state of knowledge concerning Ancient  Egyptian – a snapshot. Creating a precedent: an Egyptologist selected to  teach the future elite of a nation.&nbsp; Visit of His Excellency Wahid  Galal, Ambassador of Egypt, to our centre. Teaching of Ancient Egyptian  (hieroglyphs) in YSU well engaged. Mass media again highlights what is  going on in AEC.&nbsp; Conference of our Vice-Director in Tbilissi. We are on  academia.edu.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352762/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_15_07.05.2010_">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER&nbsp; 15 (JULY 7, 2010)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Edito: The length of human “history” expands by the day. Could the  ancients have been inspired by nature to produce “ancient Egyptian  blue”?. Students’ first experiments in ancient Egyptian gesso and  draughtsmanship. Additional scientific articles in our research areas  just received! The world digital library and Egyptology. AEC Egyptology  Newsletter’s previous Edito referred by British association:</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352761/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_14_25.03.2010_">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER&nbsp; 14 (MARCH 25, 2010)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Edito: Academic acknowledgment in a fifth scientific discipline!  “AGORA” will be screened by students as testing ground on ancient  “Egyptian” art. The major cost savings of the “Point of Synthesis”  academic shift! Prof. Richard Wilkinson made an Honorary Member of our  centre. Silent appearnce of a copy of von Hohenburg’s very rare  Thesaurus Hiroglyphicorum. Advances in Egyptology No. 1 (2010) printed  &amp; revised deadline for No. 2! (2011)</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352760/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_13_15.02.2010_">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER&nbsp; 13 (FEBRUARY 15, 2009)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Edito: The “Point of Synthesis” (P.S) major academic methodological  shift! Research on the “[Proto-]Indo-European” stratum of Ancient  Egyptian in progress…and our linguistic programs. New approved course on  the “Technology of ancient Egyptian art” at the YSU Faculty of History.  Visit of Mr. Frederic Grapin, Consul of France in Armenia, in our  centre…The “Sarcophagus Project” on its final approach. They talk about  us (follow up)…and the “Sarcophagus Project”. Egyptology courses will  start on February 10, 2010 for the first promotion of Armenian  “Egyptologists”. Advances in Egyptology No. 1 (2010) in print! &amp;  call for issue No. 2! (2011).</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352758/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_12_01.10.2009_">AEC EGYPTOLOGY NEWSLETTER&nbsp; 12 (OCTOBER 1, 2009)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">Edito: The stupefying hidden structure of Utterance 36 of the Daily  Ritual! A letter of Sir Gaston Maspero to an aspirant Egyptologist. “AEC  Egyptology Newsletter” – a new name for, by consensus, a new academic  publication.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352757/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_11_01.05.2009_">AEC NEWSLETTER&nbsp; 11 (MAY 1, 2009)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito – ““UNEXPECTED”, One thousand scholars…plus  one”; Further closing acknowledgments; Foundation of Egyptology in  Armenia recorded by National Academy of Sciences; Press archives  concerning our centre and staff now online; AEC Newsletter  Egyptologists’ Readership Statistic per Country; The “A.. Case.”  Aspirant Lawyer-Egyptologist caught in our center’s corridor; Further  major discoveries on ancient Egyptian pigments… this time by UCLA team;  Art of making “herbal wines” already known in Predynastic Egypt; Various  News; Electronic Resources of use…and non use; They talk about us…</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352754/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_10_15.02.2009_">AEC NEWSLETTER&nbsp; 10 (FEBRUARY 15, 2009)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito – “Thank you Mr Obama for returning its Letters  of Nobility to “history” …and therefore to the task of “historian”; A  new philosophy for the partial oblivion of… history; The Times Higher  Education recent article on the instrumentalisation of …history; British  Museum’s major discovery of degraded oil in ancient Egyptian pigments;  Set of pigments just discovered in KV63 (Valley of the Kings, Tomb 63)  !; Similar ochre use in Armenian Erebuni (scientific correspondence);  The use of glue in ancient Egypt (scientific correspondence);  Acknowledgments and please become a supporter of our centre!</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352753/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_9_15.01.2009_">AEC NEWSLETTER 9 (JANUARY 15, 2009)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito -&nbsp;”Not only “Imperial varnishes”, but also  “Imperial pigments”, and&nbsp; thus clearly “Imperial art and technology”” –  First tests experiments with ferrous oxide (ochre) and twigs for ancient  Egyptian draughtsmanship – Further experiments with common reed pens  (Phragmites communis L.) – Experiments with gum as a pigment binder of  Egyptian blue and steatite – They talk about us and Should you wish to  help… – Advances in Egyptology No. 1 (2009) – Call for contributions!</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352752/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_8_15.12.2008_">AEC NEWSLETTER &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 8 (DECEMBER 15, 2008)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito – “Reconstructing the art of ancient Egyptian  sarcophagus making!” -Reconstruction of ancient Egyptian blue in Yerevan  University&nbsp; – Reconstructing ancient Egyptian natural pigments –  Reconstructing an ancient Egyptian gesso for sarcophagi’s background  layer – Should you wish to help us… -Advances in Egyptology&nbsp;No. 1, Call  for contributions!</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352743/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_7_01.11.2008_">AEC NEWSLETTER &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7 (NOVEMBER 1, 2008)!</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito – “Labelling ancient Egyptian Complex varnishes  as “imperial”” – Presentation of AEC’s annual results before the High  Scientific Council – Khonsu-Ms’s sarcophagus (Dyn. 21- Deir el-Bahari)  will inspire us—The current state of our researches &amp; projects&nbsp; –  Our needs… (follow up) -Advances in Egyptology&nbsp;No. 1, Call for  contributions!</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352742/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_6_01.10.2008_">AEC NEWSLETTER 6 (OCTOBER 1, 2008)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito – “Celebrating the First Anniversary of our  centre” – Our data and collections in growth – Expeditions &amp;  partnerships – Our forthcoming projects -&nbsp;Advances in Egyptology&nbsp;No. 1,  Call for contributions!</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352741/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_5_01.07.2008_">AEC NEWSLETTER 5 (JULY 01, 2008)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito – “Successful Partnership with the Jerusalem  Botanical Garden”. Collecting&nbsp;Pistacia, cedar and pine resins in  Jerusalem. The second side of our travel to Jerusalem…a forthcoming book  – New prospects in the field of comparative studies – Those we also  wish to thank.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352740/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_4_01.06.2008_">AEC NEWSLETTER 4 (1 JUNE 2008)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito -&nbsp;“Mummies are not museum “objects”&nbsp;- The  “Sarcophagus Project” – The 5000 photos of plants species of Egypt-mark  exceeded !- Our predecessors in the study of “The Plants of Ancient  Egypt”:&nbsp;Georg A. Schweinfurth&nbsp;(1836-1925).&nbsp; Gifts from our sponsors ! –  Follow up…and Arpag Mekhitarian. Encaustic and “Fayum Portraits”…an  introduction.</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://www.babao.org.uk/index/reburialissues"><img alt="" height="109" src="http://armenianegyptologycentre.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/image506.jpg?w=300&amp;h=109" title="image506" width="300" /></a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352737/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_3_03.05.2008_">AEC NEWSLETTER 3 (01 MAY 2008)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito -&nbsp;Is “mny” the solvent in Ancient Egyptian  varnish?&nbsp;- Wherever you are, whoever you are, join us! – The Sarcophagus  Project, Team and plans in formation – The Sarcophagus Project,  Searched data, questions and specialists – We are looking for  information concerning F. Woenig – Our predecessors in the study of “The  Plants of Ancient Egypt”:&nbsp;Victor Loret&nbsp;(1859-1946) – Gifts from our  sponsors ! – Follow up – Serge Rosmorduc’s free program to write  hieroglyphs: JSesh</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352734/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_2_08.04.2008_">AEC NEWSLETTER 2 (08 APRIL 2008)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito – The “SARCOPHAGUS PROJECT” accepted! – Over  1250 connections to our website since its opening! – The press talks  again about us! – The Flora of Ancient Egypt (FoAE) in progress…- Our  predecessors in the study of “The Plants of Ancient Egypt”:&nbsp;Carl  Sigismund Kunth&nbsp;(1788-1850) – Gifts from our sponsors ! – Follow up –  “Pharmacy in Ancient Egypt” conference – University of Manchester (U.K.)</span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;"><a href="http://yerevan.academia.edu/AshkhenZakharyan/Papers/352727/AEC_Egyptology_Newsletter_1_15.11.2008_">AEC NEWSLETTER 1 (15 NOVEMBER 2007)</a></span><br /> <span style="font-size: x-small;">The Director’s Edito -&nbsp;“In Memoriam Champollioni”&nbsp;- Our website is  on!&nbsp; – The “Sarcophagus Project” – The “Armenian Egypt Exploration  Society (A-EES)” – Our Ethical Charter for Good Egyptology – Our  center’s specialization: The Plants of Ancient Egypt – The Press talks  about us! – Please sponsor one or more computers ! – Those we wish to  thank!</span></blockquote><br /><div style="text-align: center;"><span class="titol"><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span class="text"><span style="font-size: small;">See the full <a href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/07/alphabetical-list-of-open-access.html">List of Open Access Journals in Ancient Studies</a></span></span></span></span></div>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/141253487382987199/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/10/open-access-journal-armenian-egyptology.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/141253487382987199"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/141253487382987199"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2011/10/open-access-journal-armenian-egyptology.html"
         title="Open Access Journal: Armenian Egyptology Centre Newsletter"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
