<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<entry xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
       xmlns:openSearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearchrss/1.0/"
       xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
       xmlns:gd="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005"
       xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0">
   <id>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-116259103207720939.post-1325915763363633418</id>
   <published>2012-04-09T07:05:00.001-04:00</published>
   <updated>2012-04-09T07:05:46.714-04:00</updated>
   <category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind"
             term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
   <title type="text">Ancient Arabia: Languages and Cultures</title>
   <content type="html"><![CDATA[<a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/">Ancient Arabia: Languages and Cultures</a><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: x-small;">The Arabian Peninsula lies at the heart of the Middle East and in  antiquity it stood between the mighty civilizations of Egypt and  Mesapotamia. Yet, our ignorance until now of the history of Arabia  before the emergence of Islam in the 7th century BC, has left a huge  blank at the centre of what we know of the ancient Near East. This blank  is now gradually being filled in, bringing to light not only previously  little known - or even unknown - cultures spread over a vast region,  but also a more complete picture of the ancient Near East as a whole.&nbsp;</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">Geographically "Ancient Arabia" refers to the Arabian Peninsula with,  to the  north, the Syro-Arabian desert stretching into what is modern  Syria and Jordan. Chronologically, it covers all periods from the first  evidence of human activity in the Peninsula, some 400,000 years ago, to  the emergence of Islam...</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The AALC project is creating the OCIANA, which will bring together in  one corpus the almost 39,000 Ancient North Arabian inscriptions known  to date. The initial phase of this project has been completed and at  present the OCIANA contains 3420 previously unpublished Safaitic  inscriptions recorded by the late Geraldine King in 1989 on the <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/safaitic-database-online">Basalt Desert Rescue Survey</a>.  The AALC project has also put online a downloadable pdf of Geraldine  King's fundamental study of the inscriptions in a dialect and script  used mainly by nomads in the Ḥismā sand desert of southern Jordan and  northern Saudi Arabia, and which are therefore called "Hismaic"  (formerly "<a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/component/content/article/24" rel="shadowbox" style="color: #003366;">Thamudic E</a>").</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">In addition, the site is making available some 800 texts recorded in  the mountainous region of Dhofar, in the south of modern Oman by the <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/dhofar-epigraphic-project" target="_self">Dhofar Epigraphic Project</a>.  They were painted on cave walls and inscribed on stones in a script  that as yet remains undeciphered and in a language that is still  unknown. A concordance of the inscriptions has been provided which it is  hoped will aid their eventual decipherment.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;">The OCIANA will be continuously updated as more inscriptions are  discovered. Similarly, as more rock-art, and historical, archaeological,  and linguistic material from ancient Arabia becomes available it is  planned to make it accessible either on the AALC site or via links to  other sites.</span><br /><span style="font-size: x-small;"><span><span>The AALC project also is also making available other primary sources for ancient Arabia such as </span><a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/wj-bankes-journey-to-petra-1818" target="_self">Norman Lewis's</a><span>&nbsp;previously  unpublished transcription of W.J. Bankes's journal of his visit to  Petra in 1818, as well as links to websites, further reading and  bibliography for the study of ancient Arabia, and biographical notes on  some of the scholars who have contributed most to this website and its  associated projects, and to the study of ancient Arabia.</span></span></span><br /><br /><blockquote class="tr_bq"><span style="font-size: xx-small;">The AALC Projects<br /></span>                          <br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;"><img alt="thamudic_d" height="348" src="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/images/stories/thamudic_d.jpg" style="float: right; margin-bottom: 20px; margin-left: 20px;" width="136" />The  languages and cultures of ancient Arabia have long been studied in the  University of Oxford, a legacy of the pioneering work undertaken by the  late <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/11" target="_self">Professor A.F.L. Beeston</a>.  The primary aim of the project Ancient Arabia : Languages and Cultures  (AALC) is to make accessible through a single central portal a variety  of resources for the study of ancient Arabia, thereby creating a global  resource for the study of the languages and cultures of ancient Arabia  and the Arabs before the emergence of Islam.</span><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;">The Academic Director of AALC is <a href="http://www.orinst.ox.ac.uk/staff/iw/mmacdonald.html" target="_self">Michael Macdonald</a>, an expert in the languages and cultures of Ancient Arabia. AALC was initiated and is managed by <a href="http://www.krc.ox.ac.uk/" target="_blank">The Khalili Research Centre</a> (KRC) of the <a href="http://www.orinst.ox.ac.uk/" target="_blank">Faculty of Oriental Studies</a> in the <a href="http://www.ox.ac.uk/" target="_blank">University of Oxford</a>, and the Director of the KRC, <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/krc/index.php/staff/13-professor-jeremy-johns" target="_blank">Jeremy Johns</a>,  is the Administrative Director of AALC. The technical aspects of the  project, including this website, are managed by Daniel Burt, and the  scanning and cataloguing is the work of Jennifer Lockie.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;">The AALC is managed by a small committee consisting of the team members already mentioned, reinforced by <a href="http://www.orinst.ox.ac.uk/staff/iw/rhoyland.html" target="_blank">Professor Robert Hoyland</a>.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;">In October 2011, AALC received an initial grant from the University  of Oxford's John Fell Fund. Further applications to continue the work of  AALC and its associated projects are pending and in preparation.</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;">Much of the focus of the initial year (2010–2011) of the AALC project  is to digitise and publish the work undertaken by the late <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/10" target="_self">Dr Geraldine King</a>, including her previously unpublished doctoral thesis on <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/early-north-arabian-hismaic" target="_self">Early North Arabian Thamudic E [Hismaic]</a>,  and the large amounts of epigraphic material that she recorded and had  prepared for publication before her early death (including the <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/black-desert-rescue-survey">Basalt Desert Rescue Survey</a> and the <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/dhofar-epigraphic-project">Dhofar Epigraphic Project</a>).</span><br /><br /><span style="font-size: xx-small;">In addition to the work undertaken by Geraldine King, the site will  also contain work undertaken by Michael Macdonald and his collaborators,  including the massive <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/safaitic-database-online" target="_self">Safaitic Database Online</a>, alongside other primary sources for the study of ancient Arabia, such as <a href="http://krc.orient.ox.ac.uk/aalc/index.php/projects/wj-bankes-journey-to-petra-1818" target="_self">W.J. Bankes's journal of his visit to Petra</a> in 1818, and links to websites and bibliography for the study of  ancient Arabia, and biographical notes on some of the scholars who have  contributed most to this website and its associated projects and to the  study of ancient Arabia.</span><br /><br /></blockquote></blockquote>]]></content>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/feeds/1325915763363633418/comments/default"
         title="Post Comments"/>
   <link rel="replies"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/04/ancient-arabia-languages-and-cultures.html#comment-form"
         title="0 Comments"/>
   <link rel="edit"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1325915763363633418"/>
   <link rel="self"
         type="application/atom+xml"
         href="https://www.blogger.com/feeds/116259103207720939/posts/default/1325915763363633418"/>
   <link rel="alternate"
         type="text/html"
         href="http://ancientworldonline.blogspot.com/2012/04/ancient-arabia-languages-and-cultures.html"
         title="Ancient Arabia: Languages and Cultures"/>
   <author>
      <name>Charles Jones</name>
      <uri>https://plus.google.com/114326413909322730653</uri>
      <email>noreply@blogger.com</email>
   </author>
</entry>
